[
  {
    "question": "What science did Aristotle define as âthe knowledge of immaterial beingâ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Metaphysics",
    "choices": [
      "A. Psychology",
      "B. Logic",
      "C. Metaphysics",
      "D. Philosophy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which WWF group does this theme music belong to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "D-Generation X",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nation of Domination",
      "B. D-Generation X",
      "C. Legion of Doom",
      "D. Hart Foundation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position is former Major League Baseball player, Rollie Fingers famous for playing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pitcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. First Base",
      "C. Pitcher",
      "D. Third Base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position is former baseball player for the Cincinnati Reds, Johnny Bench famous for playing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Catcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Second Base",
      "B. Shortstop",
      "C. Catcher",
      "D. Pitcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Baltimore Orioles, Cal Ripken Jr. is most known for playing what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shortstop",
    "choices": [
      "A. Right Field",
      "B. Catcher",
      "C. Pitcher",
      "D. Shortstop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Steve Garvey is a famous former baseball player, who is known for playing what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "First Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. First Base",
      "B. Shortstop",
      "C. Third Base",
      "D. Catcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position is former Major League Baseball player, Joe Morgan most known to have played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Second Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Outfield",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Second Base",
      "D. Catcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position is former professional baseball player, Mike Schmidt famous for playing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pitcher",
      "B. Catcher",
      "C. Third Base",
      "D. Second Base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these positions is former baseball player, Dwight Evans most famous for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Right Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Right Field",
      "B. Pitcher",
      "C. Second Base",
      "D. Center Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Successful Major League Baseball player and coach, Donald Edward Don Gullett, was famous for playing what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pitcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pitcher",
      "B. Second Base",
      "C. Right Field",
      "D. Catcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Whitey Ford was a successful Major League Baseball player, who played in what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pitcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pitcher",
      "B. First Base",
      "C. Catcher",
      "D. Shortstop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Carlton Fisk was a successful Major League Baseball player, who played for 24 years with the Boston Red Sox and Chicago White Sox, in what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Catcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. Pitcher",
      "C. Left Field",
      "D. None of the Above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pittsburgh Steelers of the 50s had a third string quarterback from Louisville, who was not making it. They cut him and he landed with the Colts. Who was he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Unitas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Terry Bradshaw",
      "B. Bert Jones Jr",
      "C. Len Dawson",
      "D. Johnny Unitas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first football team to win back to back Super Bowls with different coaches?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Francisco",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Francisco",
      "B. Dallas",
      "C. Miami",
      "D. Pittsburgh"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many points did Wilt Chamberlain score in his best game versus New York?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "100",
    "choices": [
      "A. 71",
      "B. 100",
      "C. 82",
      "D. 99"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is the youngest NBA player to score 10,000 points.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kobe Bryant",
    "choices": [
      "A. Spud Webb",
      "B. Kobe Bryant",
      "C. Moses Malone",
      "D. Michael Jordon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is the shortest player ever to win the Slam Dunk Contest.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spud Webb",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kobe Bryant",
      "B. Spud Webb",
      "C. Vince Carter",
      "D. Tracy McGrady"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He retired with the NBAs highest scoring average (30.1 points per game).",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jarmaine ONeal",
      "B. Shaquille ONeal",
      "C. Dwyane Wade",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Karl Malone received the award Most Valuable Player in 1996-97. What team did he play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Utah Jazz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sacramento Kings",
      "B. Miami Heat",
      "C. LA Lakers",
      "D. Utah Jazz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is the NBAs All-Time scorer.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "B. Ken Johnson",
      "C. Clyde Lovelette",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wilt Chamberlain is a great player indeed. In a game against the Celtics he made the best rebounding effort ever. How many rebounds did he make in this famous game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "55",
    "choices": [
      "A. 16",
      "B. 57",
      "C. 55",
      "D. 31"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first player to top 20,000 points in NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Pettit",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Pettit",
      "B. Spud Webb",
      "C. Clyde Drexler",
      "D. Wilt Chamberlain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "George Muresan and Manute Bol are the tallest players in NBA history. How tall are they?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "77 (2.31m)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 77 (2.31m)",
      "B. 72 (2.18m)",
      "C. 78 (2.33m)",
      "D. 74 (2.23m)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the shortest player in the history of NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tyronne Bogues",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tyronne Bogues",
      "B. Spud Webb",
      "C. Larry Bird",
      "D. Eddie Griffin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was a player, coach, and owner  -all for one team. He was also instrumental in developing the NFL.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Halas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wellington Mara",
      "B. George Halas",
      "C. Red Grange",
      "D. Pete Rozelle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This college and pro great had a very strange nickname -Crazy Legs.   His last name was Hirsch.  What was his real first name ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elroy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lester",
      "B. Arnie",
      "C. Cliff",
      "D. Elroy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Compton Junior College gave us this all-time great runner, who played fullback and was nicknamed Joe the Jet.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Perry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Battles",
      "B. Neale",
      "C. Sanders",
      "D. Perry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "His real name is Yelverton Abraham, and he played for San Francisco as well as the NY Giants. He attended LSU.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tittle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Motley",
      "B. Strong",
      "C. Groza",
      "D. Tittle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great sportsman was the first football player to be all-pro at defensive back one year and running back another.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gifford",
    "choices": [
      "A. Grange",
      "B. Thorpe",
      "C. Gifford",
      "D. Haynes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This quarterback was cut by the Steelers and picked up by another team, played in high tops, and his teammates include Lenny Moore and Steve Myhra.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Unitas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Terry Bradshaw",
      "B. Johnny Unitas",
      "C. John Brodie",
      "D. Norm Van Brocklin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great defensive end came from South Carolina State and played for the Rams. He is credited with inventing the head slap move.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lamar Lundy",
      "B. David Jones",
      "C. Merlin  Olsen",
      "D. Rosy Grier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great running back was once traded for eleven players.  He had great speed and great moves, returned kicks, caught passes, and ran the ball.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ollie Matson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barry Sanders",
      "B. Ollie Matson",
      "C. Dick Lane",
      "D. Marcus Allen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great football player is known for catching the immaculate reception .",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Franco Harris",
    "choices": [
      "A. O.J. Simpson",
      "B. Lynn Swann",
      "C. John Stallworth",
      "D. Franco Harris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Many of the greatest coaches, both pro and college, trace their learning to Miami University of Ohio and the teachings of this coaching great, who led Cleveland to many championships.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Brown",
    "choices": [
      "A. Woody  Hayes",
      "B. Weeb Ewbank",
      "C. Paul Brown",
      "D. Don Shula"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Miami Heat enter the NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1988",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1988",
      "B. 1974",
      "C. 1963",
      "D. 1958"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams does the Atlantic Division of the Eastern Conference have?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Larry Brown led this team from 1997 to 2003.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Philadephia 76ers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago Bulls",
      "B. LA Lakers",
      "C. Denver Nuggets",
      "D. Philadephia 76ers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mark Price, Larry Nance, Brad Daugerty, Shawn Kemp and Austin Carr have been chosen to be this teams all-time starting five.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleveland Cavaliers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cleveland Cavaliers",
      "B. Philadelphia 76ers",
      "C. Denver Nuggets",
      "D. Houston Rockets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team is one of the five playing in the Southwest Division of the Western Conference. Tracy McGrady (as of 2005)  plays for this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Houston Rockets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston Rockets",
      "B. Minnesota Timberwolves",
      "C. Utah Jazz",
      "D. San Antonio Spurs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Arguably the most famous NBA team. Michael Jordan played for this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miami Heat",
      "B. Utah Jazz",
      "C. Sacramento Kings",
      "D. Chicago Bulls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which division do the Sacramento Kings play in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pacific Division of the Western Conference",
    "choices": [
      "A. Southwest Division of the Western Conference",
      "B. Atlantic Division of the Eastern Conference",
      "C. Pacific Division of the Western Conference",
      "D. Central Division of the Eastern Conference"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team drafted and then exchanged for another player Chris Webber in 1993.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Orlando Magic",
    "choices": [
      "A. Orlando Magic",
      "B. Sacramento Kings",
      "C. Golden State Warriors",
      "D. Miami Heat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team won its first division title in the 1969-70 season, when Spencer Heywood signed with the club.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Denver Nuggets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Philadelphia 76ers",
      "B. Detroit Pistons",
      "C. Chicago Bulls",
      "D. Denver Nuggets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team moved to Detroit in 1957. It was founded by Fred Zollner in 1940.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pistons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Knicks",
      "B. Warriors",
      "C. Pistons",
      "D. Lakers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these people founded the World Wrestling Entertainment, Inc?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vincent McMahon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hulk Hogan",
      "B. Shane McHamon",
      "C. Vincent McMahon",
      "D. Ric Flair"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In professional wrestling, the high side thrust kick, often used by Shawn Michaels as a finishing move, is also known by what name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sweet Chin Music",
    "choices": [
      "A. Leg Drop",
      "B. Sweet Chin Music",
      "C. Batista Bomb",
      "D. 5 Star"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Hank Aaron wear for the Atlanta Braves?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "44",
    "choices": [
      "A. 26",
      "B. 44",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In Major League Baseball, first and second bases are this far apart.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "90",
    "choices": [
      "A. 85",
      "B. 95",
      "C. 90",
      "D. 93"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many home runs did Hank Aaron hit in his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "755",
    "choices": [
      "A. 609",
      "B. 625",
      "C. 750",
      "D. 755"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many innings are in a Little League baseball game, excluding extra innings?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 7"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many games are in a Major League Baseball season per team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "162",
    "choices": [
      "A. 155",
      "B. 162",
      "C. 160",
      "D. 170"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For what team did Tony Dorsett play after he left the Cowboys?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Denver Broncos",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston Oilers",
      "B. Minnesota Vikings",
      "C. Pittsburgh Steelers",
      "D. Denver Broncos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Roger Staubach win the Heisman Trophy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1963",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1963",
      "B. 1962",
      "C. 1965",
      "D. 1964"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Cowboys had the first selection in the 1974 draft. Who did they take?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ed Too Tall  Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Dorsett",
      "B. Thomas Henderson",
      "C. Ed Too Tall  Jones",
      "D. Randy White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Troy Aikman graduated from UCLA, but where did he begin his college career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oklahoma",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miami",
      "B. Stanford",
      "C. Oklahoma",
      "D. Texas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players won the Super Bowl MVP despite his teams loss?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Howley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Staubach",
      "B. Harvey Martin",
      "C. Randy White",
      "D. Chuck Howley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these Cowboys won the Super Bowl XII MVP trophy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harvey Martin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harvey Martin",
      "B. Tony Dorsett",
      "C. Duane Thomas",
      "D. Michael Irvin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Chicago Bulls drafted this player in 1984, who is probably the best in the NBA ever. He played his final game on April 16, 2003.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shaquille ONeal",
      "B. Magic Johnson",
      "C. Kevin Garnett",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was selected by the Phoenix Suns in the first round (15th pick overall) of the 1996 NBA Draft.  In 2005 he was awarded MVP (most valuable player).",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Nash",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carmelo Anthony",
      "B. Karl Malone",
      "C. Kobe Bryant",
      "D. Steve Nash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was drafted in 2002 by Phoenix Suns, right after Nikoloz Tskitishvili , Dajuan Wagner, Nene, and Chris Wilcox.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Amare Stoudemire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shawn Kemp",
      "B. LeBron James",
      "C. Jason Kidd",
      "D. Amare Stoudemire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was drafted in 1962 by the Celtics. He is also known as Hondo.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jonh Havlicek",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maurice Cheeks",
      "B. Jonh Havlicek",
      "C. Peja Sojakovich",
      "D. Sam Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1986 Detroit Pistons had great luck- they made two good draft picks. One of them was John Salley and the other was the 27th selected player.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis Rodman",
    "choices": [
      "A. LeBron James",
      "B. Vlade Divac",
      "C. Dennis Rodman",
      "D. Chris Webber"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although this player was the 36th selected player drafted by the Philadelphia 76ers in 1978, he turned out to be the best point guard drafted that year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maurice Cheeks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerome James",
      "B. Maurice Cheeks",
      "C. Butch Lee",
      "D. Butch Lee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although he wasnt the best player on his college team, he became an All-Star player in his fifth season. Detroit Pistons drafted him in 1971.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Curtis Rowe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roko Ukic",
      "B. Curtis Rowe",
      "C. Ben Gordon",
      "D. Jackson Vroman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was the 31st selected in 2001 draft by the Golden State Warriors.  He and Jamison was chossen to represent the Washington Wizards at the 2005 NBA All-Star Game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gilbert Arenas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carmelo Anthony",
      "B. Ben Gordon",
      "C. Vlade Divac",
      "D. Gilbert Arenas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This European player was drafted in 2001 by the San Antonio Spurs. He became the youngest player ever to appear in a game with the Spurs making his NBA debut at 19 years old.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Parker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Parker",
      "B. Vlade Divac",
      "C. Peja Stojakovic",
      "D. Raul Lopez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before they were the Detroit Pistons, the Pistons played in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ft. Wayne, Indiana",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gary, Indiana",
      "B. Louisville, Kentucky",
      "C. Ft. Wayne, Indiana",
      "D. Cincinnati, Ohio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before they were the L.A. Lakers, they played in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Minneapolis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Denver",
      "B. Milwaukee",
      "C. Minneapolis",
      "D. Cincinnati"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where were the NBA Hawks located, before moving to Atlanta?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "St. Louis,MO",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rochester, NY",
      "B. Syracuse, NY",
      "C. Cincinnati, OH",
      "D. St. Louis,MO"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These are the only two original NBA teams that never  moved.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Knicks and Celtics",
    "choices": [
      "A. Warriors and Bulls",
      "B. Bulls and Celtics",
      "C. Knicks and Celtics",
      "D. Warriors and Knicks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the Atlanta Braves team originate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston",
      "B. They were always in Atlanta",
      "C. Sacramento",
      "D. Milwaukee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where were the Dodgers playing before they moved to L.A.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brooklyn, NY",
    "choices": [
      "A. Newark, NJ",
      "B. Sacramento, CA",
      "C. Brooklyn, NY",
      "D. Washington, DC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the original home to the NFL Rams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleveland, OH",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cincinnati, OH",
      "B. Canton, OH",
      "C. L.A., CA",
      "D. Cleveland, OH"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the Philadelphia Eagles use to play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pittsburgh and Philadelphia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rochest, NY",
      "B. Pittsburgh and Philadelphia",
      "C. Cincinnati, OH",
      "D. Canton, OH"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To which city do the Sacramento Kings trace their origins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rochester, NY",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington, DC",
      "B. Pittsburgh, PA",
      "C. Louisville, KY",
      "D. Rochester, NY"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the San Francisco Giants play before San Francisco?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York, NY",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington, DC",
      "B. Buffalo, NY",
      "C. Atlanta, GA",
      "D. New York, NY"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team won the 1994 NCAA Division I-A national football championship. The motto of the team is: Not the victory but the action. Not the goal but the game. In the deed the glory.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nebraska",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nebraska",
      "B. Oklahoma",
      "C. Ohio State",
      "D. Florida St"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1927 this Ivy League team won the NCAA Division I-A national football championship.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yale",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harvard",
      "B. Army",
      "C. Princeton",
      "D. Yale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1958, this team shared their first title from NCAA Division I-A national football championship with Iowa.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "LSU",
    "choices": [
      "A. LSU",
      "B. Army",
      "C. BYU",
      "D. Florida"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team won the 2005 NCAA Football Championship, lead by head coach Mack Brown",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Texas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Notre Dame",
      "B. Texas",
      "C. LSU",
      "D. USC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team, with head coach Tom Osborne, won the most NCAA football Championships in the 1990s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nebraska",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tennessee",
      "B. Nebraska",
      "C. Florida",
      "D. Florida State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Dickinson poll, in 1928 this football team, coached by Howard Jones, won its first national title.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "USC",
    "choices": [
      "A. LSU",
      "B. USC",
      "C. BYU",
      "D. Yale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team, nicknamed The Hurricanes, won three NCAA Football Titles in the 1980s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miami",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miami",
      "B. Oklahoma",
      "C. Penn State",
      "D. Notre Dame"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Notre Dame and their head coach Knute Rockne, win their first NCAA football Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1924",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1987",
      "B. 1980",
      "C. 1938",
      "D. 1924"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team, led by head coach James Tressel,  won the 2002 NCAA championship, beating Miami in overtime.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ohio State",
    "choices": [
      "A. USC",
      "B. Ohio State",
      "C. LSU",
      "D. Miami"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the nickname of North Carolina and of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tar Heels",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hoyas",
      "B. Buckeyes",
      "C. Tar Heels",
      "D. Bruins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which American university has chosen the spider as its official mascot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Richmond",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Richmond",
      "B. Boston College",
      "C. University of Rhode Island",
      "D. Valipariaso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Eagles athletic teams represent which college/university?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston College",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston College",
      "B. University of Arizona",
      "C. University of Philadelphia",
      "D. Yale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of the University of Tennessees teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Volunteers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hokies",
      "B. Terrapins",
      "C. Crimsom Tide",
      "D. Volunteers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Boilermakers is the nickname of which American university?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Purdue University",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Michigan",
      "B. Indiana State University",
      "C. Northwestern University",
      "D. Purdue University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1933 this team won the first NFL Championship Game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Giants",
      "B. Chicago Bears",
      "C. Canton Bulldogs",
      "D. Washington Redskins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the 1940 National Football League Championship Game with 73-0?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Giants",
      "B. Oakland Raiders",
      "C. Washington Redskins",
      "D. Chicago Bears"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams won their first Super Bowl in 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "None of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Seattle",
      "D. Cincinnati"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which championship game was called The Greatest Game Ever Played and was the first  championship game to go into overtime?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The 1958 Championship Game",
    "choices": [
      "A. The 1983 Championship Game",
      "B. The 1974 Championship Game",
      "C. The 1990 Championship Game",
      "D. The 1958 Championship Game"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1967 NFL Championship Game Green Bay beat Dallas 21-17. Which nickname is attached to this game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Ice Bowl",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Long Fourth-Quarter Game",
      "B. The Ice Bowl",
      "C. The One -Quarter Game",
      "D. The First Super Bowl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which NFL team won their 12th Championship in 1997?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Green Bay Packers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Green Bay Packers",
      "B. New England Patriots",
      "C. Chicago Bears",
      "D. Cleveland Bowns"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams was defeated at the Super Bowl XXXIII game by the Denver Broncos?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Atlanta Falcons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta Falcons",
      "B. Providence Steam Roller",
      "C. Frankford Yellow Jackets",
      "D. Tennessee Titans"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won Super Bowl VII and Super Bowl VIII?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miami Dolphins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pittsburgh Steelers",
      "B. San Francisco 49ERs",
      "C. Miami Dolphins",
      "D. Dallas Cowboys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player from Alabama University was the Championship MVP in 1968.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bart Starr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Horning",
      "B. Darryl LaMonica",
      "C. Bart Starr",
      "D. Max McGee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players have never won the Super Bowl MVP?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dan Marino",
    "choices": [
      "A. Richard Dent",
      "B. Jake Scott",
      "C. Dan Marino",
      "D. Chuck Howley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Ultimate Warrior and Rick Rude competed for the Intercontinental Title in which SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1989",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1989",
      "B. 1990",
      "C. 1988",
      "D. 1991"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Honky Tonk man lost the Intercontinental Title to Ultimate Warrior at the first SummerSlam in 1988, but who was Honky originally to defend his title against?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brutus Beefcake",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Murracco",
      "B. Jake Roberts",
      "C. Brutus Beefcake",
      "D. Jim Duggan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bret Hart wrestled in every SummerSlam that he could, while a WWF SuperStar.  From 1988-1997 he missed only one SummerSlam.  What year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1996",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1989",
      "B. 1990",
      "C. 1996",
      "D. 1988"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How Many Times has Randy Savage been the Macho King at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 0",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Largest in terms of attendance SummerSlam took Place in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1992",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2001",
      "B. 2002",
      "C. 1994",
      "D. 1992"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the SmackDown! US title match from the 2003 edition of SummerSlam, who walked out the US Champion?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eddie Guerrero",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tajiri",
      "B. Chris Benoit",
      "C. Eddie Guerrero",
      "D. Rhyno"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first steel cage match at SummerSlam was between which two competitors?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ultimate Warrior/Rick Rude",
    "choices": [
      "A. Diesel/Mabel",
      "B. Bret Hart/Owen Hart",
      "C. Ultimate Warrior/Rick Rude",
      "D. Mankind/Hunter Hearst Helmsley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times has SummerSlam been in New York City, at Madison Square Garden?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "At least 3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. At least 3",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won five NBA titles in the 1980s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Lakers",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Knicks",
      "B. Chicago Bulls",
      "C. Los Angeles Lakers",
      "D. Boston Celtics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL team did O.J. Simpson play for at the end of his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Francisco 49ers",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Francisco 49ers",
      "B. Oakland Raiders",
      "C. Philadelphia Eagles",
      "D. Miami Dolphins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NBA team did Bill Walton lead to a NBA title?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Portland Trail Blazers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "B. Utah Jazz",
      "C. San Antonio Spurs",
      "D. Houston Rockets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What college basketball team did Billy King, general manager of the Philadelphia 76ers, play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duke",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alabama",
      "B. UCLA",
      "C. Georgetown",
      "D. Duke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NBA team is known for their cowbells?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sacramento Kings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta Hawks",
      "B. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "C. Sacramento Kings",
      "D. San Antonio Spurs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL team went 1-15 during the 1989 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Cowboys",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston Texans",
      "B. Chicago Bears",
      "C. Dallas Cowboys",
      "D. The New York Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did Oklahoma beat in the 2000 Orange Bowl to win the national title?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Florida Sate",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida Sate",
      "B. ISU",
      "C. Miami",
      "D. Nebraska"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Ralph Kiner, who was inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame in 1975, wear when he played for the Pittsburgh Pirates in the 40s and 50s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 11",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Tom Seaver, who was elected to the Baseball Hall of Fame on January in 1992,  wear when he was a player for the New York Mets in the 1970s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "41",
    "choices": [
      "A. 35",
      "B. 47",
      "C. 41",
      "D. 32"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Major League Baseball player Pete Rose wear when he played for the Cincinnati Reds?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 14",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 7"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did  Baseball Hall of Famer, Rod Carew, wear on his uniform when he played for the Minnesota Twins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "29",
    "choices": [
      "A. 33",
      "B. 6",
      "C. 29",
      "D. 44"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Don Mattingly wear when he played as a part-time first baseman and outfielder for the New York Yankees in 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "46",
    "choices": [
      "A. 33",
      "B. 18",
      "C. 23",
      "D. 46"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did baseball player Darryl Strawberry wear when he played for the Los Angeles Dodgers in the 1990s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "44",
    "choices": [
      "A. 44",
      "B. 39",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 18"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did American football quarterback Joe Montana wear when he played for the college team Notre Dame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 18",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 16",
      "D. 12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did O. J. Simpson, a member of the Pro Football Hall of Fame, wear when he played for the Buffalo Bills in the 70s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "32",
    "choices": [
      "A. 44",
      "B. 33",
      "C. 32",
      "D. 34"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Kirby Puckett,  who was elected to the Baseball Hall of Fame in 2001, wear when he was a player for the Minnesota Twins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "34",
    "choices": [
      "A. 14",
      "B. 34",
      "C. 32",
      "D. 18"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Carlton Fisk, who was inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame in 2000, wear when he played for the Chicago White Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "72",
    "choices": [
      "A. 27",
      "B. 72",
      "C. 15",
      "D. 13"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This college was first to have the first overall pick for both the NFL and the NBA in the same year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Utah",
    "choices": [
      "A. Notre Dame",
      "B. Texas",
      "C. Utah",
      "D. USC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two schools are given credit for playing the first college football game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Princeton - Rutgers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago - Ohio State",
      "B. UCLA - USC",
      "C. Princeton - Rutgers",
      "D. Purdue - Notre Dame"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In NCAA football, a conference can play a conference championship game if it has this many teams.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 16",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these bascetball players scored 100 points in one college game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Selvey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "B. Rod Thorn",
      "C. Frank Selvey",
      "D. Kareem Abdul Jabbar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For which college did Wilt Chamberlain play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Villanova",
      "B. Kansas",
      "C. UCLA",
      "D. North Carolina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For which college  did Reggie Jackson play baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arizona State",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida",
      "B. UCLA",
      "C. Texas",
      "D. Arizona State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which college used to have the nickname The Ramblin Wrecks?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Georgia Tech",
    "choices": [
      "A. Purdue",
      "B. Georgia Tech",
      "C. Texas Tech",
      "D. Oklahoma State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which college has the team nicknamed The Boiler Makers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Purdue",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida",
      "B. Purdue",
      "C. Miami",
      "D. Stanford"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which college has the team nicknamed The Sooners?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oklahoma",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Diego State",
      "B. Oklahoma",
      "C. Purdue",
      "D. Florida"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which college football team set the record for most consecutive wins, eventually losing to Notre Dame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oklahoma",
    "choices": [
      "A. Oklahoma",
      "B. USC",
      "C. Nebraska",
      "D. Army"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which three teams are eligible to win The Commanders Trophy ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Army, Navy and Air Force",
    "choices": [
      "A. Indiana, Purdue and Ball state.",
      "B. UCLA, USC and Stanford",
      "C. Harvard, Yale, and Princeton",
      "D. Army, Navy and Air Force"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former football quarterback, inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 1977, was the MVP of the first two Super Bowls?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bart Starr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Art Donovan",
      "B. Eric Dickerson",
      "C. Al Davis",
      "D. Bart Starr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former American football wide receiver, nicknamed Bambi, was inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 1978.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lance Alworth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Hutson",
      "B. Charlie Joiner",
      "C. Bobby Mitchell",
      "D. Lance Alworth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first person to become a member of both the Pro Football Hall of Fame and the Baseball Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cal Hubbard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cal Hubbard",
      "B. Jackie Jensen",
      "C. Dave Winfield",
      "D. Bo Jackson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former quarterback was named the Most Valuable Player of Super Bowl XXIX, and was inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Kelly",
      "B. Bobby Layne",
      "C. Norm Van Brocklin",
      "D. Steve Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which versatile athlete, inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 1963, won Olympic gold medals in the pentathlon and decathlon?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Thorpe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kirk Gibson",
      "B. Bo Jackson",
      "C. Jim Thorpe",
      "D. Jim Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This legendary Green Bay Packers head coach, inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame in 1971, had the following maxim: Winning isnt everything; its the only thing.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vince Lombardi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Noll",
      "B. Vince Lombardi",
      "C. Tom Landry",
      "D. Bill Parcells"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This retired cornerback, who played college football at Grambling University, was inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame on July 28, 1984.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "William Brown",
    "choices": [
      "A. Buck Buchanan",
      "B. William Brown",
      "C. Charlie Joiner",
      "D. Willie Davis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Henry Aaron hit home run number 715 off of which Dodger pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Al Downing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Drysdale",
      "B. Don Sutton",
      "C. Al Downing",
      "D. Sandy Koufax"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the Braves move to Atlanta?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1966",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1967",
      "B. 1965",
      "C. 1968",
      "D. 1966"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Chipper Jones actual first name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Larry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Peter",
      "B. Paul",
      "C. Larry",
      "D. George"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Atlanta Fulton County Stadium had what nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Launching Pad",
    "choices": [
      "A. Braveland",
      "B. The Hot-Lanta",
      "C. The Launching Pad",
      "D. The Homer Dome"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This pitcher ended Pete Roses 44 game hit streak in 1978 with a strikeout.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gene Garber",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Smoltz",
      "B. Bruce Sutter",
      "C. Pat Jarvis",
      "D. Gene Garber"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1996 World Series, this Braves player hit a home run in his first two at-bats.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Andruw Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Justice",
      "B. Andruw Jones",
      "C. Fred McGriff",
      "D. Chipper Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the winning pitcher in game six of the 1995 World Series, 1-0 victory over the Cleveland Indians?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Glavine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Avery",
      "B. Greg Maddux",
      "C. John Smoltz",
      "D. Tom Glavine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the first modern heavyweight boxing champion?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John L. Sullivan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Fotzsimmons",
      "B. Jimmy Ellis",
      "C. John L. Sullivan",
      "D. James J. Corbett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which boxing heavyweight champ was the subject of the movie The Great White Hope?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jack Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marvin Hart",
      "B. Jack Johnson",
      "C. Jersey Joe Walcott",
      "D. Tommy Burns"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who lost the boxing heavyweight championship to Joe Louis?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "James J. Braddock",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Dempsey",
      "B. James J. Braddock",
      "C. Jess Willard",
      "D. Max Baer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the only undefeated boxing heavyweight champ, later killed in an airplane accident?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rocky Marciano",
    "choices": [
      "A. Floyd Patterson",
      "B. Ezzard Charles",
      "C. Leon Spinks",
      "D. Rocky Marciano"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From whom did Muhammad Ali get the championship the first time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sonny Liston",
    "choices": [
      "A. Leon Spinks",
      "B. Cassius Clay",
      "C. Sonny Liston",
      "D. Floyd Patterson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did Muhammad Ali beat to get the boxing crown the second time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Foreman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Frazier",
      "B. Ernie Terrell",
      "C. George Foreman",
      "D. Ken Norton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which boxers shared the boxing heavyweight crown in 1978 ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ali, Norton, Spinks, Holmes and Ali",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ali, Spinks and Holmes",
      "B. Norton, Spinks, Holmes and  Dokes",
      "C. Ali and Norton",
      "D. Ali, Norton, Spinks, Holmes and Ali"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How did boxer James J. Braddock get most of his money?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "From Joe Louis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shipping",
      "B. Appearance fees",
      "C. From Joe Louis",
      "D. Boxing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country did boxing champion Lennox Lewis represent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "England",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ireland",
      "B. Canada",
      "C. Texas",
      "D. England"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Former NBA player, Michael Jeffrey Jordan was born on February 17, what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1963",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1965",
      "B. 1963",
      "C. 1960",
      "D. 1961"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the height of former NBA player, Michael Jordan?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6 6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 68",
      "B. 6 6",
      "C. 67",
      "D. 65"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Michael Jordan majored in geography at what university?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of North Carolina",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of North Carolina",
      "B. Duke University",
      "C. Arizona State University",
      "D. Florida State University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Former NBA player Michael Jordan won his second Olympic gold medal in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1992",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1992",
      "B. 1988",
      "C. 1996",
      "D. 1984"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did Michael Jordan wear after the return to NBA from his first retirement?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "45",
    "choices": [
      "A. 23",
      "B. 15",
      "C. 45",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On January 19, 2000, Jordan returned to the NBA not as a player, but as part owner and President of Basketball Operations of which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Washington Wizards",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Washington Wizards",
      "B. The Los Angeles Clippers",
      "C. The Indiana Pacers",
      "D. The Chicago Bulls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former catcher managed the New York Mets in 1973?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi Berra",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gil Hodges",
      "B. Joe Frazier",
      "C. Wes Westrum",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joining the team in 1962, this former infielder, manager and coach was the first 3rd baseman to play for the New York Mets.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Zimmer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wayne Garrett",
      "B. Don Zimmer",
      "C. Ed Charles",
      "D. Elliot Maddox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great pitcher of the New York Mets won the Rookie of the Year award in 1972 by going 15-10 with a 2.32 ERA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jon Matlack",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Koosman",
      "B. Tom Seaver",
      "C. Jon Matlack",
      "D. Nino Espinosa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This right-handed Major League Baseball player won the World Series MVP award, and then became the first player to sign with new team after winning the award, joining the Orioles in 1987.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ray Knight",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lenny Dykstra",
      "B. Dave Kingman",
      "C. Ray Knight",
      "D. Darryl Strawberry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Dominican Republic born baseball player, played shortstop for the New York Mets in 1979?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Taveras",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Phillips",
      "B. Frank Taveras",
      "C. Tim Foli",
      "D. Ray Sadecki"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former Major League Baseball shortstop, who at the time played for the New York Mets, got into a fight with Pete Rose during the 1973 playoffs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bud Harrelson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tim Foli",
      "B. Teddy Martinez",
      "C. Bud Harrelson",
      "D. Rafael Santana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former pitcher, manager and executive in Major League Baseball, who led the Philadelphia Phillies to their first World Series title in 1980, managed the New York Mets during 1993-96.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Green",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas Green",
      "B. Davey Johnson",
      "C. Joe Torre",
      "D. Bobby Valentine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became owner of  Major League Baseball, New york Mets in 1961?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joan Payson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nelson Doubleday",
      "B. Lorinda De Roulet",
      "C. Joan Payson",
      "D. M. Donald Grant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player, signed by the New York Yankees as an amateur free agent in 1976, played for the New York Mets during 1984-1987.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rafael Santana",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rafael Santana",
      "B. Kevin Elster",
      "C. Larry Bowa",
      "D. Al Pedrique"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After five seasons as a roving instructor for the Seattle Mariners, this man eventually got hired by the New York Mets as the pitching coach, a position he held for ten years.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mel Stottlemyre",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mel Stottlemyre",
      "B. Joe Pignatano",
      "C. Bob Apodaca",
      "D. Rube Walker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player and American national icon was known as The Sultan of Swat.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Christy Mathewson",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Lou Gehrig",
      "D. Cy Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which multiple MVP winner was called the Georgia Peach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ty Cobb",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson",
      "B. Ty Cobb",
      "C. Albert Belle",
      "D. Eddie Murray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Baseball Hall of Famer is known as The Splendid Splinter.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johnny Bench",
      "B. Ted Williams",
      "C. Joe DiMaggio",
      "D. Hank Aaron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Hall of Fame pitcher was known as Rapid Robert?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Feller",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Turley",
      "B. Bob Esposito",
      "C. Bob Miller",
      "D. Bob Feller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former baseball player, called The Ol Perfesser, left his mark on the game as a manager.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Casey Stengel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miller Huggins",
      "B. Earl Weaver",
      "C. Connie Mack",
      "D. Casey Stengel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player appeared in 14 World Series, won the American League MVP Award three times and was elected to the Hall of Fame in 1972. His given name is Lawrence Peter but hes better known under what nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dutch",
      "B. L.P.",
      "C. Yogi",
      "D. Larry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former baseball player called The Major won the World Series in his first two seasons as manager.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ralph Houk",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ralph Houk",
      "B. Earl Weaver",
      "C. Joe McCarthy",
      "D. Dick Howser"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player for the New York Mets was called Choo-Choo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Clarence Coleman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rusty Staub",
      "B. Jerry Grote",
      "C. Rod Kanehl",
      "D. Clarence Coleman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player, nicknamed True, was a three time 20-game winner for the Oakland As.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vida Blue",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Hunter",
      "B. Dennis Eckersley",
      "C. Vida Blue",
      "D. Rollie Fingers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New York Yankee pitcher was known as Louisiana Lightning?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Guidry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fritz Peterson",
      "B. Ron Guidry",
      "C. Bob Turley",
      "D. Mel Stottlemyre"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player, who started his career with the Texas Rangers in 1991 at the age of 19, is known as Pudge.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ivan Rodriguez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rusty Greer",
      "B. Alfonso Soriano",
      "C. Doug Mirabelli",
      "D. Ivan Rodriguez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dating back to 776 B.C., the ancient Olympic Games were held in the valley of Olympia in southwestern Greece, to honor this god.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zeus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Poseidon",
      "B. Hermes",
      "C. Zeus",
      "D. Apollo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person, widely regarded as the founder of the modern Olympic Games, presented his ideas of reviving the Olympics at a 1894 congress, held in Paris.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pierre de Coubertin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Father Henri Martin Didon",
      "B. Harold Abrahams",
      "C. Gaston Doumergue",
      "D. Pierre de Coubertin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The parade of the nations is part of the opening ceremony of the Olympic Games. Since the1928 Summer Olympics, which nation traditionally leads the parade?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greece",
    "choices": [
      "A. The first country in alphabetical order",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. The country with the most medals from the last Olympics",
      "D. The host country"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the most important symbols of the Olympic Games is the flag with five interlocking rings representing the unity of the continents. The rings appear in five colours, on white background. Why were the colours red, blue, green, yellow, and black chosen for the rings?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Because each country at that time had one of these colours in its national flag",
    "choices": [
      "A. Because each of these colours is a symbol of one of the continents",
      "B. Because these are the colours of Nature",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. Because each country at that time had one of these colours in its national flag"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During these Summer Olympics, 11 members of the Israeli team were taken hostage and later killed by Palestinian terrorists.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Munich 1972",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barcelona 1992",
      "B. Montreal 1976",
      "C. Munich 1972",
      "D. Los Angeles 1984"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This animal, possessing qualities such as resistance, strength and liveliness, was the first Olympic animal mascot, chosen for the1972 Munich Olympic games.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Waldi, the dachshund",
    "choices": [
      "A. Amik, the beaver",
      "B. Waldi, the dachshund",
      "C. Cobi, the dog",
      "D. Sam, the eagle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This advertising slogan of Nike triggered harsh criticism during the 1996 Olympic Games in Atlanta, because it was in contradiction with the Olympic principles.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "âYou donât win silver â you lose goldâ.",
    "choices": [
      "A. âExceed. Why compromise?â.",
      "B. âNobody is perfect. My name is nobodyâ.",
      "C. âYou donât win silver â you lose goldâ.",
      "D. âCommon sense. Uncommon resultsâ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person, president of the International Olympic Committee from 1980 to 2001, was criticised for widespread corruption in IOC members during his term, as well as for his ties with the former fascist government in his country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Juan Antonio Samaranch",
    "choices": [
      "A. Franco Carraro",
      "B. Thomas Bach",
      "C. Joao Havelange",
      "D. Juan Antonio Samaranch"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first official Winter Olympic games, initially called âThe International Winter Sports Week, were held in 1924 in this Alpine town.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chamonix",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bormio",
      "B. Chamonix",
      "C. Davos",
      "D. Kitzbuhel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The International Olympic Committee, created in June of 1894 to revive the Olympic Games, is the supreme authority of the Olympic Movement.  It is based in which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lausanne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lausanne",
      "B. Geneva",
      "C. Davos",
      "D. Paris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the wrestler that knocked Lilian Garcia off the ring apron during the 5th edition of RAW?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Charlie Haas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Charlie Haas",
      "B. Johnny Nitro",
      "C. Shelton Benjamin",
      "D. Kane"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which member of the McMahon family tried to drug Triple H backstage in one of the editions of  Raw?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shane McMahon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shane McMahon",
      "B. Linda McMahon",
      "C. Vince McMahon",
      "D. Stephanie McMahon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Amy  Dumas, an American professional wrestler, goes by what ring name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lita",
    "choices": [
      "A. Victoria",
      "B. Mickie James",
      "C. Candice Michelle",
      "D. Lita"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the second wrestler to become Mr. Money in the Bank?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "RVD",
    "choices": [
      "A. Edge",
      "B. Mick Foley",
      "C. Snitsky",
      "D. RVD"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1958, Ted Williams signed an extension with the Boston Red Sox to make him the highest paid player in Major League Baseball at the time. How much was it for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "$135,000",
    "choices": [
      "A. $206,000",
      "B. $73,000",
      "C. $527,000",
      "D. $135,000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Major League Baseball center fielder was the first player ever taken in an amateur draft by the Seattle Pilots.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gorman Thomas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tommy Davis",
      "B. Bob Coluccio",
      "C. Steve Hovley",
      "D. Gorman Thomas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Major League baseball player, who spent his career with the Chicago Cubs and St. Louis Cardinals, was elected to the Baseball Hall of Fame in 1985.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Brock",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Willie Stargell",
      "C. Lou Brock",
      "D. Red Schoendienst"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball star of the 1950s was the second black player to be signed by a Major League team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Larry Doby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Larry Doby",
      "B. Minnie Minoso",
      "C. Josh Gibson",
      "D. Satchel Paige"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball star won his only MVP award in 1923.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yogi Berra",
      "B. Willie Mays",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Roy Campanella"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Five players were elected to the Baseball Hall of Fame in the first balloting in 1936. The first four were Ty Cobb, Babe Ruth, Honus Wagner, Christy Mathewson. Who was the fifth inductee?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walter Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cy Young",
      "B. Walter Johnson",
      "C. Nap Lajoie",
      "D. Clark Griffith"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Barry Bonds hit the headlines since he became a rookie for which of these teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pirates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Giants",
      "B. Astros",
      "C. Mets",
      "D. Pirates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did Babe Ruth start his career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Red Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Braves",
      "B. Yankees",
      "C. White Sox",
      "D. Red Sox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ken Griffey Jr. has played with the Reds but which other team did he start his career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mariners",
    "choices": [
      "A. Red Sox",
      "B. Mariners",
      "C. Braves",
      "D. Cardinals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ernie Banks, known as Mr. Cub, started his career with which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cubs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pirates",
      "B. Giants",
      "C. Cubs",
      "D. Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams did Alex Rodriguez start his career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mariners",
    "choices": [
      "A. Angels",
      "B. Rangers",
      "C. Yankees",
      "D. Mariners"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jeff Bagwell was drafted by the Red Sox but started his career with which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Astros",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mets",
      "B. Orioles",
      "C. Astros",
      "D. Phillies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Murphy played his last game on May 21, 1993 for the Colorado Rockies and he started his career with which of these teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Braves",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mariners",
      "B. Phillies",
      "C. Reds",
      "D. Braves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Reggie Jackson was inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame in 1993. Which team did he start his career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Athletics",
    "choices": [
      "A. Athletics",
      "B. Angels",
      "C. Yankees",
      "D. Orioles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While Sammy Sosa gained most of his fame with the Cubs, which team did he debut for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rangers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cubs",
      "B. Rangers",
      "C. Orioles",
      "D. White Sox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Frank Robinson had a long and successful playing career. Which team did Frank debut with on April 17, 1956?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Reds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cardinals",
      "B. Reds",
      "C. Orioles",
      "D. Cubs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who of the following never played quarterback for Alabama Crimson Tide?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Archie Manning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bart Starr",
      "B. Joe Namath",
      "C. Kenny Stabler",
      "D. Archie Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This quarterback won the 1966 Heisman Trophy.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Spurrier",
    "choices": [
      "A. Archie Manning",
      "B. Steve Spurrier",
      "C. Joe Namath",
      "D. Bert Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Former Minnesota Viking and New York Giant quarterback Fran Tarkenton played for what SEC team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Georgia Bulldogs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida Gators",
      "B. LSU Tigers",
      "C. Tennessee Vols",
      "D. Georgia Bulldogs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1969 this quarterback passed for three touchdowns and 436 yards against Alabama, but the Tide won 33-32,\nwho is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Archie Manning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Spurrier",
      "B. Archie Manning",
      "C. Bert Jones",
      "D. Pat Sullivan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Auburns Pat Sullivan win the Heisman Trophy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1971",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1972",
      "B. 1970",
      "C. 1973",
      "D. 1971"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This quarterback won the 1996 Heisman Trophy.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Danny Wuerffel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Danny Wuerffel",
      "B. Peyton Manning",
      "C. Eli Manning",
      "D. Archie Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former college quarterback went on to play running back for the Dallas Cowboys and then became a head coach in the NFL.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dan Reeves",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bert Jones",
      "B. Dan Reeves",
      "C. Calvin Hill",
      "D. Robert Newhouse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following SEC quarterbacks, which one did not come in second in the Heisman Trophy voting?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eli Manning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Heath Shuler",
      "B. Peyton Manning",
      "C. Rex Grossman",
      "D. Eli Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Ben Wallace, signed by the Chicago Bulls in 2006, play college basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Virginia Union",
    "choices": [
      "A. Virginia Commonwealth",
      "B. Virginia Union",
      "C. UNC-Wilmington",
      "D. Iona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Scottie Pippen play college basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Central Arkansas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Texas Tech",
      "B. SE Oklahoma",
      "C. Central Arkansas",
      "D. Southern Mississippi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wally Szczerbiak , who spent much of his childhood in Europe, played basketball at what college?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miami (Ohio)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Indiana State",
      "B. Ball State",
      "C. Miami (Ohio)",
      "D. Bowling Green"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these basketball players did not attend the University of Arizona?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Desmond Mason",
    "choices": [
      "A. Loren Woods",
      "B. Desmond Mason",
      "C. Mike Bibby",
      "D. Michael Dickerson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Danny Granger played basketball at what college?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Mexico",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wyoming",
      "B. Colorado State",
      "C. Utah State",
      "D. New Mexico"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Brad Miller of the Sacramento Kings played basketball at what Big Ten University?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Purdue",
    "choices": [
      "A. Penn State",
      "B. Michigan State",
      "C. Wisconsin",
      "D. Purdue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Quentin Richardson, who signed with the New York Knicks in 2005, played college basketball at what school?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "DePaul",
    "choices": [
      "A. Memphis",
      "B. DePaul",
      "C. Missouri",
      "D. Cincinnati"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "NBA player Eddie Jones played college basketball at what school?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Temple",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston",
      "B. Alabama",
      "C. Temple",
      "D. Villanova"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did New Jersey Net guard Jason Kidd go to college?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "California",
    "choices": [
      "A. UCLA",
      "B. USC",
      "C. California",
      "D. Arizona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jason Williams, nicknamed White Chocolate, played college basketball at the University of Florida in 1998. What school did Williams play for before he transferred to Florida?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marshall",
    "choices": [
      "A. West Virginia",
      "B. Marshall",
      "C. Cincinnati",
      "D. Western Kentucky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former professional wrestler won the 1986 Slammy Award for Best Male Performance?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Junk Yard Dog",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hulk Hogan",
      "B. Roddy Piper",
      "C. Junk Yard Dog",
      "D. Mr. Wonderful"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Big John Studd wrestled for Fritz Von Erichs World Class promotion under which identity?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Captain USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Assassin",
      "B. Captain USA",
      "C. John Bolder",
      "D. Big Ben Caster"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first King of the Ring?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Murraco",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brett Hart",
      "B. Don Murraco",
      "C. Bob Orton",
      "D. Ted Dibiase"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the winner of the WWF champion vs. the NWA champion match in 1980?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Backlund",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harley Race",
      "B. Dusty Rhodes",
      "C. Ric Flair",
      "D. Bob Backlund"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Hulk Hogan had two title defences on Saturday Nights Main Event in 1985. Which of the listed wrestlers was one of his opponents?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cowboy Bob Orton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roddy Piper",
      "B. Cowboy Bob Orton",
      "C. Big John Studd",
      "D. Mr. Wonderful"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1979, this wrestler won the PWI Rookie of the year award, by the name of Sweet Brown Sugar. He went on to lose all three of his Wrestlemania appearances, and was a mid-carder at best in the WWF.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Koko B. Ware",
    "choices": [
      "A. Koko B. Ware",
      "B. Butch Reed",
      "C. Virgil",
      "D. Bad News Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which wrestler, winner of the PWI awards for most popular wrestler of the year, and most hated wrestler of the year, was also the first runner-up for the most inspirational wrestler of the year award in 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roddy Piper",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Undertaker",
      "B. Ric Flair",
      "C. Roddy Piper",
      "D. Randy Savage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the minor league baseball team, featured in the 1987 movie Long Gone starring William L. Peterson?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tampico Stogies",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Pete. Cardinals",
      "B. Tampico Stogies",
      "C. Tampa Cigars",
      "D. St. Peter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the film Mr. Baseball, Tom Selleck portrays an aging New York Yankees player who is traded to what Japanese baseball team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nagoya Chunichi Dragons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seibu Lions",
      "B. Yomiuri Giants",
      "C. Nagoya Chunichi Dragons",
      "D. Nippon Ham Fighters"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the the Southeastern Conference (SEC) receive permission from the NCAA to conduct an annual championship game in football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1992",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1990",
      "B. 1991",
      "C. 1992",
      "D. 1993"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two teams played the first overtime game in the history of Division-I college football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Toledo and Nevada",
    "choices": [
      "A. Toledo and Nevada",
      "B. Arkansas and Ole Miss",
      "C. Washington and Washington State",
      "D. Auburn and Georgia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Charles Woodson, who won the Heisman trophy in 1997, played in what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cornerback",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wide Receiver",
      "B. Quarterback",
      "C. Cornerback",
      "D. Halfback"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before becoming head coach of the University of Alabama football team, Paul Bear Bryant was head coach of three other university teams. Name the team which he did not coach.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Texas Tech",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kentucky",
      "B. Texas AM",
      "C. Maryland",
      "D. Texas Tech"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the head coach at Florida State, who preceded Bobby Bowden?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Darrell Mudra",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill McCartney",
      "B. None Of These",
      "C. Darrell Mudra",
      "D. Lee Corso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This man, who was head coach at The Ohio State University for 28 years, delivered the following words: There was no one who had better people than I did, or better football players. And, we outworked the other teams.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Woody Hayes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Knute Rockne",
      "B. Dan Devine",
      "C. Woody Hayes",
      "D. Lou Holtz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite losing the 1950 World series in four straight games, this baseball team was nicknamed The Whiz Kids.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phillies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dodgers",
      "B. Braves",
      "C. Phillies",
      "D. Cubs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NHL team was nicknamed The Broad Street Bullies during their first ever winning season in 1973.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Philadelphia Flyers",
    "choices": [
      "A. The New York Rangers",
      "B. The Chicago Blackhawks",
      "C. The Philadelphia Flyers",
      "D. The St Louis Blues"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From 1962-1968, this baseball team was known by the nickname, The Lovable Losers, but in 1969 a miracle happened and they won the World Series.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Mets",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Mets",
      "B. The Giants",
      "C. The Reds",
      "D. The Pirates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the nickname of The Atlanta Braves?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Bravos",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Georgians",
      "B. The Peaches",
      "C. Teds Boys",
      "D. The Bravos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When keeping a box score of a baseball game, what is the number of the catcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about the position of the catcher in baseball is true?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The catcher is the only player in professional sports who is in foul territory before each play.",
    "choices": [
      "A. There is no limit on the maximum size for a catchers mitt.",
      "B. The catcher is the only player in professional sports who is in foul territory before each play.",
      "C. The catcher almost always bats last or next to last.",
      "D. Every team is required to have at least three catchers on their roster."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was the first catcher in the history of professional baseball to play close to the batter.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Charles Zimmer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willard Hershberger",
      "B. Larry McLean",
      "C. Nat Hicks",
      "D. Charles Zimmer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first catcher in the history of baseball to wear a mask?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fred Thayer, 1877",
    "choices": [
      "A. Muddy  Ruel , 1924",
      "B. Fred Thayer, 1877",
      "C. Bill Lennon, 1871",
      "D. Hank Gowdy, 1917"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On June 28, 1907, this Yankees catcher was unable to throw out any of the 13 Washington Senators who stole second base.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Branch Rickey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Branch Rickey",
      "B. Ray Schalk",
      "C. John McGraw",
      "D. Casey Stengel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1960, the New York Yankees set a record for having three catchers each of whom hit at least twenty home runs. Who were they?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi Berra, Elston Howard, Johnny Blanchard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yogi Berra, Elston Howard, Thurmon Munson",
      "B. Yogi Berra, Sammy White, Elston Howard",
      "C. Yogi Berra, Elston Howard, Hank  Bauer",
      "D. Yogi Berra, Elston Howard, Johnny Blanchard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did baseball catchers first started using chest protectors?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1885",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1895",
      "B. 1915",
      "C. 1905",
      "D. 1885"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company was the first to start producing catchers mitts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Draper and Maynard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bresnahan",
      "B. Draper and Maynard",
      "C. Wilson",
      "D. Rawlings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1914, this catcher broke the record for throwing out base runners in an inning.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Les Nunamaker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve ONeil",
      "B. Les Nunamaker",
      "C. Muddy  Reul",
      "D. Bill Dickey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first catcher to catch 4 no-hitters in his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ray Schalk",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ray Schalk",
      "B. Bill Dickey",
      "C. Jorge Posada",
      "D. Johnny Bench"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first catcher to win both the Silver Slugger Award (Best Hitter at his position) and Golden Glove Award (Best fielder at his position) in the same year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ivan Rodriguez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ivan Rodriguez",
      "B. Johnny Bench",
      "C. Carleton Fisk",
      "D. Roy Campanella"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these statements about famous baseball catchers is incorrect?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Piazza was the first catcher to hit 50 homers and 200 hits in a season",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yogi Berra hit the first pinch hit home run in the World Series",
      "B. Mike Piazza was the first catcher to hit 50 homers and 200 hits in a season",
      "C. Clint Courtney was the first catcher to wear glasses",
      "D. Clint Courtney was the first catcher to wear an oversized mitt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This football player turned actor appeared in four Rocky movies playing boxer Apollo Creed.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carl Weathers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fred Williamson",
      "B. Carl Williamson",
      "C. Carl Weathers",
      "D. Fred Weathers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the first Super Bowl played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1967",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1965",
      "B. 1966",
      "C. 1967",
      "D. 1968"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won Super Bowl III in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Colts",
      "B. Browns",
      "C. Jets",
      "D. Packers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team won their second consecutive Super Bowl on January 13th, 1974.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dolphins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dolphins",
      "B. Packers",
      "C. Steelers",
      "D. Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team was the first team to win four Super Bowls?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steelers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steelers",
      "B. Rams",
      "C. Cowboys",
      "D. 49ers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did the Dallas Cowboys beat to win Super Bowl XXX?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steelers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bears",
      "B. Steelers",
      "C. Packers",
      "D. Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won Super Bowl XXXII?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Broncos",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steelers",
      "B. Broncos",
      "C. Packers",
      "D. Seahawks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first references to indoor billiards date back to this century, when the game became especially fashionable among royalties.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "15th century",
    "choices": [
      "A. 13th century",
      "B. 15th century",
      "C. 10th century",
      "D. 7th century"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pool, also known as pocket billiards, is the most popular variation of billiards in which country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "United States",
    "choices": [
      "A. United Kingdom",
      "B. Germany",
      "C. Australia",
      "D. United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these variations of the game of billiards uses the biggest playing tables?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Snooker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Straight Pool",
      "B. Carom Billiards",
      "C. Snooker",
      "D. Rotation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In most variations of the game of billiards, chalk is applied on what?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The cue tip",
    "choices": [
      "A. The table",
      "B. The cue tip",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. The players hands"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Eight ball, a popular type of pool in United States and United Kingdom, is played with this number of balls (excluding the cue ball).",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fifteen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nine",
      "B. Sixteen",
      "C. Eight",
      "D. Fifteen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "World Confederation of Billiard Sports (WCBS), the international governing centre of billiards, snooker, and pool, is headquartered in what country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Switzerland",
    "choices": [
      "A. United States",
      "B. France",
      "C. Switzerland",
      "D. United Kingdom"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the game of billiards, what situation does the term Double kiss refer to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A coloured ball rebounding in a rail and striking the cue ball that has just hit it",
    "choices": [
      "A. A shot intended to separate two closely clung balls",
      "B. A shot pocketing two balls at the same time",
      "C. A coloured ball rebounding in a rail and striking the cue ball that has just hit it",
      "D. A shot with the cue ball being very closely clung to another ball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these distinguished American presidents home concealed a secret billiards room?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Thomas Jefferson",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Washington",
      "B. Thomas Jefferson",
      "C. Theodore Roosevelt",
      "D. Abraham Lincoln"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what time of the year is the US Open held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "August / September",
    "choices": [
      "A. May / June",
      "B. June / July",
      "C. August / September",
      "D. January"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which New York area does the US Open take place?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Queens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brooklyn",
      "B. Staten Island",
      "C. Bronx",
      "D. Queens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these cities does not host any Tennis Masters Series tournaments?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "London",
    "choices": [
      "A. London",
      "B. Rome",
      "C. Monaco",
      "D. Madrid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the Grand Slams has not been won by Pete Sampras?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roland Garros",
    "choices": [
      "A. US Open",
      "B. Roland Garros",
      "C. Wimbledon",
      "D. Australian Open"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nick Bollettieri is one of the most famous tennis coaches. Where is his training campus located?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Florida",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida",
      "B. New York",
      "C. California",
      "D. Arizona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andre Agassi won first position in singles rankings for the first time in his career in this year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1995",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1992",
      "B. 1993",
      "C. 1995",
      "D. 1997"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This tennis players nickname is Mr Boom Boom.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boris Becker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Sampras",
      "B. Ivan Lendl",
      "C. Michael Cheng",
      "D. Boris Becker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The other name of Queens Club Championship is this.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stella Artois Championship",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sony Championship",
      "B. Stella Artois Championship",
      "C. Vodafone Championship",
      "D. Davis Cup"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first high-profile tennis player to be caught with a banned substance.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Petr Korda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Petr Korda",
      "B. Jim Courier",
      "C. Marcelo Rios",
      "D. Goran Ivanisevic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Terry Bradshaw was a quarterback for which of the following teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steelers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Falcons",
      "B. Giants",
      "C. Eagles",
      "D. Steelers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For which of these teams did Troy Aikman play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cowboys",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cowboys",
      "B. Cardinals",
      "C. Seahawks",
      "D. Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dick Butkus was a great middle linebacker for which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ravens",
      "B. Steelers",
      "C. Bears",
      "D. Redskins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From 1983-1998 John Elway was the starting quarterback for which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Broncos",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jets",
      "B. Broncos",
      "C. Packers",
      "D. Rams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob Griese was the quarterback for which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dolphins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Saints",
      "B. Vikings",
      "C. Patriots",
      "D. Dolphins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lawrence Taylor played his entire career for which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Giants",
    "choices": [
      "A. Raiders",
      "B. Chargers",
      "C. Packers",
      "D. Giants"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lynn Swann was a wide receiver for which N.F.L. team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steelers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steelers",
      "B. Colts",
      "C. Dolphins",
      "D. Bengals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Walter Payton played for this team from 1975 - 1987.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. Browns",
      "B. Bears",
      "C. Seahawks",
      "D. Bengals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In his rookie season Dan Marino was the starting quarterback for which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dolphins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dolphins",
      "B. Cowboys",
      "C. Chargers",
      "D. Saints"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jim Brown was a fullback from 1957 - 1965 and was elected to the Hall Of Fame in 1971. Which team did he play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Browns",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jets",
      "B. Browns",
      "C. Packers",
      "D. Steelers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of the University of Pennsylvania?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Quakers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Owls",
      "B. Quakers",
      "C. Lions",
      "D. Wildcats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the football teams of Syracuse, Alabama, and Penn State have in common in 1965?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All three had the players number on their helmets",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were the only unbeaten teams in Div I football",
      "B. All three had the players number on their helmets",
      "C. All three averaged more than 500 yds offense per game",
      "D. All three had assistant coaches elevated to head coaches before midseason"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these teams is not in the Big Ten Conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Iowa State",
    "choices": [
      "A. Iowa State",
      "B. Illinois",
      "C. Penn State",
      "D. Michigan State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which SEC member is not in the SEC East Division?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Auburn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Auburn",
      "B. Florida",
      "C. South Carolina",
      "D. Tennessee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of The Citadel, the Military College of South Carolina?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bulldogs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bulldogs",
      "B. Cadets",
      "C. Falcons",
      "D. Rebels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The football team of Long Beach State is a member of which conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "none of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. MWC",
      "B. West Coast Conference",
      "C. none of these",
      "D. WAC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these schools is not a Div I or I-AA member in football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Dakota U",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boise State",
      "B. Montana",
      "C. Wyoming",
      "D. South Dakota U"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the very first manager of The Undertaker?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brother Love",
    "choices": [
      "A. Captain Lou Albano",
      "B. Brother Love",
      "C. Paul Bearer",
      "D. Mr. Fiji"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did Steve Austin mock backstage during a promotional shoot for Extreme Championship Wrestling?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hulk Hogan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Macho Man Randy Savage",
      "B. Hulk Hogan",
      "C. Kevin Nash",
      "D. Eric Bischoff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was The Rocks tag team partner when he battled Evolution at Wrestlemania XX?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mick Foley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stone Cold Steve Austin",
      "B. Mick Foley",
      "C. Ric Flair",
      "D. Hulk Hogan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before becoming Umaga, what gimmick did Eddie Fatu wrestle under?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jamal of 3 minute warning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Fatu",
      "B. Superfly Eddie Fatu",
      "C. Jamal of 3 minute warning",
      "D. Rosey of 3 minute warning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two wrestlers helped Yokozuna retain the WWE Championship in the first ever casket match.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Jarrett and Diesel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jeff Jarrett and Diesel",
      "B. Vince and Shane McMahon",
      "C. Matt and Jeff Hardy",
      "D. Kane and Big Show"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the three members of the original Team Xtreme.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Hardy, Matt Hardy, Lita",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sable, Torrie Wilson, Dawn Marie",
      "B. Jeff Hardy, Matt Hardy, Lita",
      "C. Shannon Moore, Matt Hardy, Crash Holly",
      "D. Matt Hardy, Lita, Shannon Moore"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is George Herman Ruths nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe",
      "B. Magic",
      "C. Oh Yeah",
      "D. The Splendid Splinter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Guess the nickname of Henry Aaron, who played with the Braves and Brewers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hammerin Hank",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hammerin Hank",
      "B. Bustem Hank",
      "C. Hit em Where They Aint Hank",
      "D. Sluggen Hank"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of Walter Johnson, one of the top pitchers of his era?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Big Train",
    "choices": [
      "A. Big Train",
      "B. Wonderful Walter",
      "C. Wicked Walter",
      "D. Shut em Down Time"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Mordecai Browns nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Three Fingers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Black and Blue Brown",
      "B. Music Mordecai",
      "C. Three Fingers",
      "D. Whizzer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Guess the nickname of Ty Cobb, who Won the Triple Crown in 1909.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Georgia Peach",
    "choices": [
      "A. Georgia On My Mind",
      "B. Kernal Cobb",
      "C. The Georgia Peach",
      "D. Corn on the Cobb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "His name is Lawrence Peter Berra but most people know him by this nickname.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pudge",
      "B. Stumpy",
      "C. Yogi",
      "D. Bump"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Carlton Fisk was best known by what nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pudge",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sweets",
      "B. Hoppy",
      "C. Minor",
      "D. Pudge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Guess the nickname of Henry Louis Gehrig.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Iron Horse",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Iron Horse",
      "B. Joltin Joe",
      "C. Swish",
      "D. Hank"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Reginald Martinez Jackson, who started his career with the As, earned what nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mr. October",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cool Reggie",
      "B. Mr. October",
      "C. Billys Headache",
      "D. Mr. Mouth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Carl Michael Yastrzemski, who played his entire career with the Boston Red Sox, was best known for what nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yaz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yaz",
      "B. King",
      "C. Rovin Carl",
      "D. Mr. April"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Detroit Tigers won the World Series in which of the following years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1984",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1972",
      "B. 1984",
      "C. 1971",
      "D. 1983"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the Pittsburgh Pirates win the World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1960",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1963",
      "B. 1960",
      "C. 1961",
      "D. 1962"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Cincinnati Reds, a Major League Baseball, became World Champions in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1975",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1975",
      "B. 1977",
      "C. 1973",
      "D. 1970"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the Oakland Athletics win their first of three consecutive World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1972",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1971",
      "B. 1969",
      "C. 1970",
      "D. 1972"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pittsburgh Pirates, nicknamed The Bucs, won  which World Series in the 1970s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1979",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1978",
      "B. 1979",
      "C. 1977",
      "D. 1976"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which World Series did the New York Yankees become world champions led by Mantle and Berra?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1958",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1957",
      "B. 1960",
      "C. 1959",
      "D. 1958"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Milwaukee Braves won the World Series in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1957",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1957",
      "B. 1954",
      "C. 1956",
      "D. 1955"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the New York Giants win the World Series over the Cleveland Indians?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1954",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1959",
      "B. 1951",
      "C. 1956",
      "D. 1954"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did The New York Mets win their first World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1969",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1968",
      "B. 1970",
      "C. 1973",
      "D. 1969"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the Los Angeles Dodgers win the fall classic led by Fernando Valenzuela?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1981",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1983",
      "B. 1982",
      "C. 1980",
      "D. 1981"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which auto racing driver became the 2005 Nextel Cup Champion?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Stewart",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carl Edwards",
      "B. Jimmie Johnson",
      "C. Jeff Gordon",
      "D. Tony Stewart"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt Jr., the son of NASCAR legend Dale Earnhardt, had how many wins in the 2005 NASCAR season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This professional NASCAR driver, winner of the 1989 Winston Cup Championship, retired after the 2005 NASCAR Nextel Cup season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rusty Wallace",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mark Martin",
      "B. Rusty Wallace",
      "C. Ricky Rudd",
      "D. Ken Schrader"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NASCAR Nextel Cup Series and Busch Series driver won the 2005 Golden Corral 500.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carl Edwards",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Stewart",
      "B. Bobby Labonte",
      "C. Jimmie Johnson",
      "D. Carl Edwards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mike Schmidt starred with the Phillies at what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. Shortstop",
      "C. Pitcher",
      "D. Third Base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Probably the greatest player of all time at his position, Johnny Bench was elected to the Hall of Fame in 1989.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Catcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. Left Field",
      "C. Shortstop",
      "D. Right Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Brooks Robinson was considered the human vacuum cleaner at his position.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. First Base",
      "B. Shortstop",
      "C. Third Base",
      "D. Second Base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe Morgan became an instant star when he was traded to the Reds. What was his position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Second Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Third Base",
      "B. Catcher",
      "C. Second Base",
      "D. Center Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While playing with different teams throughout his career, Eddie Murray was great at what position mostly with the Orioles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "First Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. First Base",
      "B. Left Field",
      "C. Center Field",
      "D. Second Base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "George Herman Ruth, better known as the Babe, usually played this position.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Right Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. Left Field",
      "C. Right Field",
      "D. Center Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Hammerin Hank Aaron primarily played which of these positions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Right Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shortstop",
      "B. Right Field",
      "C. Second Base",
      "D. Pitcher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While starting his career with the Red Sox, it was with the Yankees that Wade Boggs won the World Series. Where did you usually see Wade play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Left Field",
      "B. Third Base",
      "C. Shortstop",
      "D. Right Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kansas City Royalss player George Brett starred at this position.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catcher",
      "B. Third Base",
      "C. Pitcher",
      "D. Center Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Roy Campanella starred for the Brooklyn Dodgers during the 1950s at which position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Catcher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Second Base",
      "B. First Base",
      "C. Catcher",
      "D. Designated Hitter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was the Hall of Fame first baseman for the Minnesota Twins.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harmon Killebrew",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Ken Stabler",
      "C. Jeff Bagwell",
      "D. Harmon Killebrew"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Hall of Famer played first base with the Cincinnati Reds?.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Perez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Perez",
      "B. Bill Madlock",
      "C. John Roseboro",
      "D. Bill Maddox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This first baseman, member of the Hall of Fame, was a main cog of the New York Yankees.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Gehrig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Gehrig",
      "B. Mickey Mantle",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Hall of Famer played primarily for the Baltimore Orioles at first base.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eddie Murray",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Perez",
      "B. Al Newton",
      "C. Eddie Murray",
      "D. Jim Palmer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This power hitting Hall of Famer played at first base primarily with the San Francisco Giants.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie McCovey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Juan Marichal",
      "B. Willie Mays",
      "C. Bobby Bonds",
      "D. Willie McCovey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Hall of Famer played for The Philadelphia Athletics from 1925 to 1935.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmie Foxx",
    "choices": [
      "A. Connie Mack",
      "B. Roger Breece",
      "C. Jimmie Foxx",
      "D. Clay Jointer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Hall of Fame first baseman played for the Chicago Cubs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Chance",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tom Stephens",
      "B. Frank Chance",
      "C. Sammy Sosa",
      "D. Ron Santo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these Hall of Famers played first base for the Detroit Tigers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Greenberg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alan Trammel",
      "B. Hank Greenberg",
      "C. Denny McLain",
      "D. Al Kaline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Hall of Fame first baseman played with the New York Giants from 1923 to 1936 and was their manager in the period 1932-1941.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Terry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Flowers",
      "B. Bob Schultes",
      "C. Bill Terry",
      "D. Rocky Nelson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these Hall of Famers was first baseman for the San Francisco Giants?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Orlando Cepeda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Mayes",
      "B. Bobby Sutter",
      "C. Jocko Thomas",
      "D. Orlando Cepeda"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "One of these is an unusual hazard on the golf course.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ice",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ice",
      "B. Water",
      "C. Sand",
      "D. Trees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Golf originated in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scotland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ireland",
      "B. England",
      "C. Scotland",
      "D. Wales"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Legend of Bagger Vance (2000) is a popular Hollywood production, depicting the story of a fictional golf player who had lost his swing and found it again. Who played his role?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Matt Damon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Will Smith",
      "B. Dustin Hoffman",
      "C. Brad Pitt",
      "D. Matt Damon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The putting green refers to this.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The area around the actual hole",
    "choices": [
      "A. The area where the ball is first hit (starting position)",
      "B. The area around water hazards like ponds, lakes, etc.",
      "C. The area around the actual hole",
      "D. The area around sand traps"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Par is the theoretical number of strokes that an expert golfer should require for playing the ball into any given hole. If the distance from the starting position to the hole is 225 m - 434 m, then the par is this.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 6",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Atlanta Braves traded Doyle Alexander to the Detroit Tigers on August 12, 1987, for which player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Smoltz",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Smoltz",
      "B. Tom Glavine",
      "C. Greg Maddux",
      "D. Steve Avery"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It is widely known that the New York Mets traded Tom Seaver on June 15, 1977. Who else did the Mets trade that same day?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dave Kingman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Torre",
      "B. Bobby Valentine",
      "C. Dave Kingman",
      "D. Doug Flynn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In June 1964 the St. Louis Cardinals traded Bobby Shantz, Ernie Broglio and Doug Clemens to the Chicago Cubs for which future Hall of Famer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Brock",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Gibson",
      "B. Lou Brock",
      "C. Ernie Banks",
      "D. Ryne Sandberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After the 1981 season, the St. Louis Cardinals and the San Diego Padres swapped which shortstops?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ozzie Smith and Garry Templeton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ozzie Smith and Royce Clayton",
      "B. Jose Oquendo and Jerry Royster",
      "C. Garry Templeton and Dave Concepcion",
      "D. Ozzie Smith and Garry Templeton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The New York Yankees got pitcher Bob Sykes in return for this two time batting champion.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie McGee",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fred McGriff",
      "B. Jay Buhner",
      "C. Bill Madlock",
      "D. Willie McGee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Philadelphia Phillies gave up on this Hall of Famer after just 13 games, trading him to the Chicago Cubs for Ivan DeJesus.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ryne Sandberg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ryne Sandberg",
      "B. Scott Rolen",
      "C. Billy Williams",
      "D. Ron Cey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This southpaw was traded by the Yankees for Roger Clemens.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Wells",
    "choices": [
      "A. Terry Forster",
      "B. Fernando Valenzuela",
      "C. Sid Fernandez",
      "D. David Wells"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pete Rose was traded once in his career for which of these players?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Lawless",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Boone",
      "B. Tom Lawless",
      "C. Tim Flannery",
      "D. Tim Foli"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After the 1974 season, the Milwaukee Brewers traded Dave May and Roger Alexander for this slugger.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Henry Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Robin Yount",
      "B. Gorman Thomas",
      "C. Willie Mays",
      "D. Henry Aaron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This box-office heavyweight has portrayed numerous athlete-heroes in his movie career, but in real life his favorite competitive sport is auto racing.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Newman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Woody Allen",
      "B. Robert Redford",
      "C. Paul Newman",
      "D. Tom Cruise"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before he won the world welterweight boxing championship, and long before he had any acting experience, Brooklyns Mark Breland was tapped to debut in this military-school drama.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Lords of Discipline",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Lords of Flatbush",
      "B. Taps",
      "C. Lords of Dogtown",
      "D. The Lords of Discipline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the common links connecting the Boston Red Sox, the film Capote and the TV series Homicide?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The sister of a Red Sox executive produced Homicide, and her husband wrote Capote.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The movie and TV show included major scenes in Fenway Park.",
      "B. The movie and show were produced by Ted Williams nephew.",
      "C. The sister of a Red Sox executive produced Homicide, and her husband wrote Capote.",
      "D. Truman Capote looked divine in red."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which popular author and screenwriter is also widely known as a devoted Red Sox fan and has co-written a book entitled Faithful: Two Diehard Boston Red Sox Fans Chronicle the Historic 2004 Season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stephen King",
    "choices": [
      "A. F. Scott Fitzgerald",
      "B. John Grisham",
      "C. W.P. Kinsella",
      "D. Stephen King"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which leading man in a popular TV Western series briefly played both professional baseball and basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Connors",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Connors",
      "B. Lorne Greene",
      "C. Dennis Weaver",
      "D. James Arness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Former UCLA and Rams lineman Woody Strode fought a brief but memorable arena battle as a gladiator in what famous movie?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spartacus",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Professionals",
      "B. Gladiator",
      "C. Ben Hur",
      "D. Spartacus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After reigning as the world light-heavyweight boxing champion from 1932-34, this pugilist proceeded to transform himself  into one of the first and most successful athletes-turned-actors in Hollywood history.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maxie Rosenbloom",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maxie Rosenbloom",
      "B. Max Baer, Sr",
      "C. Max Headroom",
      "D. Max Baer, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Among Hollywoods athletic box-office stars, this Florida boy probably boasts the most accomplished college-football career of any major movie star.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Burt Reynolds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Burt Reynolds",
      "B. PeeWee Herman",
      "C. Kevin Costner",
      "D. Tom Selleck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before he nailed down his macho movie career, this African-American actor was known on the gridiron as The Hammer. He played for the Oakland Raiders, then for the Kansas City Chiefs in the first-ever Super Bowl.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fred Williamson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gary Coleman",
      "B. Denzel Washington",
      "C. Bernie Casey",
      "D. Fred Williamson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these real-life jockeys, chosen as one of People Magazines 50 Most Beautiful People in 2003, played another real-life jockey in Seabiscuit?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gary Stevens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Julie Krone",
      "B. Edgar Prado",
      "C. Billy Barty",
      "D. Gary Stevens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams does not have the color blue in their logo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Atlanta Falcons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta Falcons",
      "B. New York Islanders",
      "C. Washington Capitals",
      "D. Charlotte Bobcats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Kentucky Derby takes place yearly in Louisville, on which day?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "First Saturday in May",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fourth of July",
      "B. First Saturday in May",
      "C. Any day chosen by the owners",
      "D. Midsummers Eve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the distance, covered by the Kentucky Derby?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mile and one quarter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mile and one quarter",
      "B. Mile and one sixteenth",
      "C. Two miles",
      "D. Mile and a half"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The thoroughbred horses that run at the Kentucky Derby must be at what age?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Three years old",
    "choices": [
      "A. Two years old",
      "B. Any age",
      "C. Three years old",
      "D. Yearlings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Kentucky Derby is held at which racetrack?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Churchill Downs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Churchill Downs",
      "B. Santa Anita",
      "C. Aqueduct",
      "D. Saratoga"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What other name was given to the Kentucky Derby?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Run for the Roses",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Run for Glory",
      "B. The Fastest Two Minutes in Sport",
      "C. The Run for the Roses",
      "D. The Kentucky Speed Trial"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many horses are allowed to run in the Kentucky Derby?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "20",
    "choices": [
      "A. 15",
      "B. 20",
      "C. 18",
      "D. Unlimited number"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The award for the top pitcher in each of the two major leagues is named after which Hall of Fame pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cy Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cy Young",
      "B. Don Drysdale",
      "C. Tom Seaver",
      "D. None Of These"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Hall of Fame pitcher was best known as Dizzy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jay Dean",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Dean",
      "B. Jay Dean",
      "C. Paul Dean",
      "D. Don Dean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did Dennis Eckersley start his career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleveland Indians",
    "choices": [
      "A. Oakland As",
      "B. Cincinnati Reds",
      "C. Cleveland Indians",
      "D. San Diego Padres"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did Jim Catfish Hunter start his major league career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas City",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Diego",
      "B. Baltimore",
      "C. Cincinnati",
      "D. Kansas City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1996, this golf player, known as The Golden Bear, became the first person in the history of the PGA to win the same Senior PGA Tour event four times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jack Nicklaus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Nicklaus",
      "B. Jesper Parnevik",
      "C. Ben Hogan",
      "D. Tiger Woods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In golf, this type of shot is the first shot played from a teeing ground and is usually made with a driver.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "tee shot",
    "choices": [
      "A. chip",
      "B. bunker shot",
      "C. tee shot",
      "D. flop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL teams logo is a horseshoe?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Colts",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bears",
      "B. Ravens",
      "C. Colts",
      "D. Falcons"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL football team won the first two Super Bowls in a row?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Green Bay Packers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta Falcons",
      "B. Carolina Panthers",
      "C. New England Patriots",
      "D. Green Bay Packers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL team went 16-0 for the 2007 season and lost to the New York Giants in the Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New England Patriots",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Jets",
      "B. New England Patriots",
      "C. The Green Bay Packers",
      "D. Carolina Panthers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL football team has a lightening bolt logo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Diego Chargers",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Diego Chargers",
      "B. Atlanta Falcons",
      "C. New York Giants",
      "D. St. Louis Rams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played quarterback for the New York Jets from 2000-2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chad Pennington",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dan Marino",
      "B. Chad Pennington",
      "C. Brett Farve",
      "D. Tom Brady"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was running back for the Atlanta Falcons from 2002-2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Warrick Dunn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Warrick Dunn",
      "B. Cory Dillion",
      "C. Shaun Alexander",
      "D. Tiki Barber"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL wide receiver was drafted by the Colts in 1996?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marvin Harrison",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Rice",
      "B. Terrell Owens",
      "C. Pearless Price",
      "D. Marvin Harrison"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL football team had the second to worst record in 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "St. Louis Rams",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Tennessee Titans",
      "B. Green Bay Packers",
      "C. Atlanta Falcons",
      "D. St. Louis Rams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He played for the Boston Bruins from 1966 to 1976.  On May 10, 1970 he scored an amazing goal diving through the air after being tripped, giving Boston its first Stanley Cup in 29 years.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Orr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Phil Espeszito",
      "B. Wayne Greztky",
      "C. Gordie Howe",
      "D. Bobby Orr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former professional ice hokey player, known as The Great One, is widely accepted as the greatest player to ever play the game of hockey.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wayne Gretzky",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wayne Gretzky",
      "B. Bobby Orr",
      "C. Paul Kariya",
      "D. Mike Modano"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the last hockey player to be cut from the 1980 USA Olympic team by coach Herb Brooks, and what college team did he play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ralph Cox - UNH",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ralph Ocallahan - UNH",
      "B. Ralph Ocallahan - BU",
      "C. Ralph Cox - UNH",
      "D. Ralph Cox - BU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first Asian city to host the Olympics, in 1964?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tokyo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seoul",
      "B. Tokyo",
      "C. Nagano",
      "D. Sapporo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city hosted the first modern Olympiad in 1896?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Athens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Athens",
      "B. Rome",
      "C. Paris",
      "D. Moscow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where were the winter Olympics held in 1960, the first time the host country won the gold medal in ice hockey?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Squaw Valley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Oslo",
      "B. Squaw Valley",
      "C. Calgary",
      "D. Lake Placid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Berlin host the Olympics, allowing Germany to use the event as a Nazi propaganda tool?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1936",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1944",
      "B. 1932",
      "C. 1936",
      "D. 1940"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city hosted the first Olympics not held in a leap year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paris",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paris",
      "B. Nagano",
      "C. Lillehammer",
      "D. Sydney"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ice hockey was first played in the 1920 Olympics, which were held in what city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Antwerp",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montreal",
      "B. Antwerp",
      "C. Chamonix",
      "D. Lake Placid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the following countries, which one did NOT host both the winter and summer Olympics in the same year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Japan",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. Germany",
      "C. Japan",
      "D. United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1970, the American city of Denver was selected to host the 1976 winter Olympics, but the Games were moved to Innsbruck instead. Why?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Coloradans voted not to pay the expenses associated with hosting the Olympics.",
    "choices": [
      "A. A massive strike by construction workers made it impossible to finish all the facilities in time.",
      "B. The International Olympic Committee rescinded their decision when proof of bribery came to light.",
      "C. Several countries threatened to boycott the games because of the U.S. involvement in Vietnam.",
      "D. Coloradans voted not to pay the expenses associated with hosting the Olympics."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When were the Olympics held south of the equator?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1956 and 2000",
    "choices": [
      "A. Never",
      "B. 1996 and 2000",
      "C. 1952 and 2004",
      "D. 1956 and 2000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city has been chosen to host the 2012 Olympics, thus becoming the first three-time Olympic host city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "London",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paris",
      "B. Innsbruck",
      "C. London",
      "D. Los Angeles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city was awarded the 1920 Olympics to honor the suffering that had been inflicted on the Belgian people during World War I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Antwerp",
    "choices": [
      "A. Charleroi",
      "B. Gent",
      "C. Antwerp",
      "D. Brussels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city hosted the first womens Olympic marathon in 1984?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Los Angeles",
      "B. Rome",
      "C. Barcelona",
      "D. Montreal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did a 2002 figure skating judging scandal result in the awarding of two Olympic gold medals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Salt Lake City",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lillehammer",
      "B. Calgary",
      "C. Salt Lake City",
      "D. Innsbruck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which citys retractable dome stadium wasnt completed in time for the 1976 Olympics due to a construction strike?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Montreal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Munich",
      "B. Seoul",
      "C. Moscow",
      "D. Montreal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did a bomb explode during the 1996 Olympics, resulting in two deaths?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Atlanta",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta",
      "B. Munich",
      "C. Nagano",
      "D. Moscow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What 1968 Olympic citys altitude was responsible for many track and field records being broken because of the rarefied air?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mexico City",
    "choices": [
      "A. Helsinki",
      "B. Rome",
      "C. Denver",
      "D. Mexico City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what city did the same skier win all three Olympic alpine events for the first time in history, in 1956?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cortina DAmpezzo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Torino",
      "B. Cortina DAmpezzo",
      "C. Oslo",
      "D. Grenoble"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city hosted the 1998 debut of snowboarding as an official Olympic sport?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nagano",
    "choices": [
      "A. Albertville",
      "B. Torino",
      "C. Nagano",
      "D. Salt Lake City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which previous Olympic city hosted the equestrian events of 1956, five months before the rest of the games took place in Melbourne?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stockholm",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis",
      "B. Amsterdam",
      "C. Stockholm",
      "D. Helsinki"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city hosted the first Olympics to include the U.S.S.R., in 1952?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Helsinki",
    "choices": [
      "A. Melbourne",
      "B. Amsterdam",
      "C. Rome",
      "D. Helsinki"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following events marred the 1972 summer Olympics in Munich?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eleven Israeli athletes were killed after being kidnapped by Palestinian terrorists.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Three boxing judges were accused of bribery after they awarded the decision to a South Korean light middleweight who was dominated by his American opponent.",
      "B. The quarters of several Austrian athletes were raided as part of a massive doping investigation.",
      "C. The marathon winner was found to have run only a portion of the race, hitching a ride for several miles before returning to the course.",
      "D. Eleven Israeli athletes were killed after being kidnapped by Palestinian terrorists."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where were the summer Olympics held in 1992, when a black African woman won a gold medal for the first time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barcelona",
    "choices": [
      "A. Los Angeles",
      "B. Amsterdam",
      "C. Sydney",
      "D. Barcelona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1960 Summer Olympics, the first to be fully covered by television, were held in which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rome",
    "choices": [
      "A. Grenoble",
      "B. Tokyo",
      "C. Innsbruck",
      "D. Rome"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city hosted the Olympics in 1994, only two years after the previous games were held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lillehammer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta",
      "B. Albertville",
      "C. Lillehammer",
      "D. Barcelona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is professional wrestler Dave Finlay from?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ireland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta, Georgia",
      "B. Ireland",
      "C. Omaha, Nebraska",
      "D. North Carolina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real name of WWE superstar Viscera?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nelson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Nelson",
      "D. Mable"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is WWEs headquarters?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stamford, Connecticut",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stamford, Connecticut",
      "B. L.A., California",
      "C. Hartford, Connecticut",
      "D. New York, New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these ladies dated both Matt Hardy and Edge?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Amy Dumas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Amy Dumas",
      "B. Codi Davis",
      "C. Laura Bush",
      "D. Trish Stratus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did professional wrestler Stacy Keibler retire from wrestling?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She wanted to have a social life and move on to other endeavors.",
    "choices": [
      "A. She didnt like the fame anymore.",
      "B. She wanted to have a social life and move on to other endeavors.",
      "C. She really wanted to dance, and take a break.",
      "D. She didnt quit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which WWE star has used the ring names Vampiro Americano, Death Mask and Johnny Hawk?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "JBL",
    "choices": [
      "A. JBL",
      "B. Bret Hart",
      "C. Cena",
      "D. HHH"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which professional wrestler was the very first WWF heavyweight champion of Latino descent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pedro Morales",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Guerrerro",
      "B. Rey Mysterio",
      "C. Pedro Morales",
      "D. Tito Santana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former professional wrestler introduced the Undertaker to the WWF at the 1990 Survivor Series.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Million Dollar Man Dibiase",
    "choices": [
      "A. Slick",
      "B. Ted Million Dollar Man Dibiase",
      "C. Captain Lou Albano",
      "D. Paul Bearer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Professional wrestler Ric Flair, better known by the ring name The Nature Boy was involved in what kind of accident in 1975?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "plane accident",
    "choices": [
      "A. car accident",
      "B. jet-ski accident",
      "C. motorcycle accident",
      "D. plane accident"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1987, former AWA World Champion Rick Martel formed the tag team Strike Force with which wrestler?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tito Santana",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Garea",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Tom Zenk",
      "D. Tito Santana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Professional wrestler Cheif Jay Strongbow had a partner whose neck was broken by Ken Patera. What was his name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Billy White Wolf",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jay Youngblood",
      "B. Jules Strongbow",
      "C. Billy White Wolf",
      "D. Wahoo Mcdaneil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Former professional wrestler Bob Backlund has held the WWF/WWE world title how many times?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3 times",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2 times",
      "B. 1 time",
      "C. 3 times",
      "D. 5 times"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Abe was the originator, owner, and player for the Harlem Globetrotters.   What was Abes last name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Saperstein",
    "choices": [
      "A. Saperstein",
      "B. Davis",
      "C. Mikan",
      "D. Davidson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nicknamed The Chief, he was a great basketball center, who played for many years.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Robert Parrish",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dennis Johnson",
      "B. Walt Bellamy",
      "C. JoJo White",
      "D. Robert Parrish"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She was the first woman to sign a contract with a National Basketball Association team, the Indiana Pacers.  She was also the first player to be part of the U.S. National team while still in high school.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ann Meyers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cheryl Miller",
      "B. Nancy Lieberman",
      "C. Carol Blazejowski",
      "D. Ann Meyers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former U.S. Senator and presidential candidate was inducted into the Basketball Hall of Fame in 1982.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Bradley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Byron (Whizzer) White",
      "B. Tom McMillan",
      "C. Marv Levy",
      "D. Bill Bradley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these players has been enshrined in the Basketball Hall of Fame both as a player and coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lenny Wilkins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nat Holman",
      "B. Red Holtzman",
      "C. Red Auerbach",
      "D. Lenny Wilkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This basketball player, who played for the Harlem Globetrotters, had amazing ball-handing abilities -- he would often dribble long enough for other players to rest.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marques Haynes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Darren McCune",
      "B. Marques Haynes",
      "C. Larry Big Hands Culpepper",
      "D. Bill The Hill McGill"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He developed basketball as a five-player sport while a faculty member of Springfield College.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Amos Alonzo Stagg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Namath",
      "B. Amos Alonzo Stagg",
      "C. Dr. James Naismith",
      "D. Rodney Duff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This basketball Hall Of Famer was known for 22 years, as the Clown Prince of the Globetrotters, a team upon which he left his mark as a player. His first name was Meadowlark . What is his last name ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lemon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lemon",
      "B. Watkins",
      "C. Johnson",
      "D. McCoy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many professional American football teams were there at the end of the 1920 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 14",
      "B. 30",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first Pro Bowl game held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1939",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1955",
      "B. 1935",
      "C. 1939",
      "D. 1970"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which teams played in the first Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas City and Green Bay",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kansas City and Green Bay",
      "B. Chicago and New York",
      "C. Chicago and Boston",
      "D. Green Bay and New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Detroit Red Wings won their first Stanley Cup, after defeating the Toronto Maple Leafs in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1936",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1934",
      "B. 1959",
      "C. 1925",
      "D. 1936"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who scored the game winning goal for the Detroit Red Wings in the 1950 Stanley Cup finals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Babando",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Babando",
      "B. Tommy Ivan",
      "C. Jimmy Skinner",
      "D. Metro Prystai"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Detroit Red Wings players won gold medals in mens hockey in the 2006 Winter Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2002, this former ice hockey defenseman became head coach of the Detroit Red Wings, after the retirement of Scotty Bowman.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dave Lewis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Babcock",
      "B. Mike Ilitch",
      "C. Scotty Bowman",
      "D. Dave Lewis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1950, this NHL team scored a game-winning goal in overtime of game seven, Stanley Cup Finals.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Detroit Red Wings",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Chicago Blackhawks",
      "B. The Montreal Canadiens",
      "C. The Boston Bruins",
      "D. The Detroit Red Wings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2002, the Detroit Red Wings won their tenth Stanley Cup, led by which coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scotty Bowman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Babcock",
      "B. Dawe Lewis",
      "C. Scotty Bowman",
      "D. Wayne Maxner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Chicago Cubs win their first World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1907",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1908",
      "B. 1945",
      "C. 1932",
      "D. 1907"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first ballpark in which the Chicago Cubs played in the national league?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "23rd Street Grounds",
    "choices": [
      "A. 23rd Street Grounds",
      "B. South Side Park",
      "C. Wrigley Field",
      "D. West Side Grounds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2003 the Chicago Cubs retired the jersey of which player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Santo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Santo",
      "B. Ernie Banks",
      "C. Billy Williams",
      "D. Ryne Sandberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which manager of the Chicago Cubs was named Manager of the Year in 1989?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Zimmer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dusty Baker",
      "B. Don Baylor",
      "C. Jim Frey",
      "D. Don Zimmer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Chicago Cubs player won the MVP award in back to back seasons?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ernie Banks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Banks",
      "B. Ryne Sandberg",
      "C. Andre Dawson",
      "D. Sammy Sosa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ron Santo, who played almost his entire career with the Chicago Cubs, was named a National League All-Star how many times?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "nine",
    "choices": [
      "A. eleven",
      "B. ten",
      "C. nine",
      "D. eight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt drove for several owners. Which owner was he driving for when he won his first NASCAR championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rod Osterland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rod Osterland",
      "B. Wood Brothers",
      "C. Bud Moore",
      "D. Richard Childress"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1998, every crew member of every team formed a line to shake the hand of race car driver Dale Earnhardt on his way to Victory Lane. He had finally won the one big race that had eluded him for twenty years. What was the race?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dayton 500",
    "choices": [
      "A. Charlotte 600",
      "B. Talldageda",
      "C. Dayton 500",
      "D. Firecracker 400 at  Darlington"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these was not one of Dale Earnhardts nicknames?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ironheart",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Man in Black",
      "B. The Intimidator",
      "C. Ironhead",
      "D. Ironheart"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardts death led to more safety features added to race cars to improve a drivers chance to escape harm. Which one was not a safety feature added as a result of his death?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Restrictor Plates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roof and Hatch Escape",
      "B. Head and Neck Restraints HANS",
      "C. Restrictor Plates",
      "D. SAFFR Barrier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt appeared on the David Letterman show to reveal the ten reasons it took twenty years\nfor him to win the Daytona 500. What was the number one reason?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It took me 19 years to figure I had the emergency brake on.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Who cares it took 20 years - at least my name isnt Dick Trickle.",
      "B. It took me 19 years to figure I had the emergency brake on.",
      "C. I finally rotated and balanced my mustache.",
      "D. New pit crew - The Spice Girls."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It was on this track that Dale Earnhardt Sr. had his 76th and last career win. He was in 18th\nplace on a restart and charged through traffic to take the checkered flag in 5 laps.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Talladega",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rockingham",
      "B. Charlotte",
      "C. Atlanta",
      "D. Talladega"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wilt The Stilt Chamberlain became the first NBA player who has scored 100 points in a single game. Against which team did he score the 100 points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The New York Knicks",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Fort Wayne Pistons",
      "B. The Chicago Bulls",
      "C. The New York Knicks",
      "D. The Saint Louis Hawks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Florida State University center became a star NBA player after his pro coach sent him to play in NYCs Rucker Tournament. His unconventional behavior included sleeping on park benches. Who is this former cab driver?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dave Cowens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dave Cowens",
      "B. Nate Thurmond",
      "C. George Mikan",
      "D. Swede Holbrook"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although âonlyâ 67 (2 m) tall he was the first of the great defensive players in the NBA. His college team won the NCAA championship. His pro team won many championships. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Russell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "B. Nate Thurmond",
      "C. George Mikan",
      "D. Bill Russell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Born in Lagos, Nigeria in 1963, this player led his team to two consecutive NBA crowns in 1994 and 1995. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hakeem Olajuwon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hakeem Olajuwon",
      "B. Manute Bol",
      "C. Mikebe Mitumbo",
      "D. Dino Meneghin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Margo Dydek broke the record for the tallest player to ever play in the WNBA. How tall is she?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "72 (2.18 m)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 74 (2.23 m)",
      "B. 67 (2.00 m)",
      "C. 69 (2.05 m)",
      "D. 72 (2.18 m)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This center went in the ABA directly out of high school. He later played 21 seasons in the NBA. He  played on a team with high scorer Rick Barry and later with Barrys son, Jon. Who is this player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Moses Malone",
    "choices": [
      "A. Robert Parish",
      "B. Moses Malone",
      "C. Nate Thurmond",
      "D. Darryl Dawkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Gheorghe MureÅan, one of the tallest players to ever play in the NBA, was born in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Romania",
    "choices": [
      "A. Uganda",
      "B. Nigeria",
      "C. Romania",
      "D. Sudan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great center was sometimes called The Howlerâ because he used to yell at opponents in order to ruin the shooters concentration. His other nickname is associated with his career between college and the NBA. Who is this three-time Olympian who once scored a quadruple double?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Robinson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Moses malone",
      "B. David Robinson",
      "C. Bill Walton",
      "D. Wes Unseld"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After a great college career at Louisville, this center became the first star for the old Washington Bullets (now the Washington Wizards). He was less than 68 (2 m) tall but was noted for his great rebounding, picks and fabulous outlet passes. Who is this former NBA great?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wes Unseld",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wes Unseld",
      "B. Wllis Reed",
      "C. Nate Thurmond",
      "D. David Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player was the center at UCLA when the Bruins won 88 straight games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Walton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Walton",
      "B. Dave Cowens",
      "C. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar (aka Lew Alcindor)",
      "D. Sidney Wicks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although originally drafted in the second round as a forward, this man took over the center spot for his only NBA team and led them to an NBA championship. He later coached at Creighton University. Who is this center who was nicknamed The Captainâ in the NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willis Reed",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willis Reed",
      "B. Nate Thurmond",
      "C. Walter Dukes",
      "D. Bill Lanier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After a great college career at Bowling Green, this center played power forward for the Warriors because Wilt Cahmberlain played center. After Wilt was traded back to Philadelphia, he bloomed as a center. Who is this player who once pulled down 18 rebounds in one quarter?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nate Thurmond",
    "choices": [
      "A. Swede Holbrooke",
      "B. Moses Malone",
      "C. Willis Reed",
      "D. Nate Thurmond"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The biggest race of 2006, the Daytona 500, was won by what racer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmie Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jeff Gordon",
      "B. Jeff Burton",
      "C. Jimmie Johnson",
      "D. Tony Stewart"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which driver won the Golden Corral 500 on March 20, 2006 in Atlanta?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kasey Kahne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Earnhardt, Jr.",
      "B. Ryan Newman",
      "C. Kasey Kahne",
      "D. Carl Edwards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which driver swept both races at Pocono in 2006, winning also both poles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Denny Hamlin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Clint Bowyer",
      "B. Martin Truex, Jr.",
      "C. Denny Hamlin",
      "D. J.J. Yeley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the USG Sheetrock 400, who claimed victory at the Chicagoland raceway in controversial fashion on July 9, 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Gordon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jeff Gordon",
      "B. Matt Kenseth",
      "C. Tony Stewart",
      "D. Kevin Harvick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the 2006 Pepsi 400 on July 1 and celebrated it by climbing a fence?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Stewart",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kurt Busch",
      "B. Kyle Busch",
      "C. Carl Edwards",
      "D. Tony Stewart"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Only two drivers each got 6 poles in 2006. Kasey Kahne was one. Name the other.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kurt Busch",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kurt Busch",
      "B. Ryan Newman",
      "C. Scott Riggs",
      "D. Jeff Burton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "May 6, 2006 saw a victory for this popular NASCAR driver in the Crown Royal 400 in Richmond.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dale Earnhardt, Jr.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Stewart",
      "B. Jimmie Johnson",
      "C. Kasey Kahne",
      "D. Dale Earnhardt, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which driver swept both races at Phoenix in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kevin Harvick",
    "choices": [
      "A. Matt Kenseth",
      "B. Jeff Gordon",
      "C. Jeff Burton",
      "D. Kevin Harvick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Sharpie 500 in Bristol on August 26, 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Matt Kenseth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kevin Harvick",
      "B. Kyle Busch",
      "C. Kurt Busch",
      "D. Matt Kenseth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In one of the more controversial wins of 2006 NASCAR, who picked up his first career cup win in Talledega on October 8 in the UAW-Ford 500?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brian Vickers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Denny Hamlin",
      "B. Clint Bowyer",
      "C. Brian Vickers",
      "D. Martin Truex, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2003, this former football player became head coach at the University of Alabama, replacing Mike Price.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Shula",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Shula",
      "B. Mike Bowden",
      "C. Michael Gibbs",
      "D. Mike Anderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the head football coach at the University of Alabama after Harold Red Drew?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "JB Ears Whitworth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wallace Wade",
      "B. Gene Stallings",
      "C. Frank Thomas",
      "D. JB Ears Whitworth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former linebacker for the Dallas Cowboys played for the University of Alabama from 1960-1962.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lee Roy Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lee Roy Jordan",
      "B. Terry Beasley",
      "C. Herschel Walker",
      "D. Pat Sullivan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former American football player, who played for the Atlanta Falcons and Washington Redskins, won the 1971 Heisman Trophy.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pat Sullivan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pat Sullivan",
      "B. Joe Cribbs",
      "C. Jay Barker",
      "D. Archie Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A golfer who has done any one of these is no longer considered an amateur.  There is an odd one, however, which would not change your status of an amateur.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Played along with professional players",
    "choices": [
      "A. Played golf for money",
      "B. Received a trophey of significant monetary value",
      "C. Taught golf for money",
      "D. Played along with professional players"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the following statements is incorrect.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A frequent result of short shots is that the ball comes to rest on difficult ground.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Long shots may reduce the total number of strokes for a given hole.",
      "B. A frequent result of long shots is that the ball goes out of bounds.",
      "C. A frequent result of short shots is that the ball comes to rest on difficult ground.",
      "D. Long shots are less precise than short ones."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There are four major types of golf clubs. Which of the following pairs (club type - common shot) is wrong?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lob Wedges - Low shots",
    "choices": [
      "A. Woods - Long shots",
      "B. Putters - Shots on the green",
      "C. Lob Wedges - Low shots",
      "D. Irons - Precise shots"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The majors for men are this many in number.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I started playing for the national team of Brazil in 1999 and I joined the Barcelona soccer team in 2003?\nWho am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ronaldhino",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Beckham",
      "B. Zidane",
      "C. Jaime Moreno",
      "D. Ronaldhino"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "My real name is Edson Arantes do Nascimento and I scored 77 goals in 92 appearances with my national team. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pele",
    "choices": [
      "A. Zidane",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Pele",
      "D. Lucio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I played for the national team of West Germany from 1965-1977. I went on to become national team manager and led our team to the World Cup finals in 1990 and 1986. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Franz Beckenbauer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johan Cruyff",
      "B. Franz Beckenbauer",
      "C. Ruud Gullit",
      "D. Marco Van Basten"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2003, I joined the soccer club Real Madrid. Bend it like _______ is a movie title that makes reference to my name. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Beckham",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alfredo Di Stefano",
      "B. Zico",
      "C. David Beckham",
      "D. Ronaldo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I have a move named after me and I was born on April 25, 1947. I played for the Ajax Juniors at 10. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johan Cruyff",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe Ruth",
      "B. Landon Donovan",
      "C. Johan Cruyff",
      "D. Terrel Owens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I was born on October 30th 1960 and in 1982 I was transferred to Barcelona for a record Â£5.000.000 as a transfer fee. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Diego Maradona",
    "choices": [
      "A. Diego Maradona",
      "B. Alecko Eskandarian",
      "C. Jaime Moreno",
      "D. Julio Roberts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I played for the French national team but I was ejected from the 2006 World Cup Final for headbutting an Italian player. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zinedine Zidane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Terry Henry",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. David Trezeguet",
      "D. Zinedine Zidane"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I was born crippled and the operation that let me walk left me with a distorted leg. Yet, I managed to win two World Cup titles. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Garrincha",
    "choices": [
      "A. Garrincha",
      "B. Michael Platini",
      "C. Stanley Mathews",
      "D. Zico"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1965, I became the first British soccer player to be knighted. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stanley Matthews",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jamaal Lewis",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Stanley Matthews",
      "D. Pele"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1990 I was sold to Juventus for Â£7,700,000. Not to mention I scored 24 goals in 40 games with Fiorentina. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roberto Baggio",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alfredo Di Stefano",
      "B. Eusebio",
      "C. Zico",
      "D. Roberto Baggio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The three machines, introduced by Lou Albano in the mid-80s, featured three masked superstars. They were Axe, Andre the Giant, and who else?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Blackjack Mulligan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Big John Studd",
      "B. Sgt. Slaughter",
      "C. Samoan Afa",
      "D. Blackjack Mulligan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did professional wrestler Roddy Piper not face on Saturday Nights Main Event in 1985 and 1986?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mr. T",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Iron Shiek",
      "B. Mr. Wonderful",
      "C. Bob Orton",
      "D. Mr. T"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Saturday Nights Main Event aired on what network during the 80s and early 90s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NBC",
    "choices": [
      "A. TNT",
      "B. NBC",
      "C. CBS",
      "D. ABC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what city did Andre the Giant defeat Hulk Hogan for the WWF title?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Indianapolis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit",
      "B. Indianapolis",
      "C. St. Paul",
      "D. Boston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former tag team partner of Tony Atlas inducted him into the WWE Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "S.D. Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. S.D. Jones",
      "B. Chief Jay Strongbow",
      "C. Hulk Hogan",
      "D. Rocky Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The face (good guy) team in the main event of the 1988 Survivor Series consisted of Hulk Hogan, Randy Savage, Hillbilly Jim, Hercules, and what other wrestler?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Koko B. Ware",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jake The Snake Roberts",
      "B. Brutus Beefcake",
      "C. Tito Santana",
      "D. Koko B. Ware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Each year the NFL gives an award for kickers which is named after this former NFL great.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Groza",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tommy OBrien",
      "B. Elbert Dubinion",
      "C. Lou Groza",
      "D. Sammy Baugh"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For many years NFL placekickers would line-up directly in front of where the ball was placed. This  changed when soccer style placekickers entered the league. These two Hungarian-born brothers were the most significant of the early placekickers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Gogolaks",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Gogolaks",
      "B. The Grammaticas",
      "C. The Guys",
      "D. The Blandas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlike most NFL players, this great kicker was born in Fenstud, Norway. In Super Bowl IV, he kicked three field goals. Who was this soccer-style kicker?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jan Stenerud",
    "choices": [
      "A. Morten Andersen",
      "B. George Blanda",
      "C. Jan Stenerud",
      "D. Gary Anderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Kentucky grad had a very long Pro Football career. He won games as a kicker and as a  quarterback. He originally played for the Chicago bears but also won fame playing for the Houston Oilers and the Oakland Raiders.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Blanda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ray Guy",
      "B. Jan Stenerud",
      "C. George Blanda",
      "D. Gary Anderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This placekicker started his career in 1982 with the New Orleans Saints. He was 46 when he re-signed with the Atlanta Falcons in 2006.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Morten Andersen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jay Feely",
      "B. Jason Elam",
      "C. Morten Andersen",
      "D. Josh Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great kicker was a Danish soccer star as a teenager. He was a visiting high school student  in Indianapolis when he kicked a field goal, just to try it. This led to a scholarship to Michigan State and a  fine Pro career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Morten Andersen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Morten Andersen",
      "B. Jan Stenerud",
      "C. Gary Anderson",
      "D. Jay Feely"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As most NFL fans know, this kicker was born without toes on his right foot.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Dempsey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tom Dempsey",
      "B. Josh Brown",
      "C. Adam Vinatieri",
      "D. George Blanda"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This famous player from South Dakota is the first placekicker to win four NFL championships.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Adam Vinatieri",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Blanda",
      "B. Gary Anderson",
      "C. Adam Vinatieri",
      "D. Tom Dempsey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This quarterback played his college ball at Louisville and his pro ball for Philadelphia. In a game  against the Bears, he scored 15 points.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Akers",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Blanda",
      "B. Adam Vinatierri",
      "C. David Akers",
      "D. Lou Groza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Istanbul is the home city of the most powerful Turkish soccer teams. Which of the following teams is not based in Istanbul?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Genclerbirligi SK",
    "choices": [
      "A. Galatasaray",
      "B. Besiktas",
      "C. Genclerbirligi SK",
      "D. Fenerbahce"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following soccer teams is not from Cyprus?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kerkira",
    "choices": [
      "A. Appolon",
      "B. Omonia",
      "C. Kerkira",
      "D. AEK Larnaca"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Czech soccer team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "SK Sigma Olomouc",
    "choices": [
      "A. FC Nitra",
      "B. Vejle BK",
      "C. SK Sigma Olomouc",
      "D. NK Domzale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not a Scottish soccer team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Donegal Celtic FC",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aberdeen",
      "B. Celtic FC",
      "C. Dundee United",
      "D. Donegal Celtic FC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these soccer teams cannot play in the Italian Championship Serie A?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Getafe CF",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lazio",
      "B. Fiorentina",
      "C. Getafe CF",
      "D. Reggina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "F91 Dudelange is a soccer team based in which country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Luxembourg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Malta",
      "B. Ireland",
      "C. Luxembourg",
      "D. England"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following soccer teams plays in the French  Le Championat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "AJ Auxerre",
    "choices": [
      "A. Charleroi SC",
      "B. AJ Auxerre",
      "C. DSC Arminia Bilefeld",
      "D. AS Jeunesse Esch"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The crest of which London soccer team features a crossed pair of hammers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "West Ham",
    "choices": [
      "A. West Ham",
      "B. Fulham FC",
      "C. Chelsea FC",
      "D. Arsenal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these soccer teams is based in Poland?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Korona Kielce",
    "choices": [
      "A. Zimbru Chisinau",
      "B. Skonto FC",
      "C. Korona Kielce",
      "D. Metalist Kharkiv"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the soccer team which is not based in Romania?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Politehnica Chisinau",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gloria Bistrita",
      "B. Politehnica Chisinau",
      "C. FC Arges",
      "D. CFR Cluj"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the listed soccer teams is from Norway?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rosenborg BK",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rosenborg BK",
      "B. Silkeborg IF",
      "C. VFL Wolfsburg",
      "D. IF Elfsborg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is a Hungarian soccer club?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "FC Sopron",
    "choices": [
      "A. FC Sopron",
      "B. FC Ashdod",
      "C. FC Haka",
      "D. SCR Altach"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these players did NOT hit a walk-off home run in a World Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Thomson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Carter",
      "B. Bobby Thomson",
      "C. Bill Mazeroski",
      "D. Carlton Fisk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the last time teams played to a tie in a Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1912",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1912",
      "B. Never",
      "C. 1908",
      "D. 1994"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Cardinals beat the Mets to gain entry into the 2006 World Series. What made Mookie Wilson, a former Mets star, so happy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Preston Wilson, his nephew and stepson, plays for the Cardinals.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Preston Wilson, his stepson, plays for the Cardinals.",
      "B. Preston Wilson, his nephew, plays for the Cardinals.",
      "C. Mookie lives in St. Louis.",
      "D. Preston Wilson, his nephew and stepson, plays for the Cardinals."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who pitched the first no-hitter in Series history?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Larsen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lew Burdette",
      "B. Orel Hershiser",
      "C. Don Larsen",
      "D. Nolan Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the only player to hit 3 home runs twice in a World Series game?  If more than one person has done it, who was first?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Reggie Jackson",
      "B. No one",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Hank Aaron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was impressive about Reggie Jacksons homers in Game 6 of the 1977 Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He hit each of his homers on the first pitch.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He ignored all the bunt signs.",
      "B. He hit 2 of them as a switch-hitting right-hander.",
      "C. He hit each of his homers on the first pitch.",
      "D. He hit them all against pitchers who were former teammates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did baseball player Derek Jeter acquire the nickname Mr. November?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He hit a game-winning homer in the first World Series game ever played in November.",
    "choices": [
      "A. That is his bats nickname.",
      "B. He hit a game-winning homer in the first World Series game ever played in November.",
      "C. His uniform number is 11.",
      "D. He loves Thanksgiving."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first player in baseball history to hold World Series records as both a pitcher and hitter?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Brett",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Dizzy Gillespie",
      "D. Dizzy Dean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Three of the Hall-of-Fame players listed below never won a World Series championship. Who is the lucky exception?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Feller",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Banks",
      "B. Ted Williams",
      "C. Bob Feller",
      "D. Rod Carew"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams won their ninth World Series title in 1982?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The St. Louis Cardinals",
    "choices": [
      "A. The NY Yankees",
      "B. The St. Louis Cardinals",
      "C. The Braves (Boston, Milwaukee, Atlanta)",
      "D. The Athletics (Phila., Kansas City, Oakland)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the oldest player in the 2004 Red Sox team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ellis Burks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Timlin",
      "B. Curt Schilling",
      "C. Tim Wakefield",
      "D. Ellis Burks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these 2004 Red Sox stars was not a first-round draft pick?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Ortiz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nomar Garciaparra",
      "B. David Ortiz",
      "C. Manny Ramirez",
      "D. Jason Varitek"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Red Sox player saw limited duty and limited success in 2004, after an embarrassing incident in which he made an obscene gesture to the fans before a 2003 playoff game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Byung-Hyun Kim",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ramiro Mendoza",
      "B. Byung-Hyun Kim",
      "C. Gabe Kapler",
      "D. David McCarty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these players became a U.S. citizen during the 2004 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Manny Ramirez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pedro Martinez",
      "B. David Ortiz",
      "C. Orlando Cabrera",
      "D. Manny Ramirez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the 19-game regular season series, how many games did the 2004 Red Sox win against the Yankees?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "11",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 11",
      "C. 9",
      "D. 12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which newly acquired player, upon seeing Nomar Garciaparra leaving the Red Sox clubhouse the day of the 2004 trading deadline, said, Please tell me I wasnt traded for Nomar?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Doug Mientkiewitz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Doug Mientkiewitz",
      "B. Dave Roberts",
      "C. Curtis Leskanic",
      "D. Orlando Cabrera"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Red Sox pitcher gave up the most home runs in the 2004 regular season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tim Wakefield",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pedro Martinez",
      "B. Bronson Arroyo",
      "C. Curt Schilling",
      "D. Tim Wakefield"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2004 Boston Red Sox played 13 extra inning games during the regular season. How many of them did they win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "7",
    "choices": [
      "A. 9",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the 2004 Red Sox regular season in number of stolen bases?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Damon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jason Varitek",
      "B. Pokey Reese",
      "C. Johnny Damon",
      "D. Mark Bellhorn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Major League organization released Tim Wakefield, allowing him to sign as a free agent with the Red Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pittsburgh Pirates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Philadelphia Phillies",
      "B. San Diego Padres",
      "C. Pittsburgh Pirates",
      "D. Milwaukee Brewers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which reliever, who had been the Red Sox closer in 2003, had a better earned run average in the 2004 season than the new closer, Keith Foulke?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scott Williamson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ramiro Mendoza",
      "B. Alan Embree",
      "C. Mike Timlin",
      "D. Scott Williamson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Games 4 and 5 of the 2004 American League Championship Series were dramatic extra-inning victories for the Red Sox. How many total innings were played in those two games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "26",
    "choices": [
      "A. 25",
      "B. 26",
      "C. 23",
      "D. 24"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the only two players on the Red Sox 2004 World Series roster who already had World Series rings?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Timlin and Curt Schilling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dave Roberts and Keith Foulke",
      "B. Keith Foulke and Mike Timlin",
      "C. Mike Timlin and Curt Schilling",
      "D. Curt Schilling and Ramiro Mendoza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What astronomical event was visible the night the Red Sox completed the World Series sweep against the Cardinals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lunar eclipse",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hale-Bopp comet",
      "B. Aurora Borealis",
      "C. Perseid meteor shower",
      "D. Lunar eclipse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the winning pitcher in the clinching games of all three 2004 postseason series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Derek Lowe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Keith Foulke",
      "B. Derek Lowe",
      "C. Tim Wakefield",
      "D. Mike Timlin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Pete Roses middle name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edward",
    "choices": [
      "A. John",
      "B. James",
      "C. Edward",
      "D. Eugene"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was former baseball player Pete Rose born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1941",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1942",
      "B. 1943",
      "C. 1944",
      "D. 1941"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many different teams did Pete Rose play for in the major leagues?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these nicknames was given to Pete Rose?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Charlie Hustle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Thorny",
      "B. Pistol Pete",
      "C. Charlie Hustle",
      "D. Ramblin Rose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pete Rose got his debut on April 8th of what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1963",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1966",
      "B. 1965",
      "C. 1964",
      "D. 1963"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the catcher Pete Rose collided into in the 1970 All-star game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ray Fosse",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Roseboro",
      "B. None Of These",
      "C. Dave Duncan",
      "D. Ray Fosse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did Pete Rose and the Cincinnati Reds beat in the 1975 World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Red Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. None Of These",
      "B. Red Sox",
      "C. Tigers",
      "D. Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the score 0-0 called in tennis?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Love all",
    "choices": [
      "A. 0-0 all",
      "B. Love",
      "C. Love all",
      "D. 0 to 0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In tennis, what are the two shots that are the same movement?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Serve/Overhead",
    "choices": [
      "A. Serve/Overhead",
      "B. Volley/Forehand",
      "C. Forehand/Backhand",
      "D. Lob/Serve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although he was never a great scorer, he was a team leader, who was considred the best defensive guard during his prime. A great athlete, he had tryouts for several football teams although basketball was his best sport. Who is this great point guard and former Celtics head coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "K.C. Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Havlichek",
      "B. Jo-Jo White",
      "C. K.C. Jones",
      "D. Bob Cousy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This New York-born point guard was a star at Holy Cross before starring with the Celtics. He was one of the first point guards to be able to penetrate the defense and then dish off to another player. After his  Celtics career, he became a college coach.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Cousy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jo-Jo White",
      "B. K.C.Jones",
      "C. Bill Sharman",
      "D. Bob Cousy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great point guard had the nickname Clyde when he played for the New York Knicks.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walt Clyde Frazier",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walt Clyde Frazier",
      "B. Richie Clyde Guerin",
      "C. Jack Clyde Twyman",
      "D. Jack Clyde Drexler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This point guard played for Philadelphia in the NBA after his college career at West Texas State. Over  his 15 seasons, he averaged close to 7 assists per game, a great accomplishment for such a long career. After he retired as a player, he became Philadelphias head coach. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maurice Cheeks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Avery Johnson",
      "B. George Karl",
      "C. Mike Donleavy",
      "D. Maurice Cheeks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This point guard grew up in Kansas, where he went to school. Somehow, Red Auerbach got him into the Connecticut National Guard, to keep him from being  drafted. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "JoJo White",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dennis Johnson",
      "B. Stefan Telfair",
      "C. Nate Archibald",
      "D. JoJo White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This backcourt  wonder and Basketball Hall of Famer was often billed as the worlds greatest dribbler. He was born in Oklahoma and attended Langston University.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marques Haynes",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Stockton",
      "B. Frank McGuire",
      "C. DicK McGuire",
      "D. Marques Haynes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This point guard was a team leader for Seattle and the Celtics. After his college career at Pepperdine, he played in the NBA from 1976-1990. Although always a great leader, he never was a head coach. Who was he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hal Lear",
      "B. Dennis Johnson",
      "C. John Stockton",
      "D. Hal Greer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After graduating from the University of California at Berkley, this great point guard became the NBA rookie of the year for the 1994/1995 year. He has been in at least 8 All-Star games.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jason Kidd",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Nash",
      "B. Jason Kidd",
      "C. Kobe Bryant",
      "D. John Stockton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Major League Baseball start giving out the Rookie of the Year Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1947",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1947",
      "B. 1945",
      "C. 1949",
      "D. 1951"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Major League Baseball started giving Rookie of the Year Award in each league in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1949",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1949",
      "B. 1947",
      "C. 1950",
      "D. 1948"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Thurman Munson win the Rookie of the Year Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1970",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1972",
      "B. 1970",
      "C. 1965",
      "D. 1968"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Frank Robinson won the Rookie of the Year Award while playing with which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "CIncinnati Reds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Baltimore Orioles",
      "B. CIncinnati Reds",
      "C. Cleveland Indians",
      "D. Houson Colt 45s"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Boston Red Sox Hall of Fame outfielder, who served twice in the military as a marine corps pilot, was a two-time MVP winner (1946 and 1949) and a two-time Triple Crown winner (1942 and 1947).",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carl Yastrzemski",
      "B. Harry Hooper",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Ted Williams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players did not have his number retired by the Boston Red Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Luis Aparicio",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ted Williams",
      "B. Carl Yastrzemski",
      "C. Bobby Doerr",
      "D. Luis Aparicio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A 1930 Model A Ford Sport Coupe drives on the field as the crowd rises to sing their fight song that includes these lyrics:   If I had a son, Sir\nIll tell you what hes do\nHed yell:  To hell with Georgia\nLike his Daddy use to do!\nIn what university stadium would you be sitting?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Georgia Tech",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida State University",
      "B. Georgia Tech",
      "C. University of Alabama",
      "D. Auburn University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "College bands brings out the school spirit in the fans and some bands are renowned in their own right.  But the most famous band member in college football is not a member of a drumline or a strutting majorette, hes a sousaphone player.  What universitys band is on the field when the sousaphone player dots the i?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ohio State",
    "choices": [
      "A. Princeton",
      "B. University of Iowa",
      "C. Ohio State",
      "D. University of Miami"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Touchdown!  A Conestoga wagon pulled by two white ponies named Sooner and Boomer race around Owen Field.  Who has scored a touchdown?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Oklahoma",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sanford",
      "B. University of Colorado",
      "C. University of Oklahoma",
      "D. Texas A  M"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What university are you visiting when, at the end of the game, the fans begin to sing  Take Me Home, Country Roads",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "West Virginia University",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of North Carolina",
      "B. Virginia Tech",
      "C. West Virginia University",
      "D. University of Virginia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which university mascot made the April 28, 1997 cover of Sports Illustrated?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Uga",
    "choices": [
      "A. Handsome Dan",
      "B. Uga",
      "C. Smokey",
      "D. Sue E Pig"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "One of college footballs greatest traditions is the Rose Bowl played on New Years Day. What university hosted the only Rose Bowl not played in Pasadena?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duke",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Washington",
      "B. University of Oklahoma",
      "C. Duke",
      "D. Sanford"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This universitys symbol, a golden eagle, soared over the crowd to help begin the 2002 Winter Olympics at Salt Lake City, Utah.  This year War Eagle VII will soar above the stadium to the cry of War Eagle!  War Eagle!  What university is home to the War Eagle named Tiger?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Auburn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Princeton",
      "B. UCLA",
      "C. Auburn",
      "D. Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Several universities can be heard yelling Hold that tiger. Hold that tiger as their team rushes to the field.   But only one university has each player touch Howards Rock and run straight down a steep hill into the stadium know as  Death Valley.  What university would you be visiting when these Tigers take the field?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Clemson",
    "choices": [
      "A. LSU",
      "B. Auburn",
      "C. Memphis",
      "D. Clemson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Two universities are are almost always listed in the number one or number two spot when naming the best college fight song.  One song mentioned is Notre Dames Notre Dame Victory March.  The second fight song lyrics start: Send a volley cheer on high.  Shake down the thunder from the sky.  In which university stadium called the big house would you be sitting when the fans starting singing The Victors?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Michigan",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Texas",
      "B. University of Michigan",
      "C. Cornell",
      "D. Ohio State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Dodger pitcher was named the 1963 World Series most valuable player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sandy Koufax",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Reuss",
      "B. Don Drysdale",
      "C. Johnny Podres",
      "D. Sandy Koufax"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the manager of the 1981 World Series-winning team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tommy Lasorda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Lemon",
      "B. Walter Alston",
      "C. Billy Martin",
      "D. Tommy Lasorda"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is race car driver Ryan Newman originally from?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Bend, IN",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis, MO",
      "B. South Bend, IN",
      "C. Louisville, KY",
      "D. Indianapolis, IN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which university did NASCAR driver Ryan Newman graduate from?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Purdue",
    "choices": [
      "A. Texas Tech",
      "B. Notre Dame",
      "C. Iowa",
      "D. Purdue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Ryan Newman get his first NASCAR Busch Series victory?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2001",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2002",
      "B. 2000",
      "C. 1999",
      "D. 2001"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What award did NASCAR driver Ryan Newman win in 2003?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "SPEED Channel American Driver of the Year",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rookie of the Year",
      "B. SPEED Channel American Driver of the Year",
      "C. Winston cup",
      "D. Most popular driver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wins did NASCAR driver Ryan Newman have in 2003?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At which track did Ryan Newman win his first Cup Series points race?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Hampshire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michigan",
      "B. New Hampshire",
      "C. Pocono",
      "D. Dover"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many players are allowed on the ice during an ice hockey game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5",
      "B. 12",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 6"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which professional wrestler had won more titles than any other wrestler until he became King of the Ring in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Booker T",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bret Hart",
      "B. Shawn Michaels",
      "C. Sting",
      "D. Booker T"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these wrestlers did not win an IWGP championship title in the 20th century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Jericho",
    "choices": [
      "A. El Samurai",
      "B. Owen Hart",
      "C. Chris Jericho",
      "D. The Pegasus Kid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The members of which of these professional wrestling teams did not begin their career together as a tag team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rick Steiner and Scott Steiner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lance Storm and Chris Jericho",
      "B. Sting and Warrior",
      "C. Rick Steiner and Scott Steiner",
      "D. Curt Henning and Scott Hall"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these wrestlers was a member of the professional wrestling stable the Four Horsemen only for three weeks?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Curt Henning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sid Vicious",
      "B. Curt Henning",
      "C. Paul Roma",
      "D. Lex Lugar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This tag team won their title match but Vince McMahon decided that the title reign had to be anulled and edited out of the broadcast.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Rockers",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Rockers",
      "B. The Killer Bees",
      "C. Men On a Mission",
      "D. Marty Jannety and 1-2-3 Kid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pay-per-view of the World Wrestling Federation was named The Night the Lights Went Out in Georgia?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Judgement Day",
    "choices": [
      "A. King of the Ring",
      "B. Judgement Day",
      "C. Armageddon",
      "D. No Way Out"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these wrestlers became WWF Intercontinental Champion on April 12, 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Godfather",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hacksaw Jim Duggan",
      "B. Bad News Allen",
      "C. Vader",
      "D. The Godfather"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who has managed the wrestlers Chris Jericho, the Undertaker, Ice Train, Jazz, Sid Vicious and Too Cold Scorpio?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Teddy Long",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stephen Pritchard",
      "B. Michael Hayes",
      "C. Paul Heyman",
      "D. Teddy Long"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What incredible event took place the same month Bob Backlund defeated Bret Hart to win the WWE Title in 1994?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Foreman became heavyweight boxing champion.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Backlund had just recovered from hip surgery.",
      "B. Rick Flair won his 9th world title.",
      "C. Hogan won his first WCW title.",
      "D. George Foreman became heavyweight boxing champion."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the St. Louis Cardinals team established?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1882",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1882",
      "B. 1890",
      "C. 1900",
      "D. 1910"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Bob Gibsons earned run average in 1968?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1.12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1.12",
      "B. 1.58",
      "C. 1.00",
      "D. 1.39"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What nickname was applied to the St. Louis Cardinals team of the 1934?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gashouse Gang",
    "choices": [
      "A. Flyin Birds",
      "B. Whiz Kids",
      "C. Gashouse Gang",
      "D. Cardiac Kids"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player of the the St. Louis Cardinals set a major league record by hitting two grand slams in a single inning against the Los Angeles Dodgers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fernando Tatis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Boyer",
      "B. Mike Shannon",
      "C. Terry Pendleton",
      "D. Fernando Tatis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the St. Louis Cardinals win the World Series after beating the Milwaukee Brewers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1982",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1987",
      "B. 1968",
      "C. 1985",
      "D. 1982"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first Busch Stadium built?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1966",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1956",
      "B. 1960",
      "C. 1966",
      "D. 1970"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did Ozzie Smith play for before joining the St. Louis Cardinals in 1982?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Diego Padres",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Diego Padres",
      "B. New York Mets",
      "C. LA Dodgers",
      "D. Oakland As"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pitcher, who last played with the St. Louis Cardinals, died suddenly in his hotel room in Chicago in 2002?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Darryl Kile",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Carlton",
      "B. John Tudor",
      "C. Darryl Kile",
      "D. Bob Tewksbury"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former Cardinal played against his old team in the 1985 World Series as a member of the Kansas City Royals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dane Iorg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dane Iorg",
      "B. Keith Hernandez",
      "C. Ken Oberkfell",
      "D. Terry Pendleton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these baseball players has never played with the New York Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fran Healy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Valentine",
      "B. Fran Healy",
      "C. Warren Spahn",
      "D. Joe Torre"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who started at third base for the New York Mets on Opening Day in 1962?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Zimmer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ed Charles",
      "B. Rod Kanehl",
      "C. Elio Chacon",
      "D. Don Zimmer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The New York  Mets lost to which team in the 1988 NLCS?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Dodgers",
    "choices": [
      "A. CIncinatti Reds",
      "B. San Diego Padres",
      "C. Atlanta Braves",
      "D. Los Angeles Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many years did John Franco spend with the New York Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "15",
    "choices": [
      "A. 13",
      "B. 15",
      "C. 16",
      "D. 12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many regular season games did the Chargers win in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 12",
      "C. 13",
      "D. 14"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did the 2006 Chargers lose to in the playoffs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New England Patriots",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Jets",
      "B. Baltimore Ravens",
      "C. Indianapolis Colts",
      "D. New England Patriots"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former San Diego Charger scored a touchdown against his former team in the Chargers 2006 playoff loss?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Reche Caldwell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Reche Caldwell",
      "B. Derek Farmer",
      "C. Drew Brees",
      "D. Jesse Chatman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which member of the 2006 Chargers coaching staff was fired following the season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marty Schottenheimer",
    "choices": [
      "A. James Lofton",
      "B. Wade Phillips",
      "C. Marty Schottenheimer",
      "D. Cam Cameron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of Charger running back LaDainian Tomlinson?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "In 2006, he rushed for over 2,000 yards.",
    "choices": [
      "A. In 2006, he broke the single season scoring record.",
      "B. In 2006, he won the NFL Most Valuable Player award.",
      "C. In 2006, he rushed for over 2,000 yards.",
      "D. In 2006, he became the player to reach 100 touchdowns for a career in the shortest length of time."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Chargers were elected to (including replacement player) the 2006 AFC Pro Bowl from the 2006 team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 6"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "LaDainian Tomlinson finished first on the 2006 Chargers team in rushing yards. What running back finished second that year behind Tomlinson?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Turner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Philip Rivers",
      "B. Lorenzo Neal",
      "C. Andrew Pinnock",
      "D. Michael Turner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Charger led the team in receiving touchdowns in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Antonio Gates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Antonio Gates",
      "B. Keenan McCardell",
      "C. Vincent Jackson",
      "D. Eric Parker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Charger players did NOT break either the National Football League (NFL) rules or the law in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Antonio Cromartie",
    "choices": [
      "A. Terrence Kiel",
      "B. Antonio Cromartie",
      "C. Shawne Merriman",
      "D. Steve Foley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did the 2006 Chargers shut out on the road on Monday night by the score of 27-0?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oakland Raiders",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pittsburgh Steelers",
      "B. Tennessee Titans",
      "C. Oakland Raiders",
      "D. Kansas City Chiefs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Larry Bird wore which Boston Celtics number that was retired February 4, 1993?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "33",
    "choices": [
      "A. 23",
      "B. 33",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 12"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dennis Johnson, better known as DJ, played how many seasons with the Celtics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "7",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 9",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Robert Parish from the Boston Celtics was better known by his nickname. What was it?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Chief",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Chief",
      "B. The Captain",
      "C. The Boss",
      "D. The Playmaker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1985-86 season in the NBA championship saw what number title for the Boston Celtics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "16th",
    "choices": [
      "A. 20th",
      "B. 15th",
      "C. 16th",
      "D. 21st"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 1980s decade how many titles did the Celtics win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Dale Earnhardt Juniors full name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ralph Dale Earnhardt, Jr.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ralph Dale Earnhardt, Jr.",
      "B. Dale Ralph Earnhardt, Jr.",
      "C. Randall Dale Earnhardt, Jr.",
      "D. Dale Randall Earnhardt, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was Dale Earnhardt Jr. born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "October 10, 1974",
    "choices": [
      "A. October 10, 1974",
      "B. August 1, 1973",
      "C. March 28, 1980",
      "D. May 29, 1970"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Dale Earnhardt Juniors favourite football team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington Redskins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas Cowboys",
      "B. Oakland Raiders",
      "C. Carolina Panthers",
      "D. Washington Redskins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Dale Earnhardt Juniors mother?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brenda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barbara",
      "B. Brenda",
      "C. Kathy",
      "D. Kelley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Besides being co-owner of Chance 2 Motorsports, what other company does Dale Earnhardt  Jr. own?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "JR Motorsports",
    "choices": [
      "A. JR Motorsports",
      "B. Second Chance Driving",
      "C. JR Inc.",
      "D. Earnhardt Racing Co."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt Junior owns a share in the Paducah Raceway along with Tony Stewart and what other driver?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ken Schrader",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Schrader",
      "B. Mark Martin",
      "C. Michael Waltrip",
      "D. Kyle Petty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first man to win 8 gold medals at a single Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Phelps (USA, swimming)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carl Lewis (USA, track and field)",
      "B. Michael Phelps (USA, swimming)",
      "C. Alexander Dityatin (USSR, gymnastics)",
      "D. Usain Bolt (Jamaica, track and field)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tennis players was the World number one player for the most number of consecutive weeks?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Federer (Switzerland)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ivan Lendl (Czechoslovakia and USA)",
      "B. Roger Federer (Switzerland)",
      "C. Jimmy Connors (USA)",
      "D. Pete Sampras (USA)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which cyclist was diagnosed with testicle cancer, but recovered and won the prestigious Tour de France race for a record breaking 7 consecutive years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lance Armstrong (USA)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddy Merckx (Belgium)",
      "B. Miguel Indurain (Spain)",
      "C. Bernard Hinault (France)",
      "D. Lance Armstrong (USA)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the most Formula 1 Championships in the period 1985-2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Schumacher (Germany)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Schumacher (Germany)",
      "B. Fernando Alonso (Spain)",
      "C. Ayrton Senna (Brazil)",
      "D. Lewis Hamilton (UK)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won every competition they could between 2003-2007, including an Olympic Gold, 2 World Championships and 6 World League cups?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brazil, volleyball - men",
    "choices": [
      "A. Germany, soccer - men",
      "B. USA, basketball - men",
      "C. Brazil, volleyball - men",
      "D. South Korea, soccer- women"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which female pole vaulter was first to clear 5m?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yelena Isinbayeva (Russia)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stacy Dragila (USA)",
      "B. Svetlana Feofanova (Russia)",
      "C. Jennifer Stuczynski (USA)",
      "D. Yelena Isinbayeva (Russia)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Ethiopian is widely considered one of the greatest long distance runners in history?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Haile Gebrselassie",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilson Boit Kipketer",
      "B. Paavo Nurmi",
      "C. Haile Gebrselassie",
      "D. Hicham El Guerrouj"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these drivers won the most World Rally Championships and individual rallies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "SÃ©bastien Loeb (France)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carlos Sainz (Spain)",
      "B. Juha Kankkunen (Finland)",
      "C. Colin McRae (UK)",
      "D. SÃ©bastien Loeb (France)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which alpine skier is known as Herminator?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Herman Maier (Austria)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Herman Maier (Austria)",
      "B. Bode Miller (USA)",
      "C. Alberto Tomba (Italy)",
      "D. Pirmin Zurbriggen (Switzerland)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Athletes from which country took all gold medals in table tennis in the Olympic Games in 2000, 2004 and 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "China",
    "choices": [
      "A. USA",
      "B. Poland",
      "C. China",
      "D. Singapore"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which fact is true about the two baseball players named Goose?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Their playing days were separated by some 50 years.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Their playing days were separated by some 50 years.",
      "B. They both loved foie gras.",
      "C. Both were pitchers.",
      "D. Both their given names are Gander."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the baseball players known as Sparky, has the first and middle name of George Lee?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sparky Anderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sparky Anderson",
      "B. Sparky Frickshun",
      "C. Sparky Lyle",
      "D. Sparky Farkas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did baseball player Mordecai Brown get the nickname Three-Finger Brown?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "At age 7, his hand was mangled by a corn shredder.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was born with just 3 fingers on his pitching hand.",
      "B. At age 7, his hand was mangled by a corn shredder.",
      "C. For emphasis, he used to give opponents the finger, in triplicate.",
      "D. He held up 3 fingers to taunt batters before throwing them 3 straight fastballs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bubba was the birth name of how many of these eight athletes: Church, Crosby, Franks, Long, Trammell, Smith, Walton, Wells?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 0",
      "B. All",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following statements is true about the pigskin brothers, Tiki and Ronde Barber?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Both of their jock names are nicknames.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were born in a huddle.",
      "B. They are named after Hawaiian snack foods.",
      "C. They are fraternal, not identical twins.",
      "D. Both of their jock names are nicknames."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was Brett Favre born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "October 10, 1969",
    "choices": [
      "A. October 10, 1969",
      "B. September 12, 1970",
      "C. December 11, 1970",
      "D. November 11, 1969"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Brett Favre raised?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kiln, Mississippi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Burton, Alabama",
      "B. Green Bay, Wisconsin",
      "C. Kiln, Mississippi",
      "D. Memphis, Tennessee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams did Brett Favre play for in his professional career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NFL all-time records did Brett Favre set?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 16",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bret Favres first pass as a Packer was caught by this player.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Himself",
    "choices": [
      "A. Antonio Freeman",
      "B. Bubba Franks",
      "C. Himself",
      "D. Donald Driver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1999 match between Juventus and Manchester United ends in 2:3.  Which player scored first for Manchester United?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roy Keane",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Bekcham",
      "B. Roy Keane",
      "C. Ryan Giggs",
      "D. Andy Cole"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did Dennis Bergkamp join Arsenal?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1995",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1993",
      "B. 1996",
      "C. 1995",
      "D. 1991"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Premiership titles did Ryan Giggs win dirung 1990-2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 8",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many titles did Gerard Houllier win while with Liverpool?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many games and how many goals are accredited to David Beckham while playing for Manchester United",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "394-85",
    "choices": [
      "A. 500-91",
      "B. 250-65",
      "C. 394-85",
      "D. 350-35"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Arsenal bought Thierry Henry in 1999 from which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Juvenots",
    "choices": [
      "A. Inter",
      "B. Milan",
      "C. Juvenots",
      "D. Parma"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During which season did Manchester United first become English Champions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1907-08",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1910-11",
      "B. 1958-59",
      "C. 1907-08",
      "D. 1956-57"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was manager for Birmingham City during the 2004-2005 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Bruce",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Bruce",
      "B. Bryan Robson",
      "C. Steve Wigley",
      "D. David Moyes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these schools is NOT one of the original members of the Atlantic Coast Conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston",
    "choices": [
      "A. Clemson",
      "B. Duke",
      "C. North Carolina",
      "D. Boston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following schools was NOT added to the Atlantic Coast Conference in 2004 and 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Virginia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston College",
      "B. Miami",
      "C. Virginia Tech",
      "D. Virginia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these schools is NOT on the legendary Tobacco Road?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Clemson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Clemson",
      "B. Wake Forest",
      "C. The University of North Carolina (UNC)",
      "D. Duke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What school did NBA player Tim Duncan attend?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wake Forest",
    "choices": [
      "A. Virginia",
      "B. Wake Forest",
      "C. Georgia Tech",
      "D. UNC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Starting in 1999, the ACC has challenged what other power conference in a friendly, early-season tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Big 10",
    "choices": [
      "A. SEC",
      "B. Big East",
      "C. Big 10",
      "D. Pac-10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Conference did the ACC challenge in a friendly, early-season tournament prior to 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Big East",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pac-10",
      "B. Big Ten",
      "C. SEC",
      "D. Big East"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What school won the 2006 ACC Mens Basketball Tournament Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duke",
    "choices": [
      "A. NC State",
      "B. Duke",
      "C. Wake Forest",
      "D. UNC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What ACC school won the NCAA championship in 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "UNC",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maryland",
      "B. Duke",
      "C. NC State",
      "D. UNC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dean Smith was the all-time wins leader among college coaches until Bobby Knight surpassed him on January 1, 2007. How many seasons did Smith coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "36",
    "choices": [
      "A. 36",
      "B. 37",
      "C. 38",
      "D. 39"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Commissioner of Major League Baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kenesaw Mountain Landis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kenesaw Mountain Landis",
      "B. Bowie Kent Kuhn",
      "C. A.B. Happy Chandler",
      "D. Lt. Gen. William D. Eckert"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This commissioner barred both Willie Mays and Mickey Mantle from baseball due to the their involvement in a casino promotion.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bowie K. Kuhn",
    "choices": [
      "A. A. Bartlett Giamatti",
      "B. Bowie K. Kuhn",
      "C. Fay Vincent",
      "D. Ford C. Frick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Baseball commissioners have been lawyers, governors, lieutenants and successful businessmen. Which one of these received a doctorate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A. Bartlett Giamatti",
    "choices": [
      "A. Peter V. Ueberroth",
      "B. Bud Selig",
      "C. A.B. Happy Chandler",
      "D. A. Bartlett Giamatti"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which baseball commissioner was widely criticized for refusing to cancel games following the assassinations of Martin Luther King and Robert Kennedy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lt. Gen. William D. Eckert",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lt. Gen. William D. Eckert",
      "B. A.B. Happy Chandler",
      "C. Bowie K. Kuhn",
      "D. Ford C. Frick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Baseball Hall of Fame honored this commissioner with an annual award bearing his name presented to a baseball broadcaster for major contributions to the game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ford C. Frick",
    "choices": [
      "A. A. Bartlett Giamatti",
      "B. Ford C. Frick",
      "C. A.B. Happy Chandler",
      "D. Kenesaw Mountain Landis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball commissioner played a vital role in convincing the Chicago Cubs to install lights at the Wrigley Field stadium instead of reimbursing the league for lost night games.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Peter V. Ueberroth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fay T. Vincent",
      "B. Bud Selig",
      "C. A. Bartlett Giamatti",
      "D. Peter V. Ueberroth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1990, this commissioner banned New York Yankees owner George Steinbrenner from baseball for life.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fay T. Vincent",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bud Selig",
      "B. Fay T. Vincent",
      "C. Bowie Kuhn",
      "D. A. Bartlett Giamatti"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When were the first formal rules of basketball devised?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1892",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1940",
      "B. 1903",
      "C. 1892",
      "D. 1935"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first NBA Championship game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1947",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1937",
      "B. 1905",
      "C. 1947",
      "D. 1889"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Already a permanent part of the American Basketball Association, the 3-point shot was instituted by the NBA in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1980",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1955",
      "B. 1980",
      "C. 1965",
      "D. 1977"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former Houston Astros player was nicknamed The Toy Cannon?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmy Wynn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jose Cruz",
      "B. Jimmy Wynn",
      "C. Nolan Ryan",
      "D. Jim Umbricht"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these players won an MVP Award while playing with the Houston Astros?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Bagwell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jose Cruz",
      "B. Jeff Kent",
      "C. Nolan Ryan",
      "D. Jeff Bagwell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Houston Astros player to be inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Morgan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Abbott",
      "B. Joe Morgan",
      "C. Jacob Nelson Nellie Fox",
      "D. Carl Everett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Houston Astros player ever to win the Rookie of the Year Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Bagwell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Craig Biggio",
      "B. Brad Ausmus",
      "C. Lance Berkman",
      "D. Jeff Bagwell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In his career, Nolan Ryan had 5,714 strikeouts. How many of them came while he played with the Houston Astros?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1866",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000",
      "B. 1866",
      "C. 2745",
      "D. 1296"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these pitchers has won a Cy Young Award in 2004, while playing for the Houston Astros?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Clemens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Clemens",
      "B. Randy Johnson",
      "C. Eric Gagne",
      "D. None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first baseball player to hit a home run in Minute Maid Park?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scott Rolen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Scott Rolen",
      "B. Richard Hidalgo",
      "C. Barry Bonds",
      "D. Jeff Bagwell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Houston Astros Manager?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harry Craft",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harry Craft",
      "B. Phil Garner",
      "C. Hal Lanier",
      "D. Leo Durocher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 2 NHL teams faced off in a preseason game in London, England, in 1992?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Blackhawks vs. Montreal Canadians",
    "choices": [
      "A. Edmonton Oilers vs. Calgary Flames",
      "B. Chicago Blackhawks vs. Montreal Canadians",
      "C. Toronto Maple Leafs vs. Boston Bruins",
      "D. Vancouver Canucks vs. Detroit Red Wings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these womens names was not engraved on the Stanley Cup in the period from 2001-2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Karen Hughes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Charlotte Grahame",
      "B. Kelly Kirwin",
      "C. Karen Hughes",
      "D. Sonia Scurfield"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the Detroit Red Wings nickname from 1926 to 1930?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cougars",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cardinals",
      "B. Falcons",
      "C. Cougars",
      "D. Shamrocks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was the longest overtime game in the Stanley Cup playoffs played, prior to the 2006/2007 seasons playoffs.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1936",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1967",
      "B. 1973",
      "C. 2006",
      "D. 1936"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the Conn Smythe Trophy awarded to every year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The MVP in the Stanley Cup Playoffs",
    "choices": [
      "A. The MVP for the regular season.",
      "B. The MVP in the Stanley Cup Playoffs",
      "C. The top goalie",
      "D. The top rookie"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During what period of time did the original Ottawa Senators franchise run?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1917-1934",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1920-1925",
      "B. 1915-1926",
      "C. 1917-1934",
      "D. 1919-1920"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the 1st  European-born hockey player to be drafted first overall in the NHL entry draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mats Sundin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mats Sundin",
      "B. Ulf DahlÃ©n",
      "C. Jari Kurri",
      "D. Jaromir Jagr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the International Olympic Committee founded?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1894",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1896",
      "B. 1894",
      "C. 1898",
      "D. 1900"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Beijing 2008 Olympic Games have been scheduled to include 28 sports and how many separate events?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "301-350",
    "choices": [
      "A. 301-350",
      "B. 151-200",
      "C. 201-250",
      "D. 251-300"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "80% of the competitors in the 1904 Olympic games were from which country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. The USA",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. Australia",
      "D. France"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Roughly how many television viewers watched the 2000 Olympic Games in Sydney, Australia over the whole course of the event?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3.8 billion",
    "choices": [
      "A. 38 billion",
      "B. 3.8 billion",
      "C. 38 million",
      "D. 3.8 million"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which were the first modern Olympic Games to be subject to a boycott by more than one country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1956, Melbourne",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1980, Moscow",
      "B. 1936, Berlin",
      "C. 1920, Antwerp",
      "D. 1956, Melbourne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Members of which Olympic team were taken hostage by the terrorist group Black September during the 1972 Munich games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Israel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ethiopia",
      "B. United States of America",
      "C. Canada",
      "D. Israel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Olympic Flame was introduced in 1928 and carrying it in a relay in the lead-up to each game began in 1936. Where in Greece is the flame lit at the start of the relay?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Olympia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rhodes",
      "B. Olympia",
      "C. Olympus",
      "D. Athens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Olympic motto Citius, Altius, Fortius embodies the spirit of the Olympic movement. What is the English translation of these Latin words?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Swifter, Higher, Stronger",
    "choices": [
      "A. Swifter, Higher, Stronger",
      "B. Quicker, Shorter, Better",
      "C. Faster, Taller, Tougher",
      "D. Bigger, Better, Cleaner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1913, this young athlete became the first American-born golfer to win the US Open.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Francis Ouimet",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harry Vardon",
      "B. Francis Ouimet",
      "C. Arnold Palmer",
      "D. Gene Sarazen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which professional golfer was known as The Hawk?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ben Hogan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Byron Nelson",
      "B. Ben Hogan",
      "C. Babe Didrickson",
      "D. Fred Couples"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first professional golfer to win all four professional major championships, known as a Career Grand Slam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gene Sarazen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ben Hogan",
      "B. Bobby Jones",
      "C. Gene Sarazen",
      "D. Jack Nicklaus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This excellent amateur golfer who instituted his clambake at Rancho Santa Fe in San Diego died after a round of eighteen holes of golf in Madrid, Spain. His last words were reported as, That was a great game of golf, fellas.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bing Crosby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bing Crosby",
      "B. Bob Hope",
      "C. Bobby Jones",
      "D. Francis Ouimet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A natural right-hander, this golfer plays left-handed, probably because he copied his fathers swing. He was the second left-handed golfer to win the Masters.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phil Mickelson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Furyk",
      "B. Corey Pavin",
      "C. Retief Goosen",
      "D. Phil Mickelson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the home stadium of the New York Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shea Stadium",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yankee Stadium",
      "B. Shea Stadium",
      "C. Wrigley Field",
      "D. Fenway Park"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these NBA teams is not in the Atlantic Division of the Eastern Conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miami",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston",
      "B. Philadelphia",
      "C. Miami",
      "D. Toronto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player held the record for the most consecutive 30 home run seasons in Major League history after the completion of the 2007 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Barry Bonds",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Frank Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Upon the conclusion of the 2007 season, who held the Major League Baseball rookie record for most home runs hit in a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark McGwire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cecil Fielder",
      "B. Alex Rodriguez",
      "C. Mark McGwire",
      "D. Ryan Howard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these baseball players did not lead the majors in home runs at least 3 consecutive years in a row?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Schmidt",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Ralph Kiner",
      "D. Hank Aaron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first major leaguer to hit two grand slams in the same inning?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fernando Tatis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Robin Ventura",
      "B. Reggie Jackson",
      "C. Todd Hundley",
      "D. Fernando Tatis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Major Leaguer broke the career record for the most seasons with 40 or more home runs with 11 consecutive seasons?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alex Rodriguez",
      "B. Hank Aaron",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Barry Bonds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following catchers had the most home runs during his MLB career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Piazza",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johhny Bench",
      "B. Mike Piazza",
      "C. Carlton Fisk",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Major League Baseball slugger had the lowest average at-bats per home run ratio in his career for 2007? In other words, this mans at-bats have resulted in home runs more often than any other player in MLB history.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark McGwire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barry Bonds",
      "B. Alex Rodriguiz",
      "C. Ken Griffey Jr.",
      "D. Mark McGwire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players had NOT hit over 50 home runs in a single Major League Baseball season by the conclusion of the 2007 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carlos Delgado",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carlos Delgado",
      "B. Jimmy Foxx",
      "C. Ryan Howard",
      "D. Ken Griffey Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After the 2007 season there were two people tied for the most games with 3 or more home runs in MLB history.  Which of the players listed below is a co-owner of that record?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sammy Sosa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe Ruth",
      "B. Barry Bonds",
      "C. Sammy Sosa",
      "D. Mickey Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the only slugger in the following list that has had a 50+ home run season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Andruw Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mo Vaughn",
      "B. Frank Thomas",
      "C. Jay Buhner",
      "D. Andruw Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these sluggers never hit for at least 40 home runs in a single MLB season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Carter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Matthews",
      "B. Jose Canseco",
      "C. Reggie Jackson",
      "D. Joe Carter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All of the following players have at least 50 home runs in a season. Which one of these has the lowest overall career home run total?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Maris",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Maris",
      "B. Greg Vaughn",
      "C. Albert Belle",
      "D. Johnny Mize"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of the players listed below, who has the most career MLB home runs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sammy Sosa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rafael Palmeiro",
      "B. Mickey Mantle",
      "C. Sammy Sosa",
      "D. Frank Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players did not hit 4 home runs in one game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mickey Mantle",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Carlos Delgado",
      "D. Lou Gehrig"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mark Bellhorn hit a home run from each side of the plate in a single inning.  Who is the other switch hitter to have accomplished this feat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carlos Baerga",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chipper Jones",
      "B. Carlos Baerga",
      "C. Ruben Sierra",
      "D. Jorge Posada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players has NOT hit over 50 home runs in a single MLB season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of them have accomplished this feat.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ralph Kiner",
      "B. Jim Thome",
      "C. All of them have accomplished this feat.",
      "D. Mickey Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Several Major Leaguers have had multiple 50-plus home run seasons. Which player listed below has NOT accomplished this feat at least 3 times?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barry Bonds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe Ruth",
      "B. Mark McGwire",
      "C. Barry Bonds",
      "D. Alex Rodriguez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Major League players has NOT had multiple seasons in which he hit 50 or more home runs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Gehrig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Gehrig",
      "B. Jimmie Foxx",
      "C. Ken Griffey Jr.",
      "D. Micky Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following baseball players led or co-led their league in home runs in the most consecutive years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ralph Kinner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe Ruth",
      "B. Harmon Killibrew",
      "C. Willie Mays",
      "D. Ralph Kinner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the MLB players below has NOT hit at least 200 home runs in both the AL and the NL?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sammy Sosa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sammy Sosa",
      "B. Frank Robinson",
      "C. Fred McGriff",
      "D. Mark McGwire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following players reached the 200+ home run career mark?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tim Wallach",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bo Jackson",
      "B. Tim Wallach",
      "C. John Kruk",
      "D. Matt Nokes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How much did Manchester United pay PSV Eindhoven for Ruud Van Nistelrooy in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "19 million pounds",
    "choices": [
      "A. 20 million pounds",
      "B. 19 million pounds",
      "C. 18 million pounds",
      "D. 200 000 pounds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many goals did Denis Law score during his 11 seasons with Manchester United?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "239",
    "choices": [
      "A. 239",
      "B. 260",
      "C. 240",
      "D. 179"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Only one of the combinations (player  - his 2003/2004 squad number) is correct, which one?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Solskjaer  - 20",
    "choices": [
      "A. G. Nevilee - 3",
      "B. Solskjaer  - 20",
      "C. Keane - 17",
      "D. Beckham - 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 1963-64 season, he set the United record for most goals in one season -- 46.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Denis Law",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ruud Van Nistelrooy",
      "B. Bobi Charlton",
      "C. Erik Cantona",
      "D. Denis Law"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who scored a hat-trick when United trashed Southampton 6-1 i the 2001 premiership?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ruud Van Nistelrooy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ruud Van Nistelrooy",
      "B. Andy Cole",
      "C. Paul Scholes",
      "D. Ryan Giggs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What talented NHL player, future Hall of Famer, held the record for longest-serving captain in 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Yzerman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wayne Gretzky",
      "B. Steve Yzerman",
      "C. Mario Lemuiex",
      "D. Gordie Howe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1956, this city set a new record for the most fans at a baseball game - 114,000.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Melbourne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mexico City",
      "B. New York City",
      "C. Melbourne",
      "D. Osaka"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is the first baseball player to be caught stealing a base at least 355 times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rickey Henderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Brock",
      "B. Rickey Henderson",
      "C. Ty Cobb",
      "D. Minnie Minoso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From 1988-1989 this player set a new Major League record for most consecutive bases stolen without being thrown out.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vince Coleman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vince Coleman",
      "B. Lou Brock",
      "C. Ichiro Suzuki",
      "D. Rickey Henderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1955 this baseball Hall of Famer broke the record for most consecutive times struck out.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sandy Koufax",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Keeler",
      "B. Cy Young",
      "C. Sandy Koufax",
      "D. Nolan Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is the first baseball player to strike out at least 2,597 times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Reggie Jackson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Stargell",
      "B. Reggie Jackson",
      "C. Hank Aaron",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which baseball player became the first to hit at least 20 home runs in a month?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sammy Sosa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sammy Sosa",
      "B. Ken Griffey, Jr.",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Ken Griffey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tommy Brown broke the Major League record for the youngest person to hit a home run. How old was he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "17 years, 2 months and 7 days",
    "choices": [
      "A. 15 years, 4 months and 19 days",
      "B. 16 years, 4 months and 11 days",
      "C. 18 years, 6 months and 122 days",
      "D. 17 years, 2 months and 7 days"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first professional baseball player to hit at least 24 home runs while a still teenager?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Conigliaro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mel Ott",
      "B. Gil McDougald",
      "C. Tony Conigliaro",
      "D. Ken Griffey, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Goose Goslin and this man are the only Major League baseball players to hit into 4 double plays in a single game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Torre",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Torre",
      "B. Frank Torre",
      "C. Frank Howard",
      "D. Reggie Jackson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player became the first to hit into 350 double plays in a Major League baseball career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cal Ripken,  Jr.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Rice",
      "B. Cal Ripken,  Jr.",
      "C. Hank Aaron",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which baseball player became the first pitcher to throw 277 wild pitches?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nolan Ryan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Phil Niekro",
      "B. Jack Morris",
      "C. Juan Guzman",
      "D. Nolan Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Many pitchers have been great fielders. This man is the first pitcher to be involved in 94 double plays.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greg Maddux",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harvey Haddix",
      "B. Bobby Shantz",
      "C. Jim Kaat",
      "D. Greg Maddux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This man has the record achievement of over 14,000 Major League at-bats.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cal Ripken, Jr.",
      "B. Carl Yastrzemski",
      "C. Minnie Minoso",
      "D. Pete Rose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which great infielder broke the record for the most at-bats in a season in 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmy Rollins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jose Reyes",
      "B. Pete Rose",
      "C. Miguel Tejada",
      "D. Jimmy Rollins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first man to run a mile in under 4 minutes?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Bannister",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Hayes",
      "B. Roger Bannister",
      "C. Jim  Thorpe",
      "D. Marcel Coe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first intercollegiate basketball game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "January 18, 1896",
    "choices": [
      "A. January 18, 1907",
      "B. January 18, 1896",
      "C. January 18, 1904",
      "D. January 18, 1885"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first intercollegiate womens basketball game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "April 4, 1896",
    "choices": [
      "A. April 4, 1906",
      "B. April 4, 1916",
      "C. April 4, 1896",
      "D. April 4, 1926"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These two colleges played in the first intercollegiate nine-person baseball game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fordham University and St. Francis Xavier University.",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Pittsburgh and Youngstown State University",
      "B. Cincinnati University and The University of Akron",
      "C. Rutgers University and Princeton University",
      "D. Fordham University and St. Francis Xavier University."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who scored the first three-point shot in the NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Ford",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chris Ford",
      "B. Larry Bird",
      "C. JoJo White",
      "D. Reggie Miller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first goal in a NHL game scored?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "December 19,1917",
    "choices": [
      "A. December 19,1917",
      "B. December 19 , 1942",
      "C. December 19 , 1936",
      "D. December 19,1924"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NHL goalie to get a shutout?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Georges Vezina",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Stanley",
      "B. Charlie Broadieaux",
      "C. Georges Vezina",
      "D. Gump Worsley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the first game played under NFL rules take place?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "February 25, 1933",
    "choices": [
      "A. February 24 , 1939",
      "B. February 25, 1943",
      "C. February 25, 1946",
      "D. February 25, 1933"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two teams played in the first NFL championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bears and the New York Giants",
    "choices": [
      "A. Canton Bulldogs and the Chicago Cardinals",
      "B. Chicago Bears and the  Boston Tigers",
      "C. Chicago Bears and the New York Giants",
      "D. Canton Bulldogs and the Providence Steamrolles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first African American NFL quarterback?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie Thrower",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Tosser",
      "B. Marlin Briscoe",
      "C. Doug Williams",
      "D. Willie Thrower"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On September 17, 1948 Greenbay played Boston in an NFL game. What was the significance of the game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was the first time a penalty flag was thrown.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was the first time a NFL game that went into overtime.",
      "B. It was the first time a penalty flag was thrown.",
      "C. It was the first time an interception was returned for a touchdown.",
      "D. It was the first NFL game to be on radio."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about major league baseball pitcher Danny Graves?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was the first major leaguer from Vietnam.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was the first MLB player to toss a shutout in his first three  games.",
      "B. He was the first major leaguer from Vietnam.",
      "C. He was the first major leaguer from New Zealand.",
      "D. He was the first major league pitcher to hit a grandslam home run in his first MLB game."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Many  major league baseball players  are from the Dominican Republic. Who was the first major leaguer from the Dominican Republic?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ozzie Virgil",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ozzie Virgil",
      "B. Umberto Pena",
      "C. Chico Fernandez",
      "D. Rodrico Humberro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first major league baseball player from Japan?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Masanori Murakami",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hideki Irabu",
      "B. Hideki Nomo",
      "C. Masanori Murakami",
      "D. Yashigawa Tabata"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these NBA teams originated in Minnesota?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Lakers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta Hawks",
      "B. Los Angeles Lakers",
      "C. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "D. Memphis Grizzlies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Minnesota Twins have produced four American League MVPs--Zoilo Versalles (1965), Harmon Killebrew (1969) and Rod Carew (1977) are three of them. Name the fourth.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Justin Morneau",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Oliva",
      "B. Frank Viola",
      "C. Kirby Puckett",
      "D. Justin Morneau"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which athlete on a Minnesota team is nicknamed The Big Ticket?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kevin Garnett",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seimone Augustus",
      "B. Kevin Garnett",
      "C. Marian Gaborik",
      "D. Torii Hunter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two years the Minnesota Twins won the World Baseball Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1987  1991",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1987  1991",
      "B. 1986  1990",
      "C. 1980  1985",
      "D. 1988  1992"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real name of professional wrestler Kelly Kelly?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barbara Blank",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kelly Blank",
      "B. Shannon Brooks",
      "C. Barbara Blank",
      "D. Carly Colon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real name of professional wrestler Jeff Hardy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jeff Hardy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Fatu",
      "B. Sean Morley",
      "C. Jeff Hardy",
      "D. Jayson Paul"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real name of the professional wrestler known as the Boogeyman?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Martin Wright",
    "choices": [
      "A. James Gibson",
      "B. Brian Myers",
      "C. Cliff Compton",
      "D. Martin Wright"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the distance between the free throw line and the front of the rim in a standard basketball court?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14.9 ft",
    "choices": [
      "A. 149 m",
      "B. 15 ft",
      "C. 149 yd",
      "D. 14.9 ft"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not among the many ways of getting a lane violation in basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "On defense when you are in the key for more than three seconds not guarding someone",
    "choices": [
      "A. On a free throw when you cross the line before the shooter has shot",
      "B. On a free throw when the shooter crosses the free throw line before the ball hits the rim",
      "C. On defense when you are in the key for more than three seconds not guarding someone",
      "D. When you stand in the key on offense for more than three seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the size in circumference of the standard NBA basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "29 1/2 to 29 3/4 (74.9 to 76.8 cm)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 29 3/4 to 30 (76.8 to 76.2 cm)",
      "B. 29 1/2 to 29 3/4 (74.9 to 76.8 cm)",
      "C. 30 to 31 (76.2 to 78.7 cm)",
      "D. 29 to 29 3/4 (73.6 to 76.8 cm)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1984, FIBA introduced to basketball regulations the three-point line. What is its length from the center of the basket?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "20 ft 6 in (6.25 m)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 16 ft 7 in (5.05 m)",
      "B. 23 ft 9 in (7.23 m)",
      "C. 7 ft 1 in (2.15 m)",
      "D. 20 ft 6 in (6.25 m)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt, Jr. has a sister, half brother and half sister. What are their names?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kelley, Kerry and Taylor",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ann, Jimmy and Monica",
      "B. Kathy, Jeff and Tara",
      "C. Kelley, Kerry and Taylor",
      "D. Susie, Mike and Carol"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Dale Earnhardt, Jr.s real first name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ralph",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ralph",
      "B. James",
      "C. Michael",
      "D. Albert"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the book co-written by Dale Earnhardt, Jr. documenting his rookie season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Driver #8",
    "choices": [
      "A. My Life as a NASCAR Driver",
      "B. Life In the Fast Lane",
      "C. My Rookie Season",
      "D. Driver #8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the collective nickname of  Dale Earnhardt, Jr.s friends from his hometown?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dirty Mo Posse",
    "choices": [
      "A. Magnificent 7",
      "B. Dirty Mo Posse",
      "C. Three Musketeers",
      "D. Beach Bums"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Earnhardt, Jr. won his first NASCAR Cup Series race at which track in 2000?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Texas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Texas",
      "B. Bristol",
      "C. Darlington",
      "D. Richmond"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From 2000-2007, Dale Earnhardt, Jr. drove for what famous sponsor?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Budweiser",
    "choices": [
      "A. Budweiser",
      "B. Miller",
      "C. Pepsi",
      "D. Coca-Cola"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Detroit is the capital of the US automotive industry. The Detroit basketball team is named after what car parts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pistons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cylinders",
      "B. Wheels",
      "C. Pistons",
      "D. Brakes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "London football clubs usually bear the name of the district their stadium is located in. Which of these teams is not based in London?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Aston Villa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chelsea",
      "B. Aston Villa",
      "C. Tottenham",
      "D. Fulham"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team is known as All Blacks?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Zealand, rugby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Zimbabwe, football",
      "B. USA, basketball",
      "C. New Zealand, rugby",
      "D. Pakistan, cricket"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Philadelphia 76ers are a basketball team. What does 76 represent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1776, the year the Declaration of Independence was signed",
    "choices": [
      "A. The age of Danny Biasone when he founded the team",
      "B. 1976, the year in which the club was established",
      "C. The amount of money (in thousands) the teams founders had",
      "D. 1776, the year the Declaration of Independence was signed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Many Spanish sport clubs are named Real. What does it mean in Spanish?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Royal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Royal",
      "B. Soccer",
      "C. Sport",
      "D. Real"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "African national football teams usually have a nickname. Which countrys footballers are known as Bafana, Bafana (The Boys)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Africa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cameroon",
      "B. Ghana",
      "C. Nigeria",
      "D. South Africa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The nickname Dream Team is most often associated with which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "USA, basketball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil, volleyball",
      "B. USA, basketball",
      "C. India, cricket",
      "D. Germany, football"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Celtic and The Rangers are rival clubs from which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Glasgow",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston",
      "B. New York",
      "C. Arlington (Texas)",
      "D. Glasgow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city is home of Panathinaikos Sport Club?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Athens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pana City (Illinois)",
      "B. Athens",
      "C. Palo Alto",
      "D. San Antonio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Canadian club dominated the NHL during the 1980s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edmonton Oilers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montreal Benzins",
      "B. Edmonton Oilers",
      "C. Ottawa Diesels",
      "D. Calgary Gasolines"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bayern is a top German football team located in Munich. What is the meaning of its name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is the German name of Bavaria, the region Munich is capital of.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It is an adjective form of Bayer, a German pharmaceutical company.",
      "B. It is the German name of Bavaria, the region Munich is capital of.",
      "C. It commemorates Johann Bayer, a German astronomer.",
      "D. It means Beer Drinkers in local dialect."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "National teams of which country are known in most sports as squadra azzura (blue team)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Italy",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. Spain",
      "C. Italy",
      "D. Greece"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two teams played in the first NBA game in 1946?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York Knicks and Toronto Huskies",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Knicks and Boston Celtics",
      "B. Boston Celtics and Toronto Huskies",
      "C. Philidelphia Warrior and New York Knicks",
      "D. New York Knicks and Toronto Huskies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who scored the first basket in the first NBA game in 1946?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ossie Scechtman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Kurland",
      "B. George Mikan",
      "C. Ossie Scechtman",
      "D. Paul Arizan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the first NBA Championship in 1947?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Philadelphia Warriors",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Knicks",
      "B. Philadelphia Warriors",
      "C. Minneapolis Lakers",
      "D. Boston Celtics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first African-American to play in an NBA game in 1950?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Earl Lloyd",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nat Sweetwater Clifton",
      "B. Chuck Cooper",
      "C. Earl Lloyd",
      "D. Don Barksdale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to average a triple double for an entire season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oscar Robertson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "B. Oscar Robertson",
      "C. Elgin Baylor",
      "D. Bill Russell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to win Rookie of the Year and MVP in the same season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Elgin Baylor",
      "B. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. Bill Russell",
      "D. Jerry West"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to win the Finals MVP award in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerry West",
    "choices": [
      "A. Elgin Baylor",
      "B. Jerry West",
      "C. Sam Jones",
      "D. Bill Russell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to win MVP, All Star MVP, and Finals MVP in the same season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willis Reed",
    "choices": [
      "A. Magic Johnson",
      "B. Willis Reed",
      "C. Shaquille Oneal",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first woman drafted to the NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ann Meyers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lynette Woodard",
      "B. Cheryl Miller",
      "C. it never happened",
      "D. Ann Meyers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1979, this Boston Celtics player scored the first 3 point basket in the NBA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Ford",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Havlicek",
      "B. Jo Jo White",
      "C. Larry Bird",
      "D. Chris Ford"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the first NBA slam dunk contest in 1984?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Larry Nance",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Jordan",
      "B. Larry Nance",
      "C. Julius Erving",
      "D. Dominique Wilkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first repeat winner of the slam dunk contest?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Jordan",
      "B. Jason Richardson",
      "C. Spud Webb",
      "D. Dominique Wilkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first player to score 20,000 career points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Pettit",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry West",
      "B. George Mikan",
      "C. Bob Pettit",
      "D. Oscar Robertson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first center to lead the NBA in assists for a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willis Reed",
      "B. Bill Walton",
      "C. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "D. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to record a quadruple double in a game (double digits in 4 stat categories)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nate Thurmond",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nate Thurmond",
      "B. David Robinson",
      "C. Alvin Robertson",
      "D. Hakeem Olajuwon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This infielder came to the New York Mets from the Dodgers in December 1983.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ross Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carlos Diaz",
      "B. Billy Almon",
      "C. Ross Jones",
      "D. Buddy Biancalana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This catcher was traded to the Mets by the Cubs in 1986 for starting pitcher Ed Lynch.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dave Liddell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Hodges",
      "B. Butch Wynegar",
      "C. Alex Trevino",
      "D. Dave Liddell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 20-year-old first baseman made his debut for the New York Mets during the 1974 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brock Pemberton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rudy Pemberton",
      "B. Lou Brock",
      "C. Brock Pemberton",
      "D. Greg Brock"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Originally drafted by the Detroit Tigers, this baseman joined the New York Mets in 1997 just for one game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kevin Morgan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Morgan",
      "B. Aurelio Rodriguez",
      "C. Howard Johnson",
      "D. Kevin Morgan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which 68 reliever played for the New York Mets during the 1992 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Vitko",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Vitko",
      "B. Eric Hillman",
      "C. Randy Johnson",
      "D. Spud Webb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This spare outfielder came to the Mets on June 15, 1977 as part of the infamous Tom Seaver trade with the Reds. He hit only .230 in four seasons at Shea.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dan Norman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Henderson",
      "B. Dan Norman",
      "C. Ellis Valentine",
      "D. Joel Youngblood"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players was a pinch running specialist for the 1992 New York Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rodney McCray",
    "choices": [
      "A. Len Dykstra",
      "B. Joe Orsulak",
      "C. Rodney McCray",
      "D. Richie Ashburn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although the New York Mets drafted this right hander in 1978, he was 29 years old by the time he made his major league debut in 1986.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rick Anderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Craig",
      "B. Bruce Berenyi",
      "C. Rick Anderson",
      "D. Calvin Schiraldi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player, born in Venezuela, played for the New York Mets in 1962?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elio Chacon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Elio Chacon",
      "B. Luis Aparicio",
      "C. Rafael Santana",
      "D. Kevin Elster"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was 30 years old when he broke into the big leagues on September 14, 2003, with the New York Mets.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Glavine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Berra",
      "B. Tommie Aaron",
      "C. Mike Glavine",
      "D. Tony Piazza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Ted Williamsâ number on the Boston Red Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "9",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 11",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not one of Ted Williams nicknames?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Boston Bomber",
    "choices": [
      "A. Teddy Ballgame",
      "B. The Boston Bomber",
      "C. The Kid",
      "D. Splendid Splinter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which branch of the military did Ted Williams serve?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marines",
    "choices": [
      "A. Navy",
      "B. Army",
      "C. Marines",
      "D. Air Force"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was Ted Williams inducted into The Major league Baseball Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1965",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1966",
      "B. 1964",
      "C. 1965",
      "D. 1967"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Ted Williams debut with the Boston Red Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1939",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1937",
      "B. 1939",
      "C. 1940",
      "D. 1941"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After Ted Williams retired from play, he went on to manage what major league team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington Senators",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Fransisco Giants",
      "B. Washington Senators",
      "C. Minnesota Twins",
      "D. San Diego Padres"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these baseball players was known as The Bird?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark Fidrych",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Hamiliton",
      "B. Joe Medwick",
      "C. Howard Earl Averill",
      "D. Mark Fidrych"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Ted Williams nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Splendid Splinter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mr. 400",
      "B. The Georgia Peach",
      "C. The Great Man",
      "D. The Splendid Splinter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pitcher was known as Old Pete?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Grover Cleveland Alexander",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pee Wee Reese",
      "B. Cap Anson",
      "C. Grover Cleveland Alexander",
      "D. Pete Incaviglia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mad Hungarian was the nickname given to which of these ballplayers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Al Hrabosky",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Hrabosky",
      "B. Greg Maddux",
      "C. Rafael Furcal",
      "D. Rube Marquard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these was the nickname of Fred Merkle?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bonehead",
    "choices": [
      "A. Knucklehead",
      "B. Bonehead",
      "C. Swellhead",
      "D. Fathead"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of pitcher Mordecai Brown?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Three Finger",
    "choices": [
      "A. Two Finger",
      "B. One Finger",
      "C. Five Finger",
      "D. Three Finger"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Babe Ruth had many nicknames such as The Babe, The Bambino, The Sultan of Swat. Can you pick out another one of his nicknames?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Colossus of Clout",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Colossus of Clout",
      "B. The Wizard of Clout",
      "C. The Strongman of Clout",
      "D. The Clout Master"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these ballplayers has the nicknames Mr. November, Captain Clutch and D-Jitty?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Derek Jeter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Darrell Rasner",
      "B. Dazzy Vance",
      "C. Davey Johnson",
      "D. Derek Jeter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these medical items is the nickname of Doug Mientkiewicz?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eye Chart",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ear Plugs",
      "B. Eye Chart",
      "C. Syringe",
      "D. Stethoscope"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these baseball nicknames comes from a 1990 hit movie?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hot Diggerty Dog",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pat the Bat",
      "B. O-Dog",
      "C. Hot Diggerty Dog",
      "D. The Perfect Storm"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This precision sport, played on ice with polished heavy stones, is especially well established in Canada.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Curling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Skeleton",
      "B. Curling",
      "C. Skibob",
      "D. Luge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Snowboarding, an increasingly common extreme sport, became an official Olympic Games sport at which Winter Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1998 Winter Olympics (Japan)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2002 Winter Olympics (USA)",
      "B. 1984 Winter Olympics (Norway)",
      "C. 1992 Winter Olympics (France)",
      "D. 1998 Winter Olympics (Japan)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This winter sport, which traces its origins to an exercise for Norwegian soldiers, combines cross-country skiing and rifle shooting.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Biathlon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nordic combined",
      "B. Biathlon",
      "C. Skeleton",
      "D. Duathlon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the sport of figure skating, what is the term for a jump which includes a one-half extra rotation, generally considered to be the hardest one?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Axel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Salchow",
      "B. Flip",
      "C. Axel",
      "D. Lutz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This sport, one of the fastest in the world, is the official national winter sport of Canada.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ice hockey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Curling",
      "B. Ice hockey",
      "C. Bobsleigh",
      "D. Biathlon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This most popular skiing style, offered by many resorts, is used for recreation among both professionals and non-professionals.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alpine skiing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cross country skiing",
      "B. Freestyle skiing",
      "C. Alpine skiing",
      "D. Skijoring"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This winter sport is the second fastest non-motorized sport on Earth, after speed skydiving.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Speed skiing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Speed skating",
      "B. Freestyle skiing",
      "C. Speed skiing",
      "D. Bobsleigh"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In dogsled racing, a timed competition of teams consisting of a number of sleddogs and a dog driver, what is the name of the short neckline snapped to each dogâs collar?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "neckline",
    "choices": [
      "A. neckline",
      "B. shock cord",
      "C. gangline",
      "D. tugline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mets won how many regular season games en route to their postseason and title?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "108",
    "choices": [
      "A. 108",
      "B. 109",
      "C. 106",
      "D. 107"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The catcher Gary Carter, who wore number 8, was a powerful hitter.  He sent one over the green monster at Fenway Park during the World Series.  Which team did the Mets acquire him from?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Montreal Expos",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montreal Expos",
      "B. Kansas City Royals",
      "C. Philadelphia Phillies",
      "D. Florida Marlins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did the Mets beat to win the NL pennant and reach the World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Houston Astros",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston Astros",
      "B. Cincinnati Reds",
      "C. Los Angeles Dodgers",
      "D. Atlanta Braves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who served as the Mets pitching coach in 1986?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mel Stottlemeyer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Robinson",
      "B. Sid Fernandez",
      "C. Rick Peterson",
      "D. Mel Stottlemeyer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who screamed the now famous words, Struck em out! Struck em out! The Mets have won the World Series!?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Murphy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Howie Rose",
      "B. Ralph Kiner",
      "C. Bob Murphy",
      "D. Gary Thorne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This sport, whereby the player navigates the playing field on horseback, is the national game of Argentina.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pato",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pato",
      "B. Kosho",
      "C. Parkour",
      "D. Hapkido"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Canyoning is the extreme sport of travelling down canyons, using which of the following techniques?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jumping",
      "B. Abseiling",
      "C. All of these",
      "D. Scrambling and climbing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following sports is a fictional one and exists only in the imaginary world of a popular US science fiction movie?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Podracing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Air Racing",
      "B. Ringo",
      "C. Cyclocross",
      "D. Podracing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the rules of the International Skating Union, major speed skating competitions can be held  on outdoor or indoor ice ovals, of what standard length?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "400 m (1,310 ft)",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1000 m (3,280 ft)",
      "B. 700 m (2,300 ft)",
      "C. 400 m (1,310 ft)",
      "D. 500 m (1,640 ft)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pole vaulting, an athletics jumping discipline event, in which competitors use a long, flexible pole to leap over a bar, is under what number in the decathlon order?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eight",
    "choices": [
      "A. Three",
      "B. Four",
      "C. Eight",
      "D. Nine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kart racing, a sport that originated in the 1950s in the United States, was created and popularised in which of these professional fields?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Military air forces",
    "choices": [
      "A. Military medics",
      "B. Military mechanicians",
      "C. Infantry",
      "D. Military air forces"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Susan Oliver, an American actress and television director of the 50s and 60s, was keen on what unusual sport?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Air racing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Skydiving",
      "B. Sumo",
      "C. Motocross",
      "D. Air racing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Parkour, a relatively new sport of physical strength and agility, is usually practised in what kind of surroundings?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Urban areas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fields",
      "B. Deserts",
      "C. Urban areas",
      "D. Mountain regions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The javelin discipline has been part of the Summer Olympics since what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1908",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1908",
      "B. 1896",
      "C. 1961",
      "D. 1940"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bocce, a sport that developed into its present form in Italy, is classified as what type of sports activity?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Target sport",
    "choices": [
      "A. Strength sport",
      "B. Winter sport",
      "C. Combat sport",
      "D. Target sport"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Floorball, a type of team sport popular in Sweden, Finland and Switzerland, is similar to which of these popular sports?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ice hockey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Badminton",
      "B. Polo",
      "C. Football",
      "D. Ice hockey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In squash, small coloured dots on the ball indicate the level of bounciness, hence the skills needed to handle the ball. According to the Professional Squash Association standards, what does the red colour indicate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Medium ball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Slow ball",
      "B. Medium ball",
      "C. Fast ball",
      "D. Extra slow ball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to volleyball official rules, touching the net during play is not considered a fault in which case?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Touching the net with hair",
    "choices": [
      "A. Touching the net with hair",
      "B. Touching the net with foot",
      "C. Touching the net with a part of ones clothing",
      "D. None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Boules is a collective name for a number of games played with what type of balls?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Metal balls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rubber balls",
      "B. Wooden balls",
      "C. Metal balls",
      "D. Dotted balls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was Tony Perez elected to the Reds Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1998",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1983",
      "B. 1981",
      "C. 1998",
      "D. 1994"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who managed the Reds to the World Series victory in 1975?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sparky Anderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Danny Murtaugh",
      "B. Jack McKeon",
      "C. Sparky Anderson",
      "D. Bill Plummer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was Tom Seaver elected to the Reds Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2006",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1998",
      "B. 2006",
      "C. 2004",
      "D. 1999"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many total wins did Jack Billingham have as a Reds pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "75",
    "choices": [
      "A. 88",
      "B. 110",
      "C. 75",
      "D. 97"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was Ewell Blackwell elected to the Reds Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1960",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1961",
      "B. 1963",
      "C. 1960",
      "D. 1962"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times was Johnny Vander Meer selected to the National League All-star team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player won the National League Most Valuable Player Award in 1975 and 1976  while playing with the Reds.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Morgan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Morgan",
      "B. BIlly Williams",
      "C. Pete Rose",
      "D. Tony Perez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball player and manager, nicknamed The Ol Professor, said, Sports do not  build character. They reveal it.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Casey Stengel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Shalk",
      "B. Bill Veeck",
      "C. Casey Stengel",
      "D. Bud Selig"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What coach does this quote belong to: If the NBA were on Channel 5 and a bunch of frogs were making love on Channel 4, I would watch the frogs  even if the picture was coming in fuzzy.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Knight",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Knight",
      "B. Dick Vitale",
      "C. Chet Forte",
      "D. Bill  Walton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NFL safety made this witty remark: Most football teams are tempermental. Thats 90% temper and 10 % mental.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Doug Plank",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Jaworski",
      "B. Phil Simms",
      "C. Doug Plank",
      "D. Shannon Sharpe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What sportswriter specializing in golf remarked: The bell that tolls for all in boxing is the cash register.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Verdi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Susan Waldman",
      "B. Don King",
      "C. Bob Verdi",
      "D. Bob Arum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This running back and an outfielder said, Football is easy if a person is crazy as hell.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bo Jackson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carl Hubbard",
      "B. Deion Sanders",
      "C. Bo Jackson",
      "D. O.J. Simpson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said: You win some, you lose some, you crash some.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dale Earnhardt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Earnhardt",
      "B. Mike Ditka",
      "C. Evander Hollyfield",
      "D. Jim Loscutoff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The New York football Giants defeated the Denver Broncos in Super Bowl XXI in a convincing fashion. What was the final score?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "39-20",
    "choices": [
      "A. 44-27",
      "B. 39-20",
      "C. 17-0",
      "D. 24-10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1986-87 NFC Championship game was at Giants Stadium in a cold, blustery evening with a mean, swirling wind. The Giants won 17-0 over which division rival?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington Redskins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington Redskins",
      "B. Buffalo Bills",
      "C. Philadelphia Eagles",
      "D. Dallas Cowboys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Giants running back in Super Bowl XXI?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Morris",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tiki Barber",
      "B. Joe Morris",
      "C. Otis Anderson",
      "D. Rodney Hampton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1985, the Giants were so close to the Super Bowl they could taste it. But one forbidding defensive team with a monster coach stopped them dead in their tracks and went on to win the big game themselves. Name that team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. Green Bay Packers",
      "B. Dallas Cowboys",
      "C. Chicago Bears",
      "D. Washington Redskins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the MVP of Super Bowl XXI?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phil Simms",
    "choices": [
      "A. Otis Anderson",
      "B. Mark Bavaro",
      "C. Phil Simms",
      "D. Joe Morris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the official classification, which country won the medal count at the Olympic Games held in Beijing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "China",
    "choices": [
      "A. Russia",
      "B. Germany",
      "C. China",
      "D. USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of the American mens basketball team at the Olympic Games held in Beijing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Redeem Team",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ming Team",
      "B. Dream Team V",
      "C. Dream Team",
      "D. Redeem Team"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Several countries had only one representative at the 2008 Olympic Games. Which is not one of them?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Timor-Leste",
    "choices": [
      "A. Timor-Leste",
      "B. Grenada",
      "C. Haiti",
      "D. Nauru"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What role did Brad Pitt play at the 2008 Summer Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He fought in the boxing tournament and was eliminated in the first round",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was an umpire in the baseball tournament",
      "B. He presented the last gold medal to Michael Phelps",
      "C. He fought in the boxing tournament and was eliminated in the first round",
      "D. He organized a pro-Tibet march in Hong-Kong"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the first gold medal of the 2008 Olympics in Beijing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Katerina Emmons (Czech Republic, shooting)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Katerina Emmons (Czech Republic, shooting)",
      "B. Samuel Sanchez (Spain, cycling)",
      "C. Michael Phelps (USA, swimming)",
      "D. Xexia Chen (China, weightlifting)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 2008 Olympics, the 12-years old record of Michael Johnson in 200m run was broken. What was the new time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "19.30s",
    "choices": [
      "A. 19.30s",
      "B. 9.69s",
      "C. 15.60s",
      "D. 19.80s"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On the first day of the 2008 Olympic Games, three American women took all medals in which event?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fencing - sabre",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fencing - sabre",
      "B. Shooting - 10m air rifle",
      "C. Swimming - 400m freestyle",
      "D. Cycling - road race"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Athletics is called the queen of all sports. Who won the first gold in athletics during the 2008 Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tomasz Majewski (Poland, shot put)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tirunesh Dibaba (Ethiopia, 10km)",
      "B. Nicoleta Grasu (Romania, discus)",
      "C. Hyleas Fountain (USA, heptathlon)",
      "D. Tomasz Majewski (Poland, shot put)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many countries were represented by athletes of Chinese origin at the 2008 Olympic Games table tennis competitions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "21",
    "choices": [
      "A. 13",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 21"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "India is the second most populous country in the world, but their first individual Olympic gold came only at the 2008 Games. Which was the historical discipline?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shooting",
    "choices": [
      "A. Table tennis",
      "B. Badminton",
      "C. Shooting",
      "D. Judo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mens Gymnastics at Beijing Olympic Games was dominated by Chinese athletes. Who was the only gold medalist from a different country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leszek Blanik (Poland, vault)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shawn Johnson (USA, Beam)",
      "B. Leszek Blanik (Poland, vault)",
      "C. Gervasio Deferr (Spain, floor)",
      "D. USA (team all-around)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the mens tennis competition at the Olympic Games in 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rafael Nadal (Spain)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Novak Djokovic (Serbia)",
      "B. Roger Federer (Switzerland)",
      "C. James Blake (USA)",
      "D. Rafael Nadal (Spain)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which National Olympic Committee organized Equestrian events during the 2008 Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NOC of Hong-Kong",
    "choices": [
      "A. NOC of Singapur",
      "B. NOC of Hong-Kong",
      "C. NOC of China",
      "D. NOC of Taiwan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which volleyball finals did USA participate, in the 2008 Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Both",
    "choices": [
      "A. Womens",
      "B. Mens",
      "C. None",
      "D. Both"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who returned at Survivor Series 2007 after a 4-month absence?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edge",
    "choices": [
      "A. Big Show",
      "B. Edge",
      "C. John Cena",
      "D. Triple H"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is The Undertakers streak at WrestleMania (prior to WrestleMania 24)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "15-0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 15-0",
      "B. 16-1",
      "C. 16-0",
      "D. 15-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At WM 23, what was the stipulation of the Battle of the Billionaires?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Loser gets head shaved bald",
    "choices": [
      "A. Loser gets humiliated big time, anywhere",
      "B. Loser gets limo blown up",
      "C. Loser gos homeless for 2 weeks",
      "D. Loser gets head shaved bald"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the 2008 Royal Rumble?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Cena",
    "choices": [
      "A. Batista",
      "B. John Cena",
      "C. HHH",
      "D. Shawn Michaels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 2006 Unforgiven PPV, there was a Womens Championship Match between Lita and Trish Stratus. What was the stipulation?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "There was no stipulation",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bra and Panty",
      "B. Winner takes the Title",
      "C. Loser barks like a dog",
      "D. There was no stipulation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At New Years Revolution 2007, the WWE Womens Champion was Mickie James. Who did she face?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Victoria",
    "choices": [
      "A. Victoria",
      "B. Ashley",
      "C. Candice Michelle",
      "D. Trish Stratus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what PPV was the first ever Punjabi Prison Match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "No Mercy",
    "choices": [
      "A. New Years Revolution",
      "B. No Mercy",
      "C. SummerSlam",
      "D. Unforgiven"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 2006 Cyber Sunday, the fans decided to see Mickie James vs. Lita in what kind of match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Diva LumberJack",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bra  Panty",
      "B. Diva LumberJack",
      "C. No DQ",
      "D. Pillow Fight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Vengeance 2007 was called Night of .............?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Champions",
    "choices": [
      "A. Divas",
      "B. History",
      "C. Champions",
      "D. Losers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most distinctive feature of Cyber Sunday?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fans take over",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fans take over",
      "B. Retired wrestlers come back",
      "C. It is all about the Gold",
      "D. It is all about McMahon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these movies features Atlanta Motor Speedway?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Smokey and the Bandit II",
    "choices": [
      "A. Three",
      "B. The Ride of Their Lives",
      "C. Dale",
      "D. Smokey and the Bandit II"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are peanuts believed to be bad for auto racing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They are considered bad luck.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They are considered bad luck.",
      "B. They distract drivers while in the car.",
      "C. Fans throw them at cars.",
      "D. They get thrown on the track"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NASCAR driver won 3 races in 2003?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ryan Newman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Jr.",
      "B. Mark Martin",
      "C. Ryan Newman",
      "D. Jeff Gordon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does NASCAR stand for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing",
    "choices": [
      "A. National Association for Street Car Auto Racing",
      "B. National Alliance for Sports Car Auto Racing",
      "C. National Association for Stock Car Auto Racing",
      "D. Non Athletic Sport Centered Around Rednecks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do NASCAR cars turn left?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "For safety reasons",
    "choices": [
      "A. It brings good luck.",
      "B. people think its better going left than right",
      "C. Richard Petty wanted it that way.",
      "D. For safety reasons"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did NASCAR start?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Daytona Beach",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bristol Beach",
      "B. Daytona Beach",
      "C. Indiana Beach",
      "D. Talladega Beach"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these NFL quarterbacks retired in 2009 as the record holder for most passing yards gained in a career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brett Farve",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fran Tarkenton",
      "B. Sammy Baugh",
      "C. Dan Marino",
      "D. Brett Farve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who set an NFL record for most passing yards gained in a game in 1951?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Norm Van Brocklin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Montana",
      "B. Norm Van Brocklin",
      "C. Kenny Stabler",
      "D. Peyton Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who set an NFL record for the most pass attempts in a season in 1994?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Drew Bledsoe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Doug Williams",
      "B. John Elway",
      "C. Bernie Kosar",
      "D. Drew Bledsoe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who set an NFL record for most consecutive seasons (1959-1961) leading the league in pass attempts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Unitas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Drew Bledsoe",
      "B. George Blanda",
      "C. Johnny Unitas",
      "D. Warren Moon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who set an NFL record for most consecutive seasons (1963-1965) leading the league in completions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Blanda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rick Mirer",
      "B. John Elway",
      "C. Len Dawson",
      "D. George Blanda"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1990 and 1991, this quarterback set an NFL record for most consecutive passes attempts, with no interception.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bernie Kosar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bart Starr",
      "B. John Elway",
      "C. Bernie Kosar",
      "D. Vinny Testaverde"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these set an NFL record for the most consecutive games with a touchdown pass (1956-1960)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Unitas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Y A Tittle",
      "B. Johnny Unitas",
      "C. Dan Morino",
      "D. Steve DeBerg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first major leaguer to play at least 500 games at 5 different  positions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Rose",
      "B. Gil McDougal",
      "C. Bert Campaneris",
      "D. Nomar Garciaparra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Dodger starting infield for the 1965 season set this record.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was the first time a complete infield was composed of switch hitters.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was the first time all four infielders stole at least 20 bases each.",
      "B. It was the first time an infield was made up of four players none of whom were born in the USA.",
      "C. It was the first infield composed of players all of whom became Hall of Famers.",
      "D. It was the first time a complete infield was composed of switch hitters."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Cincinnati Red Stockings were the first professional baseball team. They played in the first professional game in 1869. Who did they beat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Antioch College",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kentucky College",
      "B. The Canton Bull Dogs",
      "C. Antioch College",
      "D. The Toledo Mud Hens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first player to steal a base in a World Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Honus Wagner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Bagby",
      "B. Honus Wagner",
      "C. Ty Cobb",
      "D. Jim Sebring"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first player to hit a home run in a World Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Sebring",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Bagby",
      "B. Jim Sebring",
      "C. Honus Wagner",
      "D. Home Run Baker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first pitcher to hit a home run in a World Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Bagby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cy Young",
      "B. Walter Johnson",
      "C. Jim Bagby",
      "D. Jim Sebring"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name for the first Most Valuable Player Award in Major League baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chalmers Award",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chalmers Award",
      "B. The Most Valuable Player Award",
      "C. The MVP",
      "D. The Chadwick Award"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Major League baseball player to win the MVP Award two years in a row?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmie Foxx",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmie Foxx",
      "B. Barry Bonds",
      "C. Bobby Bonds",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first baseball player to hit more than 40 home runs in a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Home Run Baker",
      "B. Lou Gehrig",
      "C. Nap Lajoie",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Major Leaguer to get more than 160 walks in a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mark McGwire",
      "B. Ted Williams",
      "C. Barry Bonds",
      "D. Hank Aaron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first Major League baseball franchise to lose more than 9,000 games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Philadelphia Phillies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago Cubs",
      "B. Philadelphia Phillies",
      "C. Cincinnati Reds",
      "D. Brooklyn/Los Angeles Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Babe Ruth hit 60 home runs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1927",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1919",
      "B. 1927",
      "C. 1921",
      "D. 1923"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Three Alou brothers played for the Giants. What were their first names?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Felipe, Matty, Jesus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hullub, Bob, Goto",
      "B. Felipe, Matty, Jesus",
      "C. Matty, Moises, Edgardo",
      "D. Felipe, Moises, Ozzie"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "World Heavyweight Champion Mike Tyson said that he wore black trunks to symbolize the death of this person.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "His trainer, Cus DAmato",
    "choices": [
      "A. His trainer, Angelo Dundee",
      "B. His trainer, Cus DAmato",
      "C. His step mother",
      "D. His father"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In a 1942 fight, Tommy Cross entered the ring and then had to suddenly leave. Why?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was not wearing his trunks.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He came out for the wrong fight.",
      "B. The ring was out in the open and it began to rain terribly.",
      "C. He was not wearing his trunks.",
      "D. He was in the wrong boxing ring."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which boxer became the youngest world champion in 1976?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wilfredo Benitez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sugar Ray Leonard",
      "B. Roberto Duran",
      "C. Wilfredo Benitez",
      "D. Carlos Palomino"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the Iliad, Homer tells of a wrestling match between Odysseus and whom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Telamonian Ajax",
    "choices": [
      "A. Achilles",
      "B. Paris",
      "C. Telamonian Ajax",
      "D. Priam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became the first wrestler to win a gold medal in three different Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Aleksandr Medved",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aleksandr Medved",
      "B. Dan Gable",
      "C. Dan Saunderson",
      "D. Chris Taylor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great Ultimate Fighting champion played Gaft in the pilot episode of Blade: The Series.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Lidell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Matt Hughes",
      "B. Rich Franklin",
      "C. Chuck Lidell",
      "D. Tito Sanchez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In April 1987, this boxer went on a hunger strike for over a month to protest against the conditions for a certain category of boxers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lady Tyger Trimiar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lady Tyger Trimiar",
      "B. Hector  de la Concha",
      "C. Harvey Katowicz",
      "D. Ray Boom Boom Mancini"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After many unsuccessful tries, this man in black, also known as The Intimidator, finally won The Daytona 500 in 1998 which was also the track we lost him at.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dale Earnhardt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Denny Hamlin",
      "B. Cale Yarborough",
      "C. Dale Earnhardt",
      "D. Dale Earnhardt Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of Ryan Newman, the winner of the 50th annual Daytona 500, who also has a degree in vehicle structure engineering from Purdue University?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rocket Man",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rocket Man",
      "B. Rayne Man",
      "C. June Bug",
      "D. Flyin Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of H.A. Wheeler, the former track promoter at Lowes?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Humpy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Humpy",
      "B. Hurricane",
      "C. Silverfox",
      "D. Happy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Long before Kevin Harvick won both million dollar events in one season, he was know as what?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Happy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Money",
      "B. Hardwin",
      "C. Happy",
      "D. Trucker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This is a throwback nickname to Denny Hamlin, the driver of the #11 FedEx Toyota.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hurricane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Young Buck",
      "B. Cyclone",
      "C. Hurricane",
      "D. Dynamite"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times did Tiger Woods win the PGA Championship prior to 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This legendary golfer won the PGA Championship a record-tying 5 times and is third in total major wins behind Jack Nicklaus and Tiger Woods.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walter Hagen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Arnold Palmer",
      "B. Gene Sarazen",
      "C. Ben Hogan",
      "D. Walter Hagen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The golfer who wins the PGA Championship is presented with what trophy?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Wanamaker Trophy",
    "choices": [
      "A. A Wilkinson Sword",
      "B. The Wanamaker Trophy",
      "C. The Claret Jug",
      "D. A Green Jacket"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first PGA championship was held at Siwonay in New York in 1916 and won by this golfer. The 2006 Championship was conducted at Medinah, and won by this golfer.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Barnes/Tiger Woods",
    "choices": [
      "A. Francis Ouimet/Tiger Woods",
      "B. Jim Barnes/Phil Mickelson",
      "C. Jim Barnes/Tiger Woods",
      "D. Francis Ouimet/Phil Mickelson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This golf course, the venue for the 2007 PGA Championship, was established in 1936.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Southern Hills, Tulsa Oklahoma",
    "choices": [
      "A. Southern Hills, Tulsa Oklahoma",
      "B. Sahalee, Redmond Washington",
      "C. Inverness, Toledo Ohio",
      "D. Crooked Stick, Carmel Indiana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ray Floyd won the PGA Championship two times, the second time at Southern Hills in Tulsa. When and where did this steely-eyed short game master win his first PGA Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NCR Country Club, 1969",
    "choices": [
      "A. Southern Hills Country Club, 1970",
      "B. Pebble Beach, 1977",
      "C. Canterbury Golf Club, 1973",
      "D. NCR Country Club, 1969"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great golfer never won the PGA Championship, though he came close a couple of times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greg Norman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lanny Wadkins",
      "B. Greg Norman",
      "C. Dave Marr",
      "D. Nick Price"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player received the Golden Ball award at the 2006 FIFA World Cup finals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zinadine Zidane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gianluigi Buffon",
      "B. Wayne Rooney",
      "C. Zinadine Zidane",
      "D. Fabio Cannavarro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player top scored at the 2006 FIFA World Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miroslav Klose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luca Toni",
      "B. Michael Owen",
      "C. Zinadine Zidane",
      "D. Miroslav Klose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nation didnt concede a goal in the entire 2006 FIFA World tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Switzerland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Italy",
      "B. France",
      "C. Germany",
      "D. Switzerland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nation defeated Brazil, the defending champions, in the quarter finals of the 2006 FIFA World Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "France",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. Italy",
      "C. Germany",
      "D. Portugal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player was sent off in the 2006 FIFA World Cup quarter final match between England and Portugal?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wayne Rooney",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Beckham",
      "B. Owen Hargreves",
      "C. Wayne Rooney",
      "D. Michael Owen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player broke the dead lock with only 2 minutes left of extra time in the Germany v Italy 2006 World Cup semi final?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fabio Grosso",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luca Toni",
      "B. Alberto Gilardino",
      "C. Fabio Grosso",
      "D. Alessandro Delpiero"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At which stadium was the 2006 FIFA World Cup final held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Olympiastadium (Berlin)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aol Arena (Hamburg)",
      "B. Allianz Stadium (Munich)",
      "C. Signal Iduna Park (Dortmund)",
      "D. Olympiastadium (Berlin)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "We all know that at the 2006 FIFA World Cup, Italy defeated France in a penalty shoot out, but which Italian player had the honour of holding the World Cup aloft as the winning captain?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fabio Cannavaro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Francesco Totti",
      "B. Fabio Cannavaro",
      "C. Andrea Pirlo",
      "D. Gianluigi Buffon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This basketball player helped the Knicks win the NBA championship during the 1969-1970 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willis Reed",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Jackson",
      "B. Willis Reed",
      "C. Fred Lynn",
      "D. Otis Taylor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NBA player was the 5th player chosen in the 2003 NBA Draft.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dwayne Wade",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carmelo Anthony",
      "B. Randolph Scott",
      "C. Lebron James",
      "D. Dwayne Wade"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This football player was a running back for the New England Patriots in the 1980s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Craig James",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerome James",
      "B. Greg Brock",
      "C. Craig James",
      "D. Thomas James"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This major league baseball player is among the greatest players to ever don a Kansas City Royals uniform.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Brett",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Brett",
      "B. Chris James",
      "C. George Brett",
      "D. Fred Lynn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This major league baseball player was easily the best pitcher in the National League in 1986.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Scott",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Clark",
      "B. Mike Scott",
      "C. J.R. Richard",
      "D. Matt Clark"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Tony Hawks son, who was born in 1992?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Riley Hawk",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Hawk Jr.",
      "B. Chad Hawk",
      "C. Riley Hawk",
      "D. Frank Hawk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tony Hawk is considered the pioneer of what style of skating?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vertical skating",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vertical skating",
      "B. Grind skating",
      "C. Air skating",
      "D. Street skating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Tony Hawks father?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Hawk",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Hawk",
      "B. Steve Hawk",
      "C. Spencer Hawk",
      "D. Riley Hawk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1992, Tony Hawk started what skateboard company together with Per Welinder?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Birdhouse Projects",
    "choices": [
      "A. Flip",
      "B. Blind",
      "C. Alien Workshop",
      "D. Birdhouse Projects"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Danny Biasone is often credited with financially saving this professional sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Basketball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Football",
      "B. Soccer",
      "C. Basketball",
      "D. Hockey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first African-American to play in the NBA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Earl Lloyd",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nate Sweetwater Clifton",
      "B. Earl Lloyd",
      "C. Chuck Cooper",
      "D. Chuck Connors"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Today in Major League Baseball a ground rule double is when a ball is hit fair, bounces and then goes over the outfield. Which statement is  true about this rule?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It wasnt a rule until 1930.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It became a rule when the baseball rules were canonized in 1886.",
      "B. It was always a rule in the National League but became an American League rule in 1927.",
      "C. It wasnt a rule until 1930.",
      "D. It was made a rule in both leagues in 1919."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the second Major League Baseball switch-hitter to hit 500 home runs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eddie Murray",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harmon Killebrew",
      "B. Eddie Mathews",
      "C. Mickey Mantle",
      "D. Eddie Murray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NFL player to get 200 sacks?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bruce Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bruce Smith",
      "B. Kevin Greene",
      "C. Michael Strahan",
      "D. Reggie White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NFL great was the first player to get 14 interceptions in one season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dick Lane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Herb Adderly",
      "B. Jimmy Marsalis",
      "C. Dick Lane",
      "D. Cornell Green"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Scoring a safety is a rare occurrence in an NFL game. This defensive end, who played for the Rams, was the first NFLer to score two safeties in one game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fred Dryer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Youngblood",
      "B. Fred Dryer",
      "C. Ted Hendricks",
      "D. Doug English"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Whether fortunately or unfortunately, strikes and work stoppages are a fact of life in professional sports. When was the first NHL player strike?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1925",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1925",
      "B. 1995",
      "C. 1985",
      "D. 1955"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Greg Harris and Tony Mullane were both pitchers in Major League Baseball. Why are they significant?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Each one pitched both lefty and righty.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were actually the same person.",
      "B. Babe Ruth hit his first homer off Mullane and Barry Bonds hit his first homer off Harris.",
      "C. Each one pitched both lefty and righty.",
      "D. They pitched in the first extra-innings World Series game."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which basketball league was the first to institute a three-point shot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NCAA",
    "choices": [
      "A. NCAA",
      "B. ABA",
      "C. ABL",
      "D. NBA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Major Leaguer to hit 500 homeruns in his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmie Foxx",
      "B. Lou Gehrig",
      "C. Tris Speaker",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Major Leaguer to win the All-Star Game MVP Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maury Wills",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mickey Mantle",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Jimmie Foxx",
      "D. Maury Wills"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Major Leaguer was the college roommate of the great wide receiver Lynn Swann.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fred Lynn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Randy Flores",
      "B. Fred Lynn",
      "C. Tom Seaver",
      "D. Aaron Boone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Major Leaguer to hit a grand slam home run in a Major League All-Star game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fred Lynn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Piersall",
      "B. Roberto Clemente",
      "C. Fred Lynn",
      "D. Jackie Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first baseball box score written?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1853",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1853",
      "B. 1940",
      "C. 1951",
      "D. 1923"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What baseball player had the first unassisted triple play in a World Series game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Wambsganss",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Wambsganss",
      "B. Lou Skisas",
      "C. Gus Zernial",
      "D. Harry Chiti"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1918 regular baseball season was shortened because of  World War I. What happened in the 1918 World Series, played in September?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Star Spangled Banner was sung for the first time at a sporting event.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Chicago Cubs were accused of  throwing the game to the Boston Red Sox.",
      "B. The Star Spangled Banner was sung for the first time at a sporting event.",
      "C. The Chicago White Sox were accused of throwing the series.",
      "D. It was the first World Series that was a best 4 out of 7 series of games."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year were numbers first put on baseball uniforms?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1929",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1921",
      "B. 1935",
      "C. 1923",
      "D. 1929"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first team to put players names on their uniforms?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "White Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dodgers",
      "B. Indians",
      "C. Yankees",
      "D. White Sox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1998 this pitcher wore a baseball cap that Babe Ruth had worn in 1920.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Wells",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Keys",
      "B. David Wells",
      "C. Dan Wetteland",
      "D. Roger Clemens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1945 catcher Harry ONeill was killed on Iwo Jima. In 1979 catcher Thurmond Munson died in a plane crash. How did catcher Bo Diaz die in 1990?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Crushed by a cable TV dish",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fishing boat accident",
      "B. Drowned in his bath tub",
      "C. Hunting accident",
      "D. Crushed by a cable TV dish"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There is some debate as to which city was the first to serve hot dogs at baseball games, but it seems  that one of these two cities was the first.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "St. Louis or New York",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis or Chicago",
      "B. Chicago or Cincinnati",
      "C. Cincinnati or New York",
      "D. St. Louis or New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many parts are in a basketball game during the Olympic tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In soccer, what happens to a goalkeeper who goes outside of his penalty box?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He is allowed to, but he cannot touch the ball with his hands.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He is allowed only if his team is defending.",
      "B. He is allowed to, but he cannot touch the ball with his hands.",
      "C. He gets a red card.",
      "D. His team is penalized by a free kick."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What object is tossed into the air in the Olympic event Hammer Throw?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "An iron ball attached to a wire",
    "choices": [
      "A. A screw driver",
      "B. An iron ball attached to a wire",
      "C. A hammer",
      "D. A chain saw"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In butterfly swimming, how must the athlete finish the race to have a valid result?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "By touching the pools ending wall with both hands simultaneously",
    "choices": [
      "A. By touching the pools ending wall with both hands simultaneously",
      "B. By stepping out of the pool",
      "C. By touching the pools ending wall with his/her feet",
      "D. By touching the pools ending wall with with one hand only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In high jump, how must the bar be attacked for a valid result?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It doesnt matter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Feet first",
      "B. It doesnt matter",
      "C. Butt first",
      "D. Head first"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times must athletes circle the stadium in the Olympic 10km run?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "25",
    "choices": [
      "A. 20",
      "B. 50",
      "C. 25",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is a libero in a volleyball team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A player who cannot attack nor block",
    "choices": [
      "A. Its the 7th player, allowed to join only if his team trails by more than 8 points",
      "B. A player that always stands by the net",
      "C. A player who cannot attack nor block",
      "D. The play-maker, who passes balls to attacking players"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many sets are played in male table tennis at the Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Up to 7",
    "choices": [
      "A. Up to 3",
      "B. Up to 7",
      "C. Up to 5",
      "D. Always 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between the Olympic and the World Cup soccer tournaments?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "In the Olympic tournament only players under 23 years old are allowed.",
    "choices": [
      "A. In the Olympic tournament only players under 23 years old are allowed.",
      "B. Red cards are not used during the Olympic games.",
      "C. The ball used at the Olympic Games is oval, more like the one used in American Football.",
      "D. In the Olympic tournament there are no penalty shoot-outs when a play-off match ends in a tie."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which score is impossible in a tennis tie-break set?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8-5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 99-97",
      "B. 8-5",
      "C. 8-6",
      "D. 7-5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long is a handball Olympic game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "60min, breaks excluded",
    "choices": [
      "A. 48min wall clock",
      "B. 48min, breaks excluded",
      "C. 60min, breaks excluded",
      "D. 60min wall clock"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does a red flag signal during athletic events that involve a jump?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The result is not valid because the athlete bounced off pass the measure bar.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The result is not valid because there was too strong back wind.",
      "B. The result is valid.",
      "C. The athlete is disqualified.",
      "D. The result is not valid because the athlete bounced off pass the measure bar."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is part of the result calculation in ski-jumping?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Distance and style",
    "choices": [
      "A. Style only",
      "B. Distance only",
      "C. Distance, but if the jumpers jumped the same distance, style is taken into account",
      "D. Distance and style"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long is the Olympic cycling race?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is not set",
    "choices": [
      "A. 200km",
      "B. It is not set",
      "C. 189.5km",
      "D. 200miles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To win the Triple Crown a batter must lead his league in these categories.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Home runs, rbis, batting average",
    "choices": [
      "A. Home runs, rbis, batting average",
      "B. Home runs, batting average, slugging percentage",
      "C. Home runs, hits, rbis",
      "D. Home runs, slugging percentage, rbis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul Hines was the first Triple Crown winner in the Majors. When did he win the award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1878",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1887",
      "B. 1922",
      "C. 1878",
      "D. 1894"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nap Lajoie was the first American League hitter to win the Triple Crown. For which team did he win it?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Philadelphia Athletics",
    "choices": [
      "A. The St. Louis Browns",
      "B. The Kansas City Athletics",
      "C. The Philadelphia Athletics",
      "D. The Oakland Athletics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the last triple crown winner of the 20th century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carl Yastremski",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Robinson",
      "B. Carl Yastremski",
      "C. Ted Williams",
      "D. Mickey Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The last National Leaguer to win the Triple Crown in the 20th century had the nickname Ducky. What was his last name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Medwick",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duffy",
      "B. Medwick",
      "C. Klein",
      "D. Hornsby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These were the first two men to win the Triple Crown twice each.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rogers Hornsby and Ted Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rogers Hornsby and Ted Williams",
      "B. Ted Williams and Frank Robinson",
      "C. Frank Robinson and Mickey Mantle",
      "D. Rogers Hornsby and Ducky Duffy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These  were the first two first basemen to win the Triple Crown.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmy Foxx and Lou Gehrig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Gehrig and Ty Cobb",
      "B. Lou Gehrig and Carl Yastremski",
      "C. Jimmy Foxx and Lou Gehrig",
      "D. Jimmy Foxx and  Ty Cobb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Triple Crown winner was an outfielder for the Cincinnati Reds until he was traded to the Orioles for Milt Pappas.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Robinson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vada Pinson",
      "B. Frank Robinson",
      "C. Wally Post",
      "D. Ducky Duffy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first player to win the Major League Triple Crown. He led both leagues in all three categories.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ty Cobb",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ty Cobb",
      "B. Rogers Hornsby",
      "C. Lou Gehrig",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Title of Triple Crown Loser goes to the player who would normally qualify for the Triple Crown, but is last in all three triple crown categories among all starters in his league. Who was the last Triple Crown Loser in the 20th century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ivan DeJesus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Woodie Williams",
      "B. Ivan DeJesus",
      "C. Mark Belanger",
      "D. Enzo Hernandez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the St. Louis Cardinal pitcher Chris Carpenter born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Exeter, New Hampshire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Exeter, New Hampshire",
      "B. Chicago, Illinois",
      "C. Saint Louis, Missouri",
      "D. Omaha, Nebraska"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Thats a winner! is a quote by what famous announcer of the St. Louis Cardinals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jack Buck",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Buck",
      "B. Joe Morgan",
      "C. Joe Buck",
      "D. Sammy Sosa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position did Mark McGwire play for the St. Louis Cardinals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1st base",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2nd base",
      "B. 3rd base",
      "C. shortstop",
      "D. 1st base"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The St. Louis Cardinals play at what stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Busch Stadium",
    "choices": [
      "A. Busch Stadium",
      "B. Wrigley Field",
      "C. Tropicana Field",
      "D. Coors Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the birthplace of St. Louis Cardinals outfielder, So Taguchi?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hyogo Prefecture",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hyogo Prefecture",
      "B. Santa Fe",
      "C. Los Angles",
      "D. Carson City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which first baseman was drafted by the St. Louis Cardinals in 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Albert Pujols",
    "choices": [
      "A. So Taguchi",
      "B. Albert Pujols",
      "C. Jim Edmonds",
      "D. Scott Rollen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former Utah Jazz player set an NBA record for assists in a career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Stockton",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Stockton",
      "B. Magic Johnson",
      "C. Moe Cheeks",
      "D. Mark Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1962, this former Philadelphia 76er set the record for most points scored in a game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "B. Bill Russel",
      "C. Michael Jordon",
      "D. Hakeem Olajuwon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former LA Laker retired in 1989 as the record holder for most points scored in a career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "B. Magic Johnson",
      "C. Bill Russel",
      "D. Moses Malone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1973, this person who played for four different NBA teams set a record for blocked shots in one game, with 17.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elmore Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Elmore Smith",
      "B. Bill Russel",
      "C. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "D. Moses Malone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This underrated player recorded the very first quadruple-double in NBA history.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nate Thurmond",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Stockton",
      "B. Nate Thurmond",
      "C. Jason Kidd",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This durable player retired in 1997 as the record holder for most games played in a career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Robert Parish",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Stockton",
      "B. Robert Parish",
      "C. Karl Malone",
      "D. Magic Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Indiana Pacer retired in 2005 as the record holder for most career three-pointers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Reggie Miller",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Ellis",
      "B. Tim Hardaway",
      "C. Reggie Miller",
      "D. Mark Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Houston Rocket, who retired in 2002, set an NBA record for blocks in a career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hakeem Olajuwon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hakeem Olajuwon",
      "B. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. David Robinson",
      "D. Bill Russel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Utah Jazz player, who retired in 2003, set a record for steals in a career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Stockton",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Stockton",
      "B. Jeff Hornacek",
      "C. Karl Malone",
      "D. Derek Harper."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following NBA marksmen has the best free throw percentage in a career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark Price",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mark Price",
      "B. Michael Jordan",
      "C. Gary Payton",
      "D. John Stockton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On what date did the Toronto Blue Jays play their first regular season game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "April 7, 1977",
    "choices": [
      "A. May 7, 1976",
      "B. April 7, 1977",
      "C. April 7, 1978",
      "D. May 7, 1977"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did the Toronto Blue Jays pick in their first ever expansion draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Bailor",
    "choices": [
      "A. Doug Ault",
      "B. Bob Bailor",
      "C. Ron Fairly",
      "D. Jerry Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1990, the Toronto Blue Jays traded Tony Frenandez and Fred McGriff  to San Diego for whom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Carter and Roberto Alomar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Carter and Roberto Alomar",
      "B. Roberto Alomar and Duane Ward",
      "C. Joe Carter and Sandy Alomar",
      "D. Joe Carter and Duane Ward"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did Dave Stieb hold hitless in 1990 to pitch the first no hitter in Blue Jays history?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleveland Indians",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago White Sox",
      "B. Detroit Tigers",
      "C. Kansas City Royals",
      "D. Cleveland Indians"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was John Oleruds batting average when he won the batting title in 1993?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": ".363",
    "choices": [
      "A. .375",
      "B. .380",
      "C. .363",
      "D. .358"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player hit  336 homers in 1423 games while playing for the Toronto Blue Jays?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carlos Delgado",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dave Winfield",
      "B. Carlos Delgado",
      "C. Joe Carter",
      "D. George Bell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these has not been a Blue Jay player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mitch Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dave Stewart",
      "B. Jack Morris",
      "C. Mitch Williams",
      "D. David Cone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team did the Toronto Blue Jays beat on October 5, 1985 to win their first division crown.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Yankees",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Red Sox",
      "B. The Orioles",
      "C. The Tigers",
      "D. The Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Blue Jay pitcher was nicknamed Terminator?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Henke",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimme Key",
      "B. Duane Ward",
      "C. Dave Stieb",
      "D. Tom Henke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did the Toronto Blue Jays beat on May 9, 1990, for their 1000th regular season win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The White Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. The White Sox",
      "B. The Red Sox",
      "C. The Yankees",
      "D. The Devil Rays"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Golf is âa game in which you shout Fore! shoot six, and write down fiveâ according to which popular ABC radio personality?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Harvey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Harvey",
      "B. Vic Raschi",
      "C. John Dailey",
      "D. H. L. Mencken"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which British novelist and essayist defined sport in this way: âSerious sport has nothing to do with fair play. It is bound up with hatred, jealousy, boastfulness, disregard of all rules and sadistic pleasure in witnessing violence. In other words, it is war without the shooting.â?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Orwell",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Orwell",
      "B. George Custer",
      "C. Omar Bradley",
      "D. Dwight Eisenhower"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before Arkansas State University went to the New Orleans Bowl in 2005, which Sun Belt Conference school represented the Sun Belt Conference in the Bowl the previous four years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of North Texas",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Louisiana at Lafayette",
      "B. New Mexico State University",
      "C. Middle Tennessee State University",
      "D. University of North Texas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What school was the first to represent the Sun Belt Conference with an At-Large bid to a Bowl Game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Troy University",
    "choices": [
      "A. Troy University",
      "B. Arkansas State University",
      "C. University of Louisiana at Lafayette",
      "D. University of North Texas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Sun Belt Conference basketball schools competes in football at the 1-AA level and is therefore not a member of the 1-A Sun Belt for football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Western Kentucky University",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of New Orleans",
      "B. University of Denver",
      "C. University of Arkansas at Little Rock",
      "D. Western Kentucky University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the only non-public university that is a member of the Sun Belt Conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Denver",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of New Orleans",
      "B. University of Denver",
      "C. University of South Alabama",
      "D. Troy University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following teams did not become a member of Western Athletic Conference (WAC) by leaving the Sun Belt?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Nevada",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Idaho",
      "B. New Mexico State University",
      "C. University of Nevada",
      "D. Utah State University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the NCAA Womens National Championship in 1985 as a member of the Sun Belt Conference?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Old Dominion University",
    "choices": [
      "A. Western Kentucky University",
      "B. Louisiana Tech University",
      "C. Old Dominion University",
      "D. University of North Carolina-Charlotte"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following schools was not a charter member of the Sun Belt Conference when the conference was formed in 1976?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Alabama at Birmingham",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Alabama at Birmingham",
      "B. University of South Alabama",
      "C. University of South Florida",
      "D. Jacksonville University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What MLB All-Star and University of South Alabama alumnus was voted the leagues all-time greatest baseball player during the leagues 30th Anniversary celebration in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Luis Gonzalez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Juan Pierre",
      "B. Luis Gonzalez",
      "C. Lance Johnson",
      "D. Jon Lieber"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following Sun Belt Conference Member schools is not paired up correctly with its mascot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arkansas State - Red Wolves",
    "choices": [
      "A. Middle Tennessee State - Blue Raiders",
      "B. Western Kentucky - Hilltoppers",
      "C. New Orleans - Privateers",
      "D. Arkansas State - Red Wolves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which quarterback led the New York Jets to the super bowl in the 1968- 1969 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Namath",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Montana",
      "B. Joe Namath",
      "C. Terry Bredshaw",
      "D. Steve Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1984, the New York Jets began playing their home games in this state.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Jersey",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York",
      "B. New Jersey",
      "C. Pennsylvania",
      "D. Georgia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team do the Jets share their stadium with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Giants",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bills",
      "B. Patriots",
      "C. Giants",
      "D. Dolphins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This football player, known as the Jets all-time leading rusher, announced his retirement in July 2007.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Curtis Martin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Curtis Martin",
      "B. Phillip Jackson",
      "C. Don Maynard",
      "D. Jerry Rice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which round was Leon Washington drafted by the New York Jets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4th",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1st",
      "B. 2nd",
      "C. 4th",
      "D. 3rd"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a player whose number was retired by the New York Jets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Weeb Ewbank",
    "choices": [
      "A. Weeb Ewbank",
      "B. Joe Namath",
      "C. Don Maynard",
      "D. Joe Klecko"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In January 2006, this person became the youngest head coach in the Jets history.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eric Mangini",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eric Mangini",
      "B. Al Groh",
      "C. Herman Edwards",
      "D. Pete Carrol"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This early Auburn coach said Gentlemen, it is better to have died a small boy than to fumble this football.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Heisman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Otis Armstrong",
      "B. Pop Warner",
      "C. John Heisman",
      "D. Willie Stargel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person, who coached at Michigan State from 1954-1972, said Football is not a contact sport - it is a collision sport. Dancing is a contact sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duffy Daugherty",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bo Shembechler",
      "B. Jerry Doak Walker",
      "C. Wayne Hardin",
      "D. Duffy Daugherty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After USC lost 51-0 to Notre Dame, his postgame message to his team was: All those who need showers, take them.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John McKay",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Wooden",
      "B. Pete Carroll",
      "C. John McKay",
      "D. Howard Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Notre Dame coach said, The only qualifications for a lineman are to be big and dumb. To be a back, you only have to be dumb.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Knute Rockne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ty Willingham",
      "B. Lou Holtz",
      "C. Charlie Weis",
      "D. Knute Rockne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Notre Dame coach said, Show me a good and gracious loser, and Ill show you a failure.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Knute Rockne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ara Parsegian",
      "B. Lou Holtz",
      "C. Charlie Weis",
      "D. Knute Rockne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To which Notre Dame legend is the following quote attributed? Ive found that prayers work best when you have big players.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Knute Rockne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Leahy",
      "B. Ara Parseghian",
      "C. Jessie Harper",
      "D. Knute Rockne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The importance of practice was emphasized in the following statement made by this Notre Dame head coach: Lads, youre not to miss practice unless your parents died or you died.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Leahy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Holtz",
      "B. Frank Leahy",
      "C. Ara Parseghian",
      "D. Knute Rockne"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Arkansas Razorback coach said, The man who complains about the way the ball bounces is likely to be the one who dropped it.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Holtz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tommy Nobles",
      "B. Frank Broyles",
      "C. Lou Holtz",
      "D. Houston Nutt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which University of Alabama coach said, I make my practices real hard because if a player is a quitter, I want him to quit in practice, not in a game.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bear Bryant",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gene Stallings",
      "B. Bear Bryant",
      "C. Mike Shula",
      "D. Ray Perkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Bear Bryant quarterback said When you win, nothing hurts.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Namath",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Rome",
      "B. Kenny Stabler",
      "C. Mike Ditka",
      "D. Joe Namath"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did England host and win the World Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1966",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1966",
      "B. 1958",
      "C. 1962",
      "D. 1974"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player scored the famous hand of god  goal at the 1986 World Cup.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Diego Maradonna",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pele",
      "B. Diego Maradonna",
      "C. David Beckham",
      "D. Paolo Rossi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This country scored one of soccer World Cups biggest upsets when it defeated Brazil at the 1950 World Cup in Brazil",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Uruguay",
    "choices": [
      "A. West Germany",
      "B. Chile",
      "C. Argentina",
      "D. Uruguay"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This nation played a style of soccer termed total football and reached consecutive world cups in the 1970s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Holland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Germany",
      "B. Argentina",
      "C. Brazil",
      "D. Holland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the World Cup in 1982, this player was involved in a controversial incident in his countrys semi-final victory.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harald Schumacher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marco Materazzi",
      "B. Paolo Rossi",
      "C. Harald Schumacher",
      "D. Micelle Platini"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This famous football nation won its first World Cup in 1978.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Argentina",
    "choices": [
      "A. the Soviet Union",
      "B. France",
      "C. Argentina",
      "D. Holland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player scored the winning penalty to secure Italys 4th World Cup victory in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fabio Grosso",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fabio Grosso",
      "B. Franseco Totti",
      "C. Luca Toni",
      "D. Gennarro Gattusso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2002, this nation stunned some of soccers big names to reach the semi finals of the World Cup.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Korea",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cameroon",
      "B. Australia",
      "C. South Korea",
      "D. Japan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1954, this nation, widely believed to be the greatest team of all time, were stunned by West Germany in the final.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hungary",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil",
      "B. Sweden",
      "C. Hungary",
      "D. Italy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1983, N.C. State had to win the Atlantic Coast Conference tournament to be included in the National Collegiate Athletic Association field. What three teams did they defeat to win the tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wake Forest, North Carolina, and Virginia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duke, South Carolina, and North Carolina",
      "B. Virginia, Duke, and Maryland",
      "C. Wake Forest, North Carolina, and Virginia",
      "D. Wake Forest, Georgia Tech, and Duke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lorenzo Charles hit the game winning shot in the 1983 NCAA Championship, but what was the name of the player who put up the famous air ball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Derek Whittenburg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ranzino Smith",
      "B. Cozell McQueen",
      "C. Terry Gannon",
      "D. Derek Whittenburg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1986, the North Carolina State University Football team defeated the highly ranked South Carolina team on a miracle Hail Mary pass. Which receiver caught that pass?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Danny Peebles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Danny Peebles",
      "B. Nasrallah Worthen",
      "C. Haywood Jeffries",
      "D. Torry Holt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "North Carolina State won the 1974 National Collegiate Athletic Association basketball championship, defeating which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marquette",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marquette",
      "B. UCLA",
      "C. Maryland",
      "D. Georgia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former North Carolina State coach was buried in a cemetery overlooking the highway so he could see his boys off to play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Everett Case",
    "choices": [
      "A. Norman Sloan",
      "B. Press Maravich",
      "C. Everett Case",
      "D. Jim Valvano"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players was not among the starting five in the North Carolina State University 83 basketball championship team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Anthony Grundy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lorenzo Charles",
      "B. Anthony Grundy",
      "C. Cozell McQueen",
      "D. Derek Whitterburg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1987, North Carolina State University defeated what team in the longest basketball game of the year, played in the Atlantic Coast Conference tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wake Forest",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duke",
      "B. Virginia",
      "C. Maryland",
      "D. Wake Forest"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the best definition for a perfect game in Major League baseball.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Any game in which the pitcher or pitchers throw a complete game of nine or more innings without  surrendering a base runner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Any baseball game in which the losing side never gets a runner safely on base",
      "B. Any baseball game of at least 9 innings in which the losing  side gets no hits, gets no walks, and never reaches base safely on an error",
      "C. Any game in which the pitcher or pitchers throw a complete game of nine or more innings without  surrendering a base runner",
      "D. Any baseball game in which the pitcher allows no hits, no walks, no hit batsmen and in which the winning team commits no errors"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "From 1880 to 1903 only two perfect games were thrown. Who were the two winning pitchers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Lee Richmond and John Montgomery Ward",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson and Harry Suitcase Simpson",
      "B. Ike Delock and Ed Runge",
      "C. John Lee Richmond and John Montgomery Ward",
      "D. Ed Cicotte  and Augie Donatelli"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This  great pitcher threw the first perfect game of the 20th century.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cy Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson",
      "B. Ike Delock",
      "C. Ed Cicotte",
      "D. Cy Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not the name of a pitcher who threw a perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walter Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Addie Joss",
      "B. Cy Young",
      "C. Charlie Robertson",
      "D. Walter Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Big Don No-Hit Larson pitched a perfect game for the Yankees. What was extra special about his perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was played in the World Series.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was played in the American League Championship  series.",
      "B. Larson hit two homers to win the game for the Yankees.",
      "C. It lasted over three hours.",
      "D. It was played in the World Series."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A perfect game was pitched for the Philadelphia Phillies on June 21, 1964. What was extra special about this game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The wining pitcher later became a member of the US House of Representatives.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was the first time a lefty pitched a perfect game.",
      "B. The losing team won the World Series that year.",
      "C. Because of rain the game lasted over four  hours.",
      "D. The wining pitcher later became a member of the US House of Representatives."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For which team did Jim Catfish Hunter pitch a perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Oakland As",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Washington Senators",
      "B. The Oakland As",
      "C. The New York Yankees",
      "D. The Minnesota Twins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "May 15, 1981 saw a perfect game involving the Toronto Blue Jays and the Cleveland Indians. Who was the winning pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Len Barker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dave Stieb",
      "B. Jim Clancy",
      "C. John Denny",
      "D. Len Barker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the September 30, 1984 game between the California Angels and the Texas Rangers, Mike Witt threw a perfect game. What was the final score?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Angels 1 Rangers 0",
    "choices": [
      "A. Angels 1 Rangers 0",
      "B. Angels 6, Rangers 0",
      "C. Rangers 1, Angels 0",
      "D. Rangers 6, Angels 0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jim Quick umpired a perfect game on September 16, 1988. Tom Browning was the winning pitcher for the home team. The game was played at Riverfront Stadium. Name the wining team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Reds",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Red Sox",
      "B. The Twins",
      "C. The Reds",
      "D. The Padres"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A thirty-six year old pitcher threw a perfect game for the Montreal Expos on July 28, 1991. Who was the wining pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis  Martinez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ferguson Jenkins",
      "B. Dennis  Martinez",
      "C. Al Leiter",
      "D. Kenny Rogers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On July 28, 1994 a perfect game was pitched in Arlington, Texas. This time the Rangers beat the Angels. Who was the wining pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kenny Rogers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Leiter",
      "B. Kenny Rogers",
      "C. Pedro Martinez",
      "D. Nolan Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country did the first skater to land a single Salchow skate for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sweden",
    "choices": [
      "A. United States",
      "B. Sweden",
      "C. Ukraine",
      "D. Russia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "History was made in 1988 when this man became the first skater to land a retified quadruple in competition.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kurt Browning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Josef Sobavcek",
      "B. Scott Hamilton",
      "C. Brian Boitano",
      "D. Kurt Browning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Russian figure skater never won a major title before becoming Olympic Champion in 1994.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alexei Urmanov",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ilia Kulik",
      "B. Evgeni Plushenko",
      "C. Alexei Yagudin",
      "D. Alexei Urmanov"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first man to land a quadruple-triple combination?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elvis Stojko",
    "choices": [
      "A. Timothy Goebel",
      "B. Elvis Stojko",
      "C. Evgeni Plushenko",
      "D. Alexei Yagudin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This American skater with a spellbinding jumping ability became the first man to land 3 quads in the same program in the year 2000.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Timothy Goebel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Weiss",
      "B. Timothy Goebel",
      "C. Johnny Weir",
      "D. Todd Eldredge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What historic jump combination was first done by Evgeni Plushenko?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. Triple Axel-half loop-triple flip",
      "B. Quadruple toe-triple toe-triple loop",
      "C. Quadruple toe-triple toe-double loop",
      "D. All of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although it was first done in 1988, the mens quad was not successfully landed in Olympic Games until 1998. Which lucky figure skater has his name in the history books for this achievement?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ilia Kulik",
    "choices": [
      "A. Todd Eldredge",
      "B. Elvis Stojko",
      "C. Ilia Kulik",
      "D. Alexei Yagudin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The now-commonplace triple Axel-triple toe loop combination was first done by which Olympic champion?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Viktor Petrenko",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alexei Yagudin",
      "B. Dick Button",
      "C. Robin Cousins",
      "D. Viktor Petrenko"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many different Figure Skating World Champions in the mens division were there from 1995 to 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 9",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Known for his elegant edges, this young figure skater was in a tragic accident in 1996 while skating at a show in Mexico. He was told he would never walk again. He came back in the fall of 1997, and until 2004 when he retired he was a fan favorite in competitions, usually earning bronze at best. However, he did rank second in the 2001-2002 Skate America and at the European Championships in 2002. Who is this man, who went on to win the Russian National Championships in the 2002-2003 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alexander Abt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ilia Klimkin",
      "B. Evgeni Plushenko",
      "C. Alexander Abt",
      "D. Alexei Yagudin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person is considered the most important man in the world of golf. Without him, PGA Tour events get very low TV ratings.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tiger Woods",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Collins",
      "B. Jack Nicklaus",
      "C. Arnold Palmer",
      "D. Tiger Woods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the President of Entertainment and Sports Programming Network (ESPN) in 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Bodenheimer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Peter Ubberofft",
      "B. George Bodenheimer",
      "C. Phil Knight",
      "D. Jim Collins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The ratings for the Beijing Olympics were far above those of the Athens Olympics. This is due, in part, to this man, the Chairman of Sports at NBC in 2008.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dick Ebersol",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dick Ebersol",
      "B. Jim Collins",
      "C. Phil Knight",
      "D. Tony Ponturro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bill Bowerman and this man co-founded the sports line Nike.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phil Knight",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony  Ponturro",
      "B. Phil Knight",
      "C. Jim Collins",
      "D. Steve Prontier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these men is not associated with NASCAR?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eric Grubman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eric Grubman",
      "B. Jack Roush",
      "C. Brian France",
      "D. Dale Earnhardt, Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person was a great basketball player, a poor outfielder, and a minority stockholder in the Charlotte Bobcats of the NBA. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Del Rice",
      "B. Deion Sanders",
      "C. Bo Jackson",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When he was made the Commissioner of the NHL in 1993, he was asked to bring it back to popularity in the USA. Who is this person?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gary Bettman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gordie Howe",
      "B. Gary Bettman",
      "C. Tony  Donovan",
      "D. Tim Leiweke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these people has been a Commissioner of the NBA for over 24 years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Stern",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Rozelle",
      "B. David Stern",
      "C. Marques Haynes",
      "D. Rick Barry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which family owns the Pitsburgh Steelers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rooney",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mara",
      "B. Rooney",
      "C. Davis",
      "D. Belicheck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This giant company owns The Home Depot center, The Los Angeles Kings, The L.A. Galaxy, the Houston Dynamo, the David Beckham Academy, ATP London, the Los Angeles Riptides, the Staples Center, and almost one-eighth of the Los Angeles Lakers. What is the name of this company?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Anschutz Entertainment Group",
    "choices": [
      "A. International Sporting Management",
      "B. WMG Management",
      "C. The Southern Cal Sporting Group",
      "D. Anschutz Entertainment Group"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person was one of the first great skateboarders and a video game icon.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Hawk",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tom Condon",
      "B. Tony Hawk",
      "C. John Walsh",
      "D. Sid Crosby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the owner of the Denver Broncos?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pat Bowlen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jon  Litner",
      "B. Pat Bowlen",
      "C. Coin Baden",
      "D. Kevin Plank"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The presence of two members of this sports family raises the TV ratings at tennis tournaments even when they are not winning.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Williams",
      "B. Clooney",
      "C. Sharpe",
      "D. Nastasee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This sportsman has been a great NHL player and head coach and part-owner of the Phoenix Coyotes.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wayne Gretzky",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Hull",
      "B. Scotty Bowman",
      "C. Gordie Howe",
      "D. Wayne Gretzky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This American businessman is one of the founders of Home Depot and owner of the NFL Atlanta Falcons.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arthur Blank",
    "choices": [
      "A. Arthur Tisch",
      "B. Pat Bowlen",
      "C. Arthur Blank",
      "D. Jim Nash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He founded âLittle Caesars Pizzaâ in 1959. He is the owner of the Detroit Red Wings of the NHL and the Detroit Tigers of Major League Baseball. Who i sthies person?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Ilitch",
    "choices": [
      "A. William Clay Ford, Jr.",
      "B. Kenneth Richards",
      "C. Mike Ilitch",
      "D. Pat Bowlen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the founder of the group that owns Gillette Stadium, the New England Revolution, Rand-Whitney Container Corp, and the New England Patriots?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Robert Kraft",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barton Parelli",
      "B. Robert Kraft",
      "C. Arn Tellem",
      "D. Arthur Blank"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Whhich is the official bank of the NFL and Major League Baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bank of  America",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chase Manhattan Bank",
      "B. CitiCorp",
      "C. Bank of  America",
      "D. Grand Caymans National Bank"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which athletic conference do the Southern California Trojans teams participate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "PAC-10",
    "choices": [
      "A. PAC-10",
      "B. WAC-10",
      "C. Big West",
      "D. Conference USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the home field of the Southern California Trojans football team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum",
    "choices": [
      "A. Westwood Field",
      "B. Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum",
      "C. Tustin Memorial Stadium",
      "D. Astro Dome"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Southern California Trojans finish the football season untied and undefeated for the fourth time in the teams history?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2004",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000",
      "B. 1990",
      "C. 2004",
      "D. 2002"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2005 Reggie Bush from the Southern California Trojans won what individual award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Heisman Trophy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maxwell Award",
      "B. Walter Camp Award",
      "C. Dick Butkus Award",
      "D. Heisman Trophy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Southern California Trojans player to win the Heisman award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Garrett",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Garrett",
      "B. Charles  White",
      "C. Whizzer  White",
      "D. Anthony Davis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Marcus Allen from the Southern California Trojans win the Heisman award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1981",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1981",
      "B. 1971",
      "C. 1988",
      "D. 1978"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the colors of the Southern California Trojans football team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cardinal and gold",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gold and white",
      "B. Cardinal and gold",
      "C. Cardinal and white",
      "D. Red and blue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which colleges have been among Southern California Trojansâ bitter rivals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "UCLA and Notre Dame",
    "choices": [
      "A. UCLA and Notre Dame",
      "B. BYU and Army",
      "C. Southern Methodist and Penn State",
      "D. Alabama and Air Force"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement describes best the University of Southern California?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is a private school located in Los Angeles, California.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It is a state school located in Westwood, California",
      "B. It is a state school located in Los Angeles, California.",
      "C. It is a private school located in Los Angeles, California.",
      "D. It is a private school located in Palo Alto, California."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first player form the University of Southern California to win the Outland Trophy (for best college lineman) became a solid left offensive tackle for the Minnesota Vikings. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Yary",
    "choices": [
      "A. Winston Justice",
      "B. Shaun Cody",
      "C. Sam Baker",
      "D. Ron Yary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former player from the University of Southern California Trojans was voted to the NFL All Pro Team as both offensive and defensive back. Who is this famous number 16?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Gifford",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Wood",
      "B. Sammy Baugh",
      "C. Frank Gifford",
      "D. Ed OBrien"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former University of Southern California Trojans player became an All-Star offensive tackle in the old AFL.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Mix",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Del Rio",
      "B. Lynn Swann",
      "C. Ron Mix",
      "D. Jeff Fisher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former University of Southern California Trojans member lost the race for Governor of Pennsylvania?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lynn Swann",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Wood",
      "B. Chris Cash",
      "C. Justin Fargas",
      "D. Lynn Swann"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not a former Southern California Trojans football player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Art Shell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Art Shell",
      "B. Jim Fassell",
      "C. Mike Holmgren",
      "D. Jack Del Rio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former player of the Southern California Trojans also played DB for the New York Giants but is perhaps more famous for proposing to actress Angie Harmon on The Tonight Show.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jason Sehorn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Reggie Bush",
      "B. Kori Dickson",
      "C. Jason Sehorn",
      "D. Champ Bailey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former football player from the University of Southern California was a first round draft choice of the New York Jets but caused so much turmoil that the Jets soon traded him?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Keyshawn Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dwayne Jarrett",
      "B. Keyshawn Johnson",
      "C. Terrell Owens",
      "D. Randy Moss"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the two Chicago baseball teams, Cubs and Sox play each other in the World Series and who won?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1906 and the Sox winning",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1908 and the Cubs Winning",
      "B. 1919 and the Cubs winning.",
      "C. 1906 and the Sox winning",
      "D. It never happened."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As of 2007, when was the last time the Chicago Cubs won the World Series of baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1908",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2005",
      "B. 1906",
      "C. 1908",
      "D. 1945"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which White Sox hitter had the highest career batting average?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Jackson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luke Appling",
      "B. Joe Jackson",
      "C. Frank Thomas",
      "D. Eddie Collins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which slugger from the Chicago Cubs had the most career Home Runs playing for his team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sammy Sosa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Santo",
      "B. Billy Willams",
      "C. Sammy Sosa",
      "D. Ernie Banks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As of 2007, when was the last time that the White Sox won the World Series of baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2005",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1917",
      "B. 2003",
      "C. 2004",
      "D. 2005"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following was invented before the last time that the Chicago Cubs won The World Series of baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The invention of Corn Flakes",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Invention of the Radio",
      "B. The Invention of instant coffee",
      "C. The invention of Corn Flakes",
      "D. The Invention of Television"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first All Star games of baseball were played in Chicago but at which ball park and in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Comiskey Park, 1933",
    "choices": [
      "A. Comiskey Park, 1935",
      "B. Wrigley Field, 1935",
      "C. Wrigley Field, 1933",
      "D. Comiskey Park, 1933"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first night baseball game to be played at Wrigley Field in Chicago happened on which date?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "August 9, 1988",
    "choices": [
      "A. August 9, 1988",
      "B. July 8, 1977",
      "C. August 8, 1988",
      "D. July 7, 1977"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As of 2007, which team has been the winner of the most World Series of baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "White Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Its a Tie",
      "B. Cubs",
      "C. Bulls",
      "D. White Sox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about Philip Rizzutos birth is true?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was born Fiero Francis Rizzuto on 25 September, 1917 in Brooklyn, N.Y.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was born Fiero Francis Rizzuto on 25 September, 1917 in Brooklyn, N.Y.",
      "B. He  was born Philip Francis Rizzuto on 25 September, 1916 in Hillside, New Jersey.",
      "C. He was born Carlo Philip Rizzuto on 25  September, 1915 in The Bronx, N.Y.",
      "D. He was  born Francisco Philip Rizzuto on 25 September, 1920 in Newark, New Jersey."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Phil Rizzuto play for the Yankees?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1941-1953",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1929-1945",
      "B. 1947-1962",
      "C. 1937-1950",
      "D. 1941-1953"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When Phil Rizzuto got death threats from a Boston Red Sox fan, what did manager Casey Stengel do?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He had him change uniform numbers with another player.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He had Rizzuto play second base instead of  shortstop.",
      "B. Nothing",
      "C. He sat Rizzuto so he  would be safe.",
      "D. He had him change uniform numbers with another player."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Phil Rizzuto won the Hickok Belt which is awarded to whom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The best professional athlete of the year",
    "choices": [
      "A. The best announcer of the year",
      "B. The best baseball player of the  year",
      "C. The best defensive player in baseball",
      "D. The best professional athlete of the year"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Phil Rizzutos forte?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bunting and defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hitting home runs",
      "B. Knocking in runners from second and third",
      "C. Getting extra base hits (doubles and triples)",
      "D. Bunting and defense"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these expressions was not commonly said by Phil Rizzuto as an announcer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "High enough, deep enough, gone!",
    "choices": [
      "A. Unbelievable!",
      "B. Holy Cow!",
      "C. High enough, deep enough, gone!",
      "D. Huckleberry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Phil Rizzuto often said I gotta get over that  bridge. To what did this phrase refer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He  was worried about  getting home late because of  traffic on the George Washington Bridge to NJ.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was worried about getting through the seventh inning when he got an inning off.",
      "B. He was worried about getting through to the sixth inning when Bill White would take over the announcing, making  White his bridge to relaxing.",
      "C. He  was worried about  getting home late because of  traffic on the George Washington Bridge to NJ.",
      "D. He worried  bout the game having to go to extra innings so hed have to work overtime."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On which TV show did Phil Rizzuto appear as the first mystery guest?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Whats My Line?",
    "choices": [
      "A. Beat the Clock!",
      "B. Whats My Line?",
      "C. Whom Do You trust?",
      "D. Truth or Consequences"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2006, it  was announced that Phil Rizzuto had what medical problems?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "muscle atrophy andesophageal problems",
    "choices": [
      "A. muscle atrophy andesophageal problems",
      "B. Lou Gehrigs Disease",
      "C. skin cancer",
      "D. cerebral palsy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Gilbert Arenas was drafted into the NBA by what team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Golden State Warriors",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Orlando Magic",
      "B. The Golden State Warriors",
      "C. The Washington Wizards",
      "D. The Indianapolis Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of Gilbert Arenas nicknames?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gilly-Willy",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Assassin",
      "B. Agent Zero",
      "C. G.A.",
      "D. Gilly-Willy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Gilbert Arenas is famous for doing what before taking a foul shot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He spins the ball around his waist 3 times and then dribbles the ball 3 times.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He dribbles the ball 0 times.",
      "B. He spins the ball around his waist 3 times and then dribbles the ball 3 times.",
      "C. He kisses a tattoo of his baby on his left hand and of his babys mama on his right hand.",
      "D. He makes the sign of the cross with his hand and looks up in the air with his eyes closed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not true about Gilbert Arenas?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "His middle name is not Jay.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He officially owns Team Final Boss, a professional Halo 2 gaming team.",
      "B. He has mentored a D.C. boy who lost his family in a fire at age 10.",
      "C. He has a large tent in his house converted to a low oxygen level similar to that of Colorado.",
      "D. His middle name is not Jay."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What college did Gilbert Arenas play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arizona State",
    "choices": [
      "A. Georgetown",
      "B. Arizona State",
      "C. Duke",
      "D. North Carolina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did The Detroit Red Wings play their home games during the Original Six NHL era?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Olympia",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Olympia",
      "B. The Silver Dome",
      "C. The Palace",
      "D. The Gardens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As of 2007, the Original Six team with the most Stanley Cups is The Canadiens with 24, followed by The Maple Leafs with 13.  Who is third with 10 cup wins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Red Wings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Red Wings",
      "B. Blackhawks",
      "C. Rangers",
      "D. Bruins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As of 2007, of the Original Six Teams the Montreal Canadiens have the most Stanley Cup wins.  Which two Original Six teams are tied for the most Stanley Cup losses with 12?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Red Wings  Bruins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Red Wings  Canadiens",
      "B. Red Wings  Bruins",
      "C. Rangers  Blackhawks",
      "D. Blackhawks  Toronto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As is common practice in todays NHL, most of the Original Six teams have moved into a new building over the years.  As of 2007, which of the Original Six teams has been playing in the same building the longest without moving?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York Rangers - Madison Square Gardens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings - Joe Louis Arena",
      "B. Montreal Canadiens - Bell Centre",
      "C. Toronto Maple Leafs - ACC",
      "D. New York Rangers - Madison Square Gardens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Detroit Red Wings were the last Original Six team to win the Stanley Cup.  Prior to 2006-2007 season what season was the Red Wings last Stanley Cup winning season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2001-2002",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2001-2002",
      "B. 1994-1995",
      "C. 2000-2001",
      "D. 1996-1997"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Boston Bruins head coach during their 1971-1972 Stanley Cup winning season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harry Sinden",
      "B. Tom Johnson",
      "C. Bep Guidolin",
      "D. Don Cherry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the University of Georgia win a national title in football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1980",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1982",
      "B. 1983",
      "C. 1981",
      "D. 1980"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1980, University of Georgia running back Herschel Walker gained 1616 yards to break the previous record for most yards rushed by a freshman.  What running back held this record before Herschel broke it?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pittsburghs Tony Dorsett",
    "choices": [
      "A. Texas Earl Campbell",
      "B. Penn States Kurt Warner",
      "C. Oklahomas Billy Sims",
      "D. Pittsburghs Tony Dorsett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which quarterback did not play at the University of Georgia?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Todd Blackledge",
    "choices": [
      "A. Todd Blackledge",
      "B. Mike Bobo",
      "C. Buck Belue",
      "D. Fran Tarkington"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As a freshman, Herschel Walker headed toward stardom when he ran completely over a linebacker from the University of Tennessee to score a touchdown. This linebacker picked himself up from the turf and went on to be a star defensive player with the Dallas Cowboys. Who is this defensive player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Bates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Bates",
      "B. Charlie Waters",
      "C. Brian Bosworth",
      "D. Cornelius Bennett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following did not serve as a head coach at the University of Georgia?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pat Dye",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ray Goff",
      "B. Wally Butts",
      "C. Vince Dooley",
      "D. Pat Dye"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This place kicker, who would later play for the NFL Chicago Bears, kicked a 60 yard game-winning field goal against the Clemson Tigers in 1984.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kevin Butler",
    "choices": [
      "A. Van Tiffen",
      "B. Kevin Butler",
      "C. Rex Robinson",
      "D. Al Del Greco"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Georgia is a proud member of the Southeastern Conference - Eastern Division, together with the 2006 National Champions, the Florida Gators. Which team is not a member of the SEC-East?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Auburn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vanderbilt",
      "B. Auburn",
      "C. Tennessee",
      "D. Kentucky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Georgia won the Southeastern Conference title in 2005 and in 2003 defeating which two teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arkansas and LSU",
    "choices": [
      "A. Arkansas and LSU",
      "B. Auburn and LSU",
      "C. Alabama and Auburn",
      "D. Tennessee and Alabama"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When you go paintballing what is the first thing you do before you put the carbon dioxide tank in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Put barrel plug in",
    "choices": [
      "A. Take safety off",
      "B. Put barrel plug in",
      "C. Cock it",
      "D. Load in the paintballs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In paintball, which term refers to the tank that holds the paintballs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hopper",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dopper",
      "B. Holding tank",
      "C. Hopper",
      "D. Holding tube"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of paint is used in most .68 calibre paintballs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Latex",
    "choices": [
      "A. Anti-climb paint",
      "B. Acrylic paints",
      "C. Latex",
      "D. Watercolors"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens with a paintball if put in water for 24 hours or more?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It expands",
    "choices": [
      "A. It contracts",
      "B. It expands",
      "C. It explodes",
      "D. Nothing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum temperature of a compressed 16-ounce Carbon Dioxide tank fit for a paintball gun?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "130 degrees F / 55 degrees Celsius",
    "choices": [
      "A. 120 degrees F / 50 degrees Celsius",
      "B. 130 degrees F / 55 degrees Celsius",
      "C. 140 degrees F / 60 degrees Celsius",
      "D. 110 degrees F / 43 degrees Celsius"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In paintball, you perform a Safe Velocity Test by means of what device?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Velocity chronograph",
    "choices": [
      "A. Velocity detector",
      "B. A simple stopwatch",
      "C. Velocity chronograph",
      "D. Velocity tester"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the sign CGA on paintball gas tanks stand for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Compressed Gas Association",
    "choices": [
      "A. Compact Gas Association",
      "B. Compressed Gasoline Alignment",
      "C. Compact Gas Assertion",
      "D. Compressed Gas Association"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In paintball markers, tubes that hold extra paintballs while in a battle are called what?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Speedloaders",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ballholders",
      "B. Speedloaders",
      "C. Their is no such tanks.",
      "D. Extraloaders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the most common gas used in paintball guns propellants?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carbon dioxide",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carbon dioxide",
      "B. Air",
      "C. Nitrogen",
      "D. Nitrous oxide"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which promotion did the Honky Tonk Man begin his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mid South (Memphis region)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Georgia Championship Wrestling",
      "B. Mid South (Memphis region)",
      "C. World Wide Wrestling Federation",
      "D. NWA (Charlotte region)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What championship-winning tag team was the Honky Tonk Man a part of?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Swingers",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Swingers",
      "B. The Heartbreakers",
      "C. Rhythm and Blues",
      "D. The Blond Bombers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Honky Tonk Man used a version of the swinging neckbreaker as a finishing move. What did he call this move?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shake, Rattle, and Roll",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Rockin Roller",
      "B. The one way ticket",
      "C. Shake, Rattle, and Roll",
      "D. The Rock-a-bye"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "She was only 4 ft 8.5 inches (1.43 m) tall but won a gold medal in the 1996 Olympics vaulting with a wrenched ankle. What was her name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kerri Strug",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kerri Strug",
      "B. Betty Okino",
      "C. Wendy Bruce",
      "D. Dominique Moceanu"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Hurling is an exciting game of Gaelic origin. What is a hurley?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The stick used to hit the ball",
    "choices": [
      "A. The stick used to hit the ball",
      "B. The net used in the game",
      "C. The uniform worn by players",
      "D. The ball that is hit by the stick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mike Marshall and John Slatberger invented this sport in 1972.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Footbag",
    "choices": [
      "A. Orienteering",
      "B. Footbag",
      "C. Seven-man baseball",
      "D. Frisbee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was a first round draft choice of the NFL Cardinals but he chose to play Major League Baseball. He is probably most famous for his home run in the 1988 World Series. Who is this two-sport legend?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kirk Gibson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gene Conley",
      "B. Deion Sanders",
      "C. Kirk Gibson",
      "D. Bo Jackson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This game is played on an icy, low friction surface. It is sort of a combination of bowling, shuffle board, and house sweeping.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Curling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hurling",
      "B. Curling",
      "C. Whirling",
      "D. Knurling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Chula and Pakpao are very popular in Thailand. Which statement best describes them?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They are forms of kite fighting.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They are forms of kite fighting.",
      "B. They are forms of gymnastics native to Thailand.",
      "C. They are forms of mixed martial arts taught in Thailand and derived from Chinese style  kung fu.",
      "D. They are forms of kick boxing developed in Thailand (Siam)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1961Ludwig von Bersuda was looking for a game that would also be a good conditioning sport. What sport did he invent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Underwater rugby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bo-stethnics",
      "B. Underwater (American rules) football",
      "C. Underwater rugby",
      "D. Underwater soccer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although this sport originated in Cypress Gardens, Florida, it was further developed by Australians. The sport has three categories: tricks, jumping and slalom.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barefoot waterskiing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nitrox diving",
      "B. Nitrox swimming",
      "C. Speed snorkeling",
      "D. Barefoot waterskiing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these sports is not a form of basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Penague",
    "choices": [
      "A. Penague",
      "B. Rezball",
      "C. Korfball",
      "D. Netball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1970s the Swiss biologist Hermann Brandt developed a sport which would depend on  teamwork and would not involve the terrible injuries that are so common in other sports. What sport did he invent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tchoukball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Canopying",
      "B. Tchoukball",
      "C. Orienteering",
      "D. Netball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kadima is a paddle sport in which the object is to cooperate with another person and see how many times you can hit a ball to each other without it hitting the ground. Where was this sport developed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Israel",
    "choices": [
      "A. China",
      "B. Peru",
      "C. Russia",
      "D. Israel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two gymnasts tied for the uneven bar gold at the 2003 World Gymnastics Championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hollie Vise and Chellesie Memmel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carly Patterson and Nastia Liukin",
      "B. Courntey Kupets and Terrin Humphry",
      "C. Annia Hatch and Carlinia Ponor",
      "D. Hollie Vise and Chellesie Memmel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the 2005 Womens Sr. National Gymnastics Champion in the all-around?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nastia Liukin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mary Lou Retton",
      "B. Nastia Liukin",
      "C. Shannon Miller",
      "D. Cathy Rigby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul and Morgan Hamm made history in 2000 for which of these?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Being the first set of twins to compete for USA in Gymnastics",
    "choices": [
      "A. Being the first brothers ever to compete together in the Olympics",
      "B. Being the youngest people ever to compete in the Olympics",
      "C. Being the first set of twins to compete for USA in Gymnastics",
      "D. They did not make history in 2000, as did not start competing until 2001"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1984, who became the first American ever to win the all-around title at the Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mary Lou Retton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Hamm",
      "B. Bret Conor",
      "C. Mary Lou Retton",
      "D. Carly Patterson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following gymnasts was not on the 2004 US Olympic Gymnastics team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shannon Miller",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Hamm",
      "B. Carly Patterson",
      "C. Blaine Wilson",
      "D. Shannon Miller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first gymnast ever to score a perfect 10.0?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nadia Comaneci",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mary Lou Retton",
      "B. Nadia Comaneci",
      "C. Cathy Rigby",
      "D. Shannon Miller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many medals did the Gymnastics US team get in the 2004 Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "9",
    "choices": [
      "A. 18",
      "B. 0",
      "C. 9",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Monaco Grand Prix is the crown jewel of Formula One. In what year was the inaugural race run?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1929",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1929",
      "B. 1919",
      "C. 1922",
      "D. 1939"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Indianapolis Motor Speedway is known to many fans as âThe Brickyardâ because it was once surfaced with 3.2 million bricks which replaced its original surface to make it safer for racing. What was the Speedway originally surfaced with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Crushed rock and Tar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sand and saw dust",
      "B. Crushed rock and Tar",
      "C. Concrete",
      "D. Cobblestone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In NASCAR Nextel Cup Racing there is no event more exciting than the season opener the Daytona 500, held at Daytona International Speedway every February. What trophy is the winner of the Daytona 500 awarded?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Harley J. Earl Trophy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Winston Cup",
      "B. The Harley J. Earl Trophy",
      "C. Nextel Cup",
      "D. The Daytona Florida Trophy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 24 Hours of Le Mans has been held almost every year since 1923. The race was cancelled from 1940 to 1948 due to WWII and in what other year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1936",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1926",
      "B. 1973",
      "C. 1936",
      "D. 1948"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Arguably the second most important sports car race held in the world is the 24 hours of Daytona. In what year was the inaugural 24 hours of Daytona held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1966",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1962",
      "B. 1966",
      "C. 1969",
      "D. 1973"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The inaugural Canadian Grand Prix race (for F1 cars) was held at Mosport Park in Bowmanville, Ontario approximately 70 miles northeast of Toronto, in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1967",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1969",
      "B. 1973",
      "C. 1967",
      "D. 1965"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the first F1 US Grand Prix held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1959",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1969",
      "B. 1949",
      "C. 1959",
      "D. 1979"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The inaugural Indianapolis 500 held in 1911 was won by Ray Harroun driving a Marmon âWaspâ. What was his average winning speed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "74.602 mph",
    "choices": [
      "A. 74.602 mph",
      "B. 47.602 mph",
      "C. 174.602 mph",
      "D. 7.602mph"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Gilles Villeneuve was granted a Formula 1 seat after impressing a fellow driver during a non-championship Formula Atlantic race in 1977. Who did Gilles Villeneuve impress to get his first ride in Formula one with McLaren?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "James Hunt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bruce McLaren",
      "B. Enzo Ferrari",
      "C. Frank Williams",
      "D. James Hunt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ayrton Senna died on May 1st, 1994 while racing in the San Marino Grand Prix at Imola for Williams. What team did Ayrton Senna start his Formula One career with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Toleman",
    "choices": [
      "A. McLaren",
      "B. Toleman",
      "C. Brabham",
      "D. Ferrari"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is outfielder Shane Victorino from?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hawaii",
    "choices": [
      "A. Japan",
      "B. California",
      "C. Hawaii",
      "D. Alaska"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many saves did Brad Lidge finish the regular 2008 season with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "41",
    "choices": [
      "A. 37",
      "B. 45",
      "C. 39",
      "D. 41"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the second baseman of the 2008 Philadelphia Phillies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chase Utley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Matt Stairs",
      "B. Chase Utley",
      "C. Brett Myers",
      "D. Ramon Feliz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the oldest pitcher of the 2008 Philadelphia Phillies.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jamie Moyer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bret Myers",
      "B. J.C. Romero",
      "C. Brad Lidge",
      "D. Jamie Moyer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Shawn Michaels real name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Shawn Hickenbottom",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Shawn Hickenbottom",
      "B. Michael Shawn",
      "C. Michael Shawn Hicks",
      "D. Michael Shawn Hills"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Shawn Michaels second wife whom he married in 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rebecca",
    "choices": [
      "A. Victorta",
      "B. Rebecca",
      "C. Rachel",
      "D. Vikki"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What statement concerning Shawn Michaels children is true?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "His son was born in 2000 and his daughter was born in 2004.",
    "choices": [
      "A. His son was born in 2000 and his daughter was born in 2004.",
      "B. His daughter was born in 2000 and his daughter was born in 2004.",
      "C. His son was born in 1998 and his daughter was born in 2008.",
      "D. His son was born in 2005 and his daughter was born in 2003."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Shawn Michaels win his first WWE Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1996",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1996",
      "B. 2003",
      "C. 2002",
      "D. 1997"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Shawn Michaels finishing move?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sweet Chin Music",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sharpshooter",
      "B. Pedigree",
      "C. Sweet Chin Music",
      "D. Frog Splash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What song, written by Jimmy Hart, is Shawn Michaels entrance music?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sexy Boy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sexy Boy",
      "B. Hello Ladies",
      "C. LovePassionFuryEnergy",
      "D. The Time Is Now"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Shawn Michaels grow up?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Antonio, TX.",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Antonio, TX.",
      "B. Dallas, TX",
      "C. Austin, TX",
      "D. Houston,TX"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many brothers does Shawn Michaels have?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the Yankees play immediately before Yankee Stadium was built?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Polo Grounds-the home of the New York Giants",
    "choices": [
      "A. Oriole Park-the home of the Baltimore Orioles",
      "B. Shea Stadium-the home of the New York Mets",
      "C. The Polo Grounds-the home of the New York Giants",
      "D. Ebbets Field-the home of the Brooklyn Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who owned the Yankees when Yankee Stadium was built?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jacob Ruppert and Tullinghast LHommedieu",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jacob Ruppert and Dave Ferrell",
      "B. Jacob Ruppert and Tullinghast LHommedieu",
      "C. Jacob Ruppert and Dave Devrey",
      "D. George Steinbrenner and George Costanza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The land where Yankee Stadium was built was previously used for this purpose.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lumber yard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Car lot",
      "B. Court House",
      "C. Celery farm",
      "D. Lumber yard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following has never been a nickname for Yankee Stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The house that built baseball",
    "choices": [
      "A. The house that was built for Ruth",
      "B. The house that Ruth built",
      "C. The house that Lindsay rebuilt",
      "D. The house that built baseball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On April 18, 1923 Babe Ruth hit the first home run in Yankee Stadium against this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston Red Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Oakland Athletics",
      "B. Canton Bulldogs",
      "C. Boston Red Sox",
      "D. Chicago White Sox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the maximum capacity of Yankee Stadium when it was first built?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "71,900",
    "choices": [
      "A. 58,000",
      "B. 91,200",
      "C. 63,800",
      "D. 71,900"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the correct statement about Yankee Stadium.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yankee Stadium was the first three-tiered sports facility.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yankee Stadium was always an exclusively baseball field.",
      "B. The New York Yankees have always played their regular season games at Yankee Stadium.",
      "C. Yankee Stadiums original name was The New York Yankee Baseball Field.",
      "D. Yankee Stadium was the first three-tiered sports facility."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The land on which Yankee Stadium was built was bought for this price.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "$675,000",
    "choices": [
      "A. $675,000",
      "B. $1,25,000",
      "C. $4,500",
      "D. $2,500,000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For many years he made all the announcements at Yankee Stadium.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bob Sheppard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mel Allen",
      "B. Red Barber",
      "C. Michael Kaye",
      "D. Bob Sheppard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On June 22, 1938 a famous boxing match was held in Yakee Stadium. Who lost?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Max Schmelling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Max Baer",
      "B. Joe Louis",
      "C. Jack Demosey",
      "D. Max Schmelling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does not have a monument at Monument Park, a section of Yankee Stadium contains a collection of monuments?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wellington Mara",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pope Paul VI",
      "B. The Victims of 9/11",
      "C. Pope John Paul II",
      "D. Wellington Mara"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first college football team to win over 50 games at Yankee Stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York University",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York University",
      "B. Notre Dame",
      "C. Fordham University",
      "D. Army"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1957, a large crowd came to hear this man speak at Yankee Stadium.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Billy Graham",
    "choices": [
      "A. L.Ron Hubbard",
      "B. Pope John Paul II",
      "C. Billy Graham",
      "D. Pope John XXIII"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1970s this professional soccer team played their home games at Yankee Stadium.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Cosmos",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Nets",
      "B. The Cosmos",
      "C. Milan A.C.",
      "D. The Kicks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first perfect game in the 20th century was pitched on May 5, 1904. Who was the winning pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cy Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rube Waddell",
      "B. Babe Ruth",
      "C. Addie Joss",
      "D. Cy Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The second perfect game in the 20th century took place on October 2, 1908 and was pitched by Addie Joss for what team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleveland Naps",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cleveland Braves",
      "B. Cleveland Browns",
      "C. Cleveland Naps",
      "D. Cleveland Lakers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On April 30, 1922, Charlie Robertson pitched a perfect game for the Chicago White Sox. What team lost that day?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Detroit Tigers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston Red Sox",
      "B. Cleveland Indians",
      "C. Detroit Tigers",
      "D. New York Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1956, during game 5 of the World Series, the New York Yankees beat the Brooklyn Dodgers 2 to 0 and it took Don Larsen just 97 pitches to complete the game. What catcher caught the game for the Yankees?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi Berra",
    "choices": [
      "A. Enos Slaughter",
      "B. Elston Howard",
      "C. Bill Skowron",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On June 21, 1964, the Philadelphia Phillies beat the New York Mets 6 to 0 behind a perfect game pitched by this player.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Bunning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kirk Gibson",
      "B. Dick Allen",
      "C. Dennis Bennett",
      "D. Jim Bunning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On September 9, 1965, this Hall of Fame Pitcher threw a perfect game against the Chicago Cubs. Who was he and what team did he pitch for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sandy Koufax, L.A. Dodgers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Drysdale, L.A. Dodgers",
      "B. Sandy Koufax, L.A. Dodgers",
      "C. Sandy Koufax, Brooklyn Dodgers",
      "D. Don Drysdale, Brooklyn Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1968, Catfish Hunter pitched a perfect game for the Oakland Athletics, beating the Minnesota Twins 4 to 0. What is Catfishs real name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "James Augustus Hunter",
    "choices": [
      "A. James Augustus Hunter",
      "B. Julian Catfish Hunter",
      "C. Catfish Hunter is his real name",
      "D. John Henry Hunter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Len Barker pitch a perfect game for the Cleveland Indians, in a 3-0 win against the Toronto Blue Jays?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1981",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1985",
      "B. 1971",
      "C. 1981",
      "D. 1975"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who pitched a perfect game for the California Angels on September 30, 1984?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Witt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Finley",
      "B. Mike Witt",
      "C. Nolan Ryan",
      "D. Frank Tanana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two baseball teams played on July 28, 1991 when Dennis Martinez pitched a perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Montreal Expos and L.A. Dodgers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montreal Expos and L.A. Dodgers",
      "B. Chicago Cubs and San Francisco Giants",
      "C. L.A. Dodgers and St. Louis Cardinals",
      "D. Montreal Expos and Chicago Cubs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "David Wells pitched a perfect game for the New York Yankees on May 17, 1998. What team was the loser?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Minnesota Twins",
    "choices": [
      "A. California Angels",
      "B. Texas Rangers",
      "C. Baltimore Orioles",
      "D. Minnesota Twins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two teams were playing when Randy Johnson pitched a perfect game on May 18, 2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arizona Diamondbacks and the Atlanta Braves",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Yankees and Boston Red Soxs",
      "B. Arizona Diamondbacks and the Atlanta Braves",
      "C. Arizona Diamondbacks and the New York Yankees",
      "D. Atlanta Braves and the New York Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the starting quarterback  for LSU in their 2005 bowl game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Matt Flynn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Craig Davis",
      "B. Matt Flynn",
      "C. Jeremy Bunting",
      "D. JaMarcus Russell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This 2005 LSU recruit insisted that he was 100 percent committed to Texas, but on National Signing Day he signed with LSU.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ryan Perrilloux",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dwayne Bowe",
      "B. Ryan Perrilloux",
      "C. Antonio Robinson",
      "D. Jeremy Bunting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of LSUs mascot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike the Tiger",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike the Tiger",
      "B. Mike the Rabbit",
      "C. Michael the Lion",
      "D. Tiger"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did LSU hire as Defensive Coordinator before the start of the 2005 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bo Pelini",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stacy Searels",
      "B. Bo Pelini",
      "C. Jimbo Fisher",
      "D. Doug Mallory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What running back led the LSU team in rushing in 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joseph Addai",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alley Broussard III",
      "B. Joseph Addai",
      "C. Shyrone Carey",
      "D. Craig Davis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what 2005 bowl game did LSU defeat Miami?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Peach bowl",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rose bowl",
      "B. Cotton bowl",
      "C. Peach bowl",
      "D. Outback bowl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the final score of LSUs 2005 bowl game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "LSU 40 - Miami 3",
    "choices": [
      "A. LSU 41 - Miami 17",
      "B. LSU 10 - Miami 45",
      "C. LSU 40 - Miami 3",
      "D. LSU 49 - Miami 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who led the 2005 LSU team in receptions?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dwayne Bowe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carlos Rachel",
      "B. Skler Green",
      "C. Dwayne Bowe",
      "D. Ryan Perrilloux"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became LSUs head coach before the start of the 2005 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Les Miles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Bryant",
      "B. Nick Saben",
      "C. Les Miles",
      "D. Karl Dunbar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the Pittsburgh Steelers when the team was founded in 1933?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pirates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gridirons",
      "B. Pirates",
      "C. Steelers",
      "D. Millers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two main colors on the Steelers uniforms?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "black and gold",
    "choices": [
      "A. blue and red",
      "B. black and gold",
      "C. yellow and gray",
      "D. black and red"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did the Steelers face in the Super Bowl in the 2005-2006 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Seahawks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Colts",
      "B. Seahawks",
      "C. Browns",
      "D. Eagles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What stadium became the Pittsburgh Steelers home field in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Heinz Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Heinz Field",
      "B. Pitt Stadium",
      "C. Qwest Field",
      "D. Husky Stadium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did the Steelers defeat to win their first Super Bowl game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Minnesota Vikings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seattle Seahawks",
      "B. Oakland Raiders",
      "C. Dallas Cowboys",
      "D. Minnesota Vikings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What boxer died in the 14th round in a fight against Ray Mancini on November 13, 1982?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duk Koo Kim",
    "choices": [
      "A. Thomas Hearns",
      "B. Roberto Duran",
      "C. Duk Koo Kim",
      "D. Marvin Hagler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How much should a boxer weigh in order to be in the Lightweight class?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "up to 59.0 kg",
    "choices": [
      "A. up to 59.0 kg",
      "B. up to 53.5",
      "C. up to 49.0 kg",
      "D. up to 47.6 kg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of Mike Tyson?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Iron Mike",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike the Punisher",
      "B. Mike the Unbeatable",
      "C. Mike the Machine",
      "D. Iron Mike"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many rounds are played in championship fights according to a rule adopted in 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 11",
      "C. 14",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did professional boxing start in 1891?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "England",
    "choices": [
      "A. Germany",
      "B. Russia",
      "C. England",
      "D. USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a rabbit punch in boxing?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A punch to the back of the neck",
    "choices": [
      "A. A hit with a head",
      "B. A punch with the inside of the glove",
      "C. A punch to the lower back",
      "D. A punch to the back of the neck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nationality of the World Boxing Organization heavyweight champion Ruslan Chagaev?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Uzbekistani",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kazakhstani",
      "B. Uzbekistani",
      "C. Russian",
      "D. Ukrainian"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the weight of gloves in heavyweight bouts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10 ounces",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8 ounces",
      "B. 12 ounces",
      "C. 14 ounces",
      "D. 10 ounces"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What boxer was crowned Sportsman of the Century by Sports Illustrated and the BBC in 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Muhammad Ali",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rocky Marciano",
      "B. Mike Tyson",
      "C. Sugar Ray Leonard",
      "D. Muhammad Ali"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This historic soccer player began his career as a poor boy from the slums in Tres Coracoes, Brazil. By the time of his retirement he had scored over a 1000 goals most of which for his Club Santos. Who is this world-famous soccer player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pele",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kaka",
      "B. Maradona",
      "C. Pele",
      "D. Ronaldhino"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous soccer player was born under the name Luis Nazario de Lima in a suburb of Rio de Janeiro?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ronaldo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ronaldhino",
      "B. Rivaldo",
      "C. Kaka",
      "D. Ronaldo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which great soccer player is famous for his âHand of God goal against England in 1986 FIFA World Cup quarter-final?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maradona",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pele",
      "B. Maradona",
      "C. Zidane",
      "D. Messi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Dutch soccer legend that played for Ajax is one of the few players named European Footballer of the Year three times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johan Cruyff",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hristo Stoichkov",
      "B. Johan Cruyff",
      "C. David Beckham",
      "D. Cristiano Ronaldo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Argentinean top goal scorer played most of his career for the famous 1950s Real Madrid team as they dominated the European Club Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alfredo Di Stefano",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alfredo Di Stefano",
      "B. Zinedine Zidane",
      "C. George Best",
      "D. Diego Maradona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Native to Algeria and from a very poor background like many top players from the past, this soccer player contributed to Frances victory in the 1998 World Cup. Who is this soccer player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zinedine Zidane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alessandro del Piero",
      "B. Zinedine Zidane",
      "C. Jean Pierre Papen",
      "D. Ferenc Puskas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Bulgarian soccer star played for FC Barcelona in the years when they were famous as âDream Teamâ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hristo Stoichkov",
    "choices": [
      "A. Trifon Ivanov",
      "B. Hristo Ivanov",
      "C. Hristo Stoichkov",
      "D. Dimitar Berbatov"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which German soccer star was voted European Soccer Player of the Year in both 1972 and 1976?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Franz Beckenbauer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lev Yashin",
      "B. Franz Beckenbauer",
      "C. Ferenc Puskas",
      "D. Michael Balack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these soccer players is popular not only on the soccerfield, but in the fashion circles, too?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Beckham",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pele",
      "B. Lev Yashin",
      "C. David Beckham",
      "D. Maradona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which great soccer goalkeeper was nicknamed âThe black spiderâ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lev Yashin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maradona",
      "B. Zinedine Zidane",
      "C. Lev Yashin",
      "D. Michael Balack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which big legend of Manchester United survived an airplane crash in 1958?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sir Bobby Charlton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sir Stanley Matthews",
      "B. Sir Bobby Charlton",
      "C. David Seaman",
      "D. George Best"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This historic soccer player was still playing professionally at the age of 50 in the top division. At his best in the late 40s to mid 50s he only played for two clubs, Blackpool and Stoke. Who is this world-famous soccer player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stanley Matthews",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ronaldo",
      "B. Stanley Matthews",
      "C. George Best",
      "D. Michel Platini"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which European soccer star was nicknamed âThe black pearlâ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eusebio da Silva Ferriera",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Weah",
      "B. Ronaldinho",
      "C. Ferenc Puskas",
      "D. Eusebio da Silva Ferriera"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which brilliant top goal scorer is a product of Atletico Madrids youth system but legend of the rival team Real Madrid?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Raul Blanco",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mendieta",
      "B. Victor Valdes",
      "C. Michel Platini",
      "D. Raul Blanco"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Hungarian soccer player was known throughout his career as The Galloping Major and later with Real Madrid as  âLittle Cannon?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ferenc Puskas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Trifon Ivanov",
      "B. Lukas Podolski",
      "C. Victor Valdes",
      "D. Ferenc Puskas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This French soccer legend finished top scorer in A Series for three consecutive seasons (1982-83, 1983-84 and 1984-85) and was voted Player of the Year by World Soccer magazine in 1984 and 1985. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Platini",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vialli",
      "B. Platini",
      "C. Reina",
      "D. Papen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which European soccer player was named  European Soccer Player of the Year three times (1988, 89 and 92) and FIFA World Player of the Year in 1992?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marco van Basten",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paolo Maldini",
      "B. Franco Baresi",
      "C. Ruud Gullit",
      "D. Marco van Basten"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which professional soccer player spent his entire club career (25 years) in  A.C. Milan?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paolo Maldini",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vialli",
      "B. Paolo Maldini",
      "C. Marco van Basten",
      "D. Franco Baresi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Milanâs defender won six scudetti (Serie A league titles) and three European Cups and his #6 jersey was retired by the club?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Franco Baresi",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Best",
      "B. Mauro Tassotti",
      "C. Franco Baresi",
      "D. Alessandro Costacurta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Brazilian soccer player was part of Barcelonaâs âDream Teamâ (1993-1994 season) and scored 30 goals in 33 matches?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Romario",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rivaldo",
      "B. Romario",
      "C. Ronaldo",
      "D. Pele"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How long does a set in volleyball last?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Until one of the teams gets at least 25 points with at least two points advantage over the other team.",
    "choices": [
      "A. 30 minutes",
      "B. Until one of the teams gets at least 25 points with at least two points advantage over the other team.",
      "C. 15 minutes",
      "D. Until one of the teams gets 25 points"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country was the European champion in football and basketball in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greece",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. Spain",
      "D. Italy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the autumn of 2006 Poland won two silver medals at the World Championships in these sports.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Volleyball (Men) and Handball (Men)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Football (Men) and Basketball (Women)",
      "B. Volleyball (Men) and Handball (Men)",
      "C. Basketball (Men) and Volleyball (Women)",
      "D. Football (Women) and Handball (Women)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many players are there in a handball team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "7",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams won the most titles in mens volleyvball in the beginning of the 21st century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brazil",
    "choices": [
      "A. Italy",
      "B. Brazil",
      "C. Russia",
      "D. USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The EHF Champions League is a major competition in this sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Handball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Volleyball",
      "B. Basketball",
      "C. Football",
      "D. Handball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In September 2007 two Mens European Championship finals were held during the same weekend. The final game in volleyball was played in Moscow and the top two basketball teams competed in Madrid. Both finals were between Russia and Spain. Who were the winners?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spain in Moscow, Russia in Madrid",
    "choices": [
      "A. Russia in both finals",
      "B. Spain in both finals",
      "C. Spain in Moscow, Russia in Madrid",
      "D. Russia in Moscow, Spain in Madrid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the top European club competition in mens basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Euroleague",
    "choices": [
      "A. ULEB Cup",
      "B. Champions League",
      "C. NBA",
      "D. Euroleague"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country was the first to beat the US basketball Dream Team at the Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Puerto Rico",
    "choices": [
      "A. Argentina",
      "B. Puerto Rico",
      "C. Soviet Union",
      "D. Spain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which team sport can you see a player called libero, whose jersey is a different color from the rest of the team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Volleyball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Volleyball",
      "B. Football",
      "C. Basketball",
      "D. Handball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1972 Dolphins led the NFL in both points scored and points allowed. How many points did they score and allow, respectively?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "385-171",
    "choices": [
      "A. 422-162",
      "B. 390-75",
      "C. 347-167",
      "D. 385-171"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many members of the 1972 Miami Dolphins made it to the Pro Bowl that year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "9",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 13",
      "D. 6"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Super Bowl MVP in 1972?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "S Jake Scott",
    "choices": [
      "A. S Jake Scott",
      "B. RB Larry Csonka",
      "C. WR Paul Warfield",
      "D. RB Mercury Morris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1972 RB Larry Csonka rushed 213 times for how many yards?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1,117",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1,178",
      "B. 2,143",
      "C. 1,098",
      "D. 1,117"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which member of the 1972 Miami Dolphins once said, Perfection ends a lot of arguments.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "RB Larry Csonka",
    "choices": [
      "A. WR Paul Warfield",
      "B. TE Jim Mandich",
      "C. QB Bob Griese",
      "D. RB Larry Csonka"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the combined record of the 1972 Dolphins regular and post season (Super Bowl included) opponents?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "98-123-3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 78-143-3",
      "B. 98-123-3",
      "C. 119-101-4",
      "D. 101-122-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2005 the Indianapolis Colts won their first 13 games and appeared ready to challenge the 1972 Miami Dolphins record, but then lost their next 2 games. Which 1998 team also won their first 13 games but lost their next 2?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Denver Broncos",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas Cowboys",
      "B. Green Bay Packers",
      "C. Denver Broncos",
      "D. New York Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1976, only four years after the 1972 Dolphins won all their games, the Tampa Bay Buccaneers failed to win a game, and finished with a record of 0-14. They were last in the NFL, scoring only 125 points all season. The 1976 Bucs defense allowed 412 points, which was next to last in the league. Which team allowed the most points in 1976?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Seattle Seahawks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seattle Seahawks",
      "B. Buffalo Bills",
      "C. Kansas City Chiefs",
      "D. New York Jets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these happened for the first time in 1913?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Baseball fans were allowed to keep foul balls.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The baseball catcher wore a face mask for the first time.",
      "B. The baseball catcher wore a chest protector for the first time.",
      "C. Baseball fans were allowed onto the field after the game.",
      "D. Baseball fans were allowed to keep foul balls."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What statement is true about Kathryn Johnston?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She was the first girl to play in the Little League.",
    "choices": [
      "A. She was the first female baseball player in NCAA baseball.",
      "B. She was the first female in the Baseball Hall of Fame.",
      "C. She was the winningest pitcher in the All-American Girls Baseball League during World War II.",
      "D. She was the first girl to play in the Little League."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Little League baseball player to become US President?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George W. Bush",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Clinton",
      "B. Lyndon B. Johnson",
      "C. George W. Bush",
      "D. Gerald Ford"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these ladies was the first woman to play on a professional minor league baseball team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kendra Hanes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maria Pepe",
      "B. Julie Croteau",
      "C. Carla Stotz",
      "D. Kendra Hanes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first pitcher to win the Gold Glove Award 17 times?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greg Maddox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Greg Maddox",
      "B. Jim Kaat",
      "C. Bob Gibson",
      "D. Bobby Shantz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first Little League World Series played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1947",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1971",
      "B. 1952",
      "C. 1939",
      "D. 1947"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The All-American Girls Professional Baseball League existed during these years.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1943-1954",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1943-1955",
      "B. 1944-1950",
      "C. 1942-1946",
      "D. 1943-1954"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Major League players at this position were the first to hit over 37,000 home runs.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "First base",
    "choices": [
      "A. Left field",
      "B. Center Field",
      "C. First base",
      "D. Right Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first non-American baseball team to win the Little League World Series was from this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mexico",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mexico",
      "B. The Dominican Republic",
      "C. Venezuela",
      "D. Japan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pitcher was the first Little Leaguer to make it to the Major Leagues?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joey Jay",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Lemon",
      "B. Roger Clemens",
      "C. Joey Jay",
      "D. Bob Gibson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This pitcher was the first Little Leaguer to be inducted into the Baseball Hall of Fame.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Hunter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joey Jay",
      "B. Don Drysdale",
      "C. Jim Hunter",
      "D. Bob Gibson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jim Barbieri was the first player to make these two accomplishments.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Play in the Little League World Series and the Major League World Series",
    "choices": [
      "A. Win a Rose Bowl and a World Series.",
      "B. Play in a Major League World Series and in an NBA game",
      "C. Play in the Little League World Series and the Major League World Series",
      "D. Win an NBA Championship and a Major League World Series"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The team that won the first Little League World Series was from which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "WIlliamsport, Pa.",
    "choices": [
      "A. WIlliamsport, Pa.",
      "B. Morrisville, Pa.",
      "C. Taipei, Taiwan",
      "D. Gary, Pa."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the second Little League World Series in 1948?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lockhaven, Pa.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lockhaven, Pa.",
      "B. Tampa, Fl.",
      "C. Bowling Green, Ky.",
      "D. Roswell, N.M."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the 1962 Little League World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Jose, Ca.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Osaka, Japan",
      "B. Austin, Tx.",
      "C. Lakewood, N.J.",
      "D. San Jose, Ca."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team was the winner of the 1951 Little League World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stamford, Ct.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston, TX.",
      "B. Austin, TX.",
      "C. Louisville, Ky.",
      "D. Stamford, Ct."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these Georgia teams was the 1983 Little League World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marietta, Ga.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta, Ga.",
      "B. Marietta, Ga.",
      "C. Burns, Ga.",
      "D. Roswell, Ga."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1999, Phoenix City, AL lost the Little League World Series to which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Osaka, Japan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tainan City, Taiwan",
      "B. Pu-Tzu Town, Taiwan",
      "C. Osaka, Japan",
      "D. Li-Teh, Taiwan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Little League World Series in 1998?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Toms River, N.J.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Toms River, N.J.",
      "B. Osaka, Japan",
      "C. David, Panama",
      "D. Tainan, Taiwan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the 1993 Little League World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Long Beach, Ca.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Norwalk, CT.",
      "B. Houston, TX.",
      "C. Birmingham, AL.",
      "D. Long Beach, Ca."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which US team won the Little League World Series championship game in 1970?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wayne, N. J.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gary, IN.",
      "B. Campbell, CA.",
      "C. Wayne, N. J.",
      "D. St. Petersburg, FL."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tampa, FL. lost the 1975 Little League World Series to which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lakewood, N. J.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lakewood, N. J.",
      "B. Morristown, TN.",
      "C. Seoul, South Korea",
      "D. Osaka, Japan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what Super Bowl did the Minnesota Vikings make their first appearance?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Super Bowl IV",
    "choices": [
      "A. Super Bowl IV",
      "B. Super Bowl VII",
      "C. Super Bowl V",
      "D. Super Bowl II"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of the Minnesota Vikings defensive line in the late 1960s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the Purple People Eaters",
    "choices": [
      "A. the Purple People Eaters",
      "B. They didnt have a nickname.",
      "C. the Berserks",
      "D. the Purple Swarm"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did the Minnesota Vikings lose to in Super Bowl VIII?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miami Dolphins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas Cowboys",
      "B. Pittsburgh Steelers",
      "C. Green Bay Packers",
      "D. Miami Dolphins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The great Brazilian soccer player was born Manoel Francisco dos Santos, but we known him better by this name.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Garrincha",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ronaldo",
      "B. Zico",
      "C. Garrincha",
      "D. Pele"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Dale Ellis set a record for the most minutes in a game. How many minutes did he play against the Milwaukee Bucks on November 9 1989?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "69",
    "choices": [
      "A. 69",
      "B. 54",
      "C. 96",
      "D. 57"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first NBA player to hit  98.1 % of his free throws in a season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jose Calderon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dolph Schayes",
      "B. Calvin Murphy",
      "C. Jose Calderon",
      "D. Bill Sharman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to play 1192 consecutive games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A.C. Green",
    "choices": [
      "A. A.C. Green",
      "B. Bob Lanier",
      "C. Calvin Murphy",
      "D. Walt Bellamy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to get 181 triple doubles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oscar Robertson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Earvin Johnson",
      "B. Oscar Robertson",
      "C. Michael Jordan",
      "D. Wilt Chamberlain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This man was very influential in NCAA football and NFL football. He played right field for the New York Yankees and was a Rose Bowl MVP.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Halas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Reggie Bush",
      "B. Bo Jackson",
      "C. George Halas",
      "D. John Elway"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What phrase did Rod Smart write on the back of his jersey when he played in the XFL?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He Hate Me",
    "choices": [
      "A. I Am So-Smart",
      "B. So Very Smart",
      "C. He Hate Me",
      "D. The Hefty Lefty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players was nicknamed The Fridge?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "William Perry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Art Monk",
      "B. Manute Bol",
      "C. William Perry",
      "D. Jared Allen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first player in Major League Baseball to lead in double plays at three different positions - at third base, at second base and shortstop.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gil McDougald",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Shofner",
      "B. Alex Rodriguiz",
      "C. Gil McDougald",
      "D. Ernie Banks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former AFL offensive tackle was nicknamed The Intellectual Assassin.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Mix",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yale Mix",
      "B. Ron Mix",
      "C. Yale Munoz",
      "D. Ron Munoz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Golfer Ernie Els has the same nickname as this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Orleans",
    "choices": [
      "A. Exeter",
      "B. New Orleans",
      "C. Tucson",
      "D. Edmonton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Wisconsin-born end had the nickname Crazylegs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elroy Hirsch",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lance Alworth",
      "B. Len Goodman",
      "C. Elroy Hirsch",
      "D. Jerry Rice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These were the first two NBA players to be traded after winning the MVP Trophy.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Moses Malone and Wilt Chamberlain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Moses Malone and Austin Carr",
      "B. Moses Malone and Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. Wilt Chamberlain and Karl Malone",
      "D. Karl Malone and Oscar Robertson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first tennis player to have twice won all four Grand Slam singles titles in the same year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rod Laver",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rod Laver",
      "B. Bjorn Borg",
      "C. Arthur Ashe",
      "D. Roger Federer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This swimmer won three silver medals at the 2008 Olympics at the age of 40.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dara Torres",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dara Torres",
      "B. Ian Thorpe",
      "C. Janice Forde",
      "D. Jeanne  Llwellyn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Thrilla in Manila, a boxing match between Muhammad Ali and Joe Frazier, was held in which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Quezon City",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pasig City",
      "B. Cebu City",
      "C. Davao City",
      "D. Quezon City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player of the Philippine Basketball Association (PBA), nicknamed the Triggerman, broke several Filipino and PBA all-time records, including the most points scored in a single game by a Filipino.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Allan Caidic",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alvin Patrimonio",
      "B. Ramon Fernandez",
      "C. Allan Caidic",
      "D. Johnny Abarientos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player received the first  MVP award of the The Philippine Basketball Association?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bogs Adornado",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bogs Adornado",
      "B. Tony Harris",
      "C. Gil Cortez",
      "D. Joy Dionisio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This practitioner of pocket billiards, called the Magician, is famous for winning many of the most prestigious nine-ball tournaments.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Efren Bata Reyes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Juan Dela Cruz",
      "B. Efren Bata Reyes",
      "C. Dyango Bustamante",
      "D. Alex Pagulayan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which facility, located in Quezon City, Philippines, was nicknamed The Big Dome?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Araneta Coliseum",
    "choices": [
      "A. Araneta Coliseum",
      "B. Cuneta Astrodome",
      "C. Makati Sports Complex",
      "D. Ynares Gym"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which athlete was described by Time Magazine as the Philippines sole bona fide international sports superstar?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Efren Bata Reyes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Manny Pacman Pacquiao",
      "B. Paeng Nepomoceno",
      "C. Efren Bata Reyes",
      "D. Sam Milby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 2008 Olympic Games, the gold and silver medalists in womens all round competition in gymnastics represented this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. China",
      "B. Russia",
      "C. USA",
      "D. Romania"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first gymnast in Olympic history to score a perfect 10?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nadia Comaneci (Romania)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Olga Korbut (USSR)",
      "B. Svetlana Boguinskaya (Russia)",
      "C. Mary Lou Retton (USA)",
      "D. Nadia Comaneci (Romania)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former gymnasts won the most medals in the Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Larissa Latynina (Russia)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Larissa Latynina (Russia)",
      "B. Olga Korbut (Soviet Union)",
      "C. Nadia Comaneci (Romania)",
      "D. Shannon Miller (USA)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former gymnasts is the most decorated male gymnast in the Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sawao Kato (japan)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alexander Dityatin (USSR)",
      "B. Sawao Kato (japan)",
      "C. Kurt Thomas (USA)",
      "D. Xiaopeng Li (China)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first US female gymnast to win the all around gold at a fully-attended Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carly Patterson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shawn Johnson",
      "B. Mary Lou Retton",
      "C. Carly Patterson",
      "D. Shannon Miller"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What gymnastics team won the all around gold medal at the 2008 Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "China",
    "choices": [
      "A. USA",
      "B. Japan",
      "C. Russia",
      "D. China"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On what surface is the Wimbledon tournament played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "grass",
    "choices": [
      "A. grass",
      "B. clay",
      "C. hard",
      "D. carpet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the official colors of the Wimbledon tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "purple and green",
    "choices": [
      "A. yellow and purple",
      "B. purple and green",
      "C. blue and yellow",
      "D. green and blue"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1985, this tennis player, only 17-years-old at the time, became the first unseeded contestant to win the Mens singles title at Wimbledon.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boris Becker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Stich",
      "B. Boris Becker",
      "C. Goran IvaniÅ¡eviÄ",
      "D. Stefan Edberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Grand Slam winner won her first out of a total of seven Ladies singles Wimbledon titles in 1988.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steffi Graf",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chris Evert",
      "B. Steffi Graf",
      "C. Jana Novotna",
      "D. Martina Navratilova"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Between which two tournaments is Wimbledon played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "French Open and US Open",
    "choices": [
      "A. German Open and Australian Open",
      "B. Australian Open and French Open",
      "C. French Open and US Open",
      "D. US Open and Australian Open"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first lady to win 6 consecutive Ladies singles titles at Wimbledon?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Martina Navratilova",
    "choices": [
      "A. Martina Navratilova",
      "B. Arantxa Sanchez Vicario",
      "C. Steffi Graf",
      "D. Martina Hingis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2001 this player became the first ever wild card entry to win the Wimbledon tournament.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Goran IvaniÅ¡eviÄ",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pat Rafter",
      "B. Andy Roddick",
      "C. Boris Becker",
      "D. Goran IvaniÅ¡eviÄ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "With whom of these tennis players has Martina Navratilova not won a Wimbledon Ladies doubles title?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gigi Fernandez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chris Evert",
      "B. Pam Shriver",
      "C. Billie Jean King",
      "D. Gigi Fernandez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In its very first year, 1877, Wimbledon began with 22 contestants, competing for this title.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mens singles title",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mens singles title",
      "B. Ladies singles title",
      "C. Mens doubles title",
      "D. Ladies doubles title"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The winner of the Ladies singles title at Wimbledon is awarded a silver plate with beautiful motifs. What is its nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rosewater Dish",
    "choices": [
      "A. Silverstone Dish",
      "B. Rosewater Dish",
      "C. Satellite Dish",
      "D. Wimbledon Dish"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pittsburgh Steelers are the oldest team in the American Conference. What year were they formed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1933",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1943",
      "B. 1953",
      "C. 1923",
      "D. 1933"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During World War II, the Steelers merged with these two other teams because of a shortage of war time players.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cardinals and Eagles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cardinals and Giants",
      "B. Browns and Cardinals",
      "C. Cardinals and Eagles",
      "D. Giants and Eagles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Steelers lost their first playoff game against this team in 1947.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Philadelphia Eagles",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis Cardinals",
      "B. Cleveland Browns.",
      "C. Philadelphia Eagles",
      "D. New York Giants"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This man was the head coach of the Pittsburgh Steelers from 1969 through 1991.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Noll",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Nocks",
      "B. Chuck Noll",
      "C. Chuck Knoll",
      "D. Chuck Knoks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, drafted by The Steelers in 1969, is widely known for being mean and a for Coke commercial with a little kid.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Green",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cy Young",
      "B. Dick Night Train Lane",
      "C. Lynn Swan",
      "D. Joe Green"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Hall of Fame Quarterback led the Steelers to 4 Super Bowl victories in the 1970s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Terry Bradshaw",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Thorpe",
      "B. John Macenroe",
      "C. Terry Bradshaw",
      "D. Joe Montana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became head coach of the Steelers in 1992?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Cowher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Green",
      "B. Tom Landry",
      "C. Joe Montana",
      "D. Bill Cowher"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Steelers lost their bid for a fifth Championship in Super Bowl XXX to this team in January 1996.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Cowboys",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Francisco 49ers",
      "B. Philadelphia Eagles",
      "C. San Diego Chargers",
      "D. Dallas Cowboys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Steelers finally won their 5th Championship in Super Bowl XL against the Seattle Seahawks in this year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2006",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2004",
      "B. 2006",
      "C. 2003",
      "D. 2005"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Steelers began playing at this Stadium in the 2001 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Heinz Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Heinz Field",
      "B. Three Rivers Stadium",
      "C. Texas Stadium",
      "D. Forbes Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To win the pitching Triple Crown, a pitcher must lead his league in these categories.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wins, ERA, strikeouts",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wins or saves, ERA, strikeouts",
      "B. Wins, ERA, Saves",
      "C. Win-loss percentage, saves, strikeouts",
      "D. Wins, ERA, strikeouts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tommy Bond was the first pitcher to qualify as a Triple Crown winner, but this great pitcher was the first to win it in the 20th century.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cy Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson",
      "B. Christy Mathewson",
      "C. Cy Young",
      "D. Tim Keefe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1930s two American League pitchers won the Triple Crown twice each. They both had the same nickname. What were their last names?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Grove and Gomez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vance and Dean",
      "B. Grove and Gomez",
      "C. Dean and Gomez",
      "D. Gomez and Addams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This left-handed pitcher, who was also a basketball player, won the National  League Triple Crown for the Dodgers in 1963, 1965, and 1966.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sandy Koufax",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Drysdale",
      "B. Lou Alcindor",
      "C. Juan Marichal",
      "D. Sandy Koufax"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was  the first pitcher to earn the Triple Crown four times?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Grover Cleveland Alexander",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hippo Vaughan",
      "B. Grover Cleveland Alexander",
      "C. Cy Young",
      "D. Ed Cicotte"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He won the Triple Crown in 2006 and was traded after the next season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johan Santana",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jake Peavy",
      "B. Roger Clemens",
      "C. Johan Santana",
      "D. John Clarkson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During modern baseball (i.e. since 1877) this is the first decade in which no pitcher could earn the Triple Crown.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1950s",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1950s",
      "B. 1880s",
      "C. 1940s",
      "D. 1890s"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the very first basketball game each team comprised of this many players.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "9",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the original name for basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Naismithball",
    "choices": [
      "A. YMCA-ball",
      "B. Courtball",
      "C. Roundball",
      "D. Naismithball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what state was the first college basketball game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Minnesota",
    "choices": [
      "A. Minnesota",
      "B. Massachusetts",
      "C. Maine",
      "D. Missouri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team was formed by Abe Saperstein?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harlem Globetrotters",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harlem Globetrotters",
      "B. New York Liberty",
      "C. Washington generals",
      "D. Boston Celtics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first college coach of a five-man basketball team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Amos Alonzo Stagg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duke Maas",
      "B. Joe Fulks",
      "C. Adolph Rupp",
      "D. Amos Alonzo Stagg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Philadelphia Warriors became the first NBA champions in this year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1947",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1943",
      "B. 1947",
      "C. 1939",
      "D. 1950"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Glory Road is a movie about the first NCAA basketball team with an all African-American starting lineup. Which university is the movie about?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Texas Western",
    "choices": [
      "A. Western Kentucky",
      "B. Rutgers University",
      "C. Kansas",
      "D. Texas Western"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who scored the first basket in the NBA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ozzie Schectman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chris Ford",
      "B. Ozzie Schectman",
      "C. Maurice Stokes",
      "D. Amos Alonzo Stagg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is given credit for taking the first jump shot in college basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ken Sailors",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Fulks",
      "B. Ken Sailors",
      "C. Maurice Stokes",
      "D. Terry Joe Barker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NBA player to score 60 points in a game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Fulks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "B. Joe Fulks",
      "C. Frank Selvy",
      "D. Joe Marasovich"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This movie tells the story of a woman who becomes the coach of the New York Knicks.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eddie",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie",
      "B. White Men Cant Jump",
      "C. Drive , She Said",
      "D. Rebound"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the first televised basketball game air?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1940",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1944",
      "B. 1956",
      "C. 1948",
      "D. 1940"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great NBA guard played from 1958â1967 for the Boston Celtics. For many years he was the best defensive guard in the NBA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "K.C. Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Havlichek",
      "B. Mike Farmer",
      "C. K.C. Jones",
      "D. Sam Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what state was the first womens college basketball game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "California",
    "choices": [
      "A. California",
      "B. New York",
      "C. Missouri",
      "D. Massachusetts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the true statement about Lisa Leslie.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She was the first woman to dunk a basketball in the WNBA.",
    "choices": [
      "A. She was the first leading scorer in the WNBA.",
      "B. She was the first woman to play in the NBA.",
      "C. She was the first woman to dunk a basketball in the WNBA.",
      "D. She was the first woman to score 60 points in a WNBA game."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first college to win the NCAA championship in basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oregon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ohio State",
      "B. Kansas",
      "C. Oregon",
      "D. Kentucky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first college to win both the NCAA championship and the National Invitation Tournament in the same year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "City College of New York",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Francisco City College",
      "B. University of Kentucky",
      "C. City College of New York",
      "D. San Francisco University"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players has won a Heisman Trophy in 1973 while in the Pennsylvania State University?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Cappelletti",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Robinson",
      "B. Ki-Jana Carter",
      "C. John Cappelletti",
      "D. Tony Hunt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1992, 1984, and 2005, who was Penn State Nittany Lions football teams head coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Paterno",
    "choices": [
      "A. Galen Hall",
      "B. Rip Engle",
      "C. Tim Curley",
      "D. Joe Paterno"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What conference is the Penn State Nittany Lions football team in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Big Ten",
    "choices": [
      "A. SEC",
      "B. Big East",
      "C. Pac-10",
      "D. Big Ten"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "By which team was former Penn State Nittany Lions player Michael Robinson chosen in the NFL Draft in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Francisco 49ers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pittsburgh Steelers",
      "B. San Francisco 49ers",
      "C. Seattle Seahawks",
      "D. Oakland raiders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In1986 the Penn State Nittany Lions football team won their which National Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Second",
    "choices": [
      "A. Second",
      "B. Third",
      "C. First",
      "D. Fifth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Penn State Nittany Lions football teams annual scrimmage game called?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Blue and White Game",
    "choices": [
      "A. Blue and White Game",
      "B. Lions vs. Lions Game",
      "C. Scrimmage At the Beaver",
      "D. Useless Pre-Season Game that is Fun to Go to"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the score of Penn State Nittany Lions in the first game of the 2008-2009 season vs. Coastal Carolina?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "66-10, Penn State won",
    "choices": [
      "A. 55-14, Penn State won",
      "B. 24-21, Penn State lost",
      "C. 66-10, Penn State won",
      "D. 66-17, Penn State lost"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Michael Fred Phelps born and raised?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Baltimore, Md",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bethesda, Md",
      "B. Baltimore, Md",
      "C. Washington D.C.",
      "D. Silver Spring, Md"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Michael Phelps attend college?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Michigan in Ann Arbor",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ohio State",
      "B. Georgetown University",
      "C. University of Michigan in Ann Arbor",
      "D. Iowa State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2004 Athens Summer Olympic Games, how many gold and bronze medals did Michael Phelps win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6 gold, 2 bronze",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5 gold, 3 bronze",
      "B. 6 gold, 1 bronze",
      "C. 6 gold, 2 bronze",
      "D. 5 gold, 2 bronze"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2004 Olympic Games, Michael Phelps set a number of world records, Olympic records, and American records. How many of each did he set?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2 WR, 3 OR, and 2 AR",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4 WR, 1 OR, and 2 AR",
      "B. 1 WR, 4 OR, and 2 AR",
      "C. 3 WR, 2 OR, and 2 AR",
      "D. 2 WR, 3 OR, and 2 AR"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2008 Olympic Games, Michael Phelps swam in 8 events. How many world records did Phelps and/or his team set?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "7",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 8",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 100 m butterfly at  the 2008 Olympic Games, Michael Phelps beat Milorad ÄaviÄ by this much.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1/100th of a second",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2/10ths of a second",
      "B. 1/10th of a second",
      "C. 2/100ths of a second",
      "D. 1/100th of a second"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A street in Michael Phelps hometown was renamed this to honor him.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Phelps Way",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Phelps Way",
      "B. Michael Phelps Drive",
      "C. Phelps Street",
      "D. Phelps Drive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The  sport of noodling has become very popular in the USA. What does it involve?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Catching catfish barehanded",
    "choices": [
      "A. Catching catfish barehanded",
      "B. Pushing an enormous plastic ball into your opponents goal",
      "C. Outdoor bowling on ice",
      "D. A form of mixed martial arts with no rules"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Eddie Feigner, Cat Osterman, and Lisa Fernandez became well known for practicing this sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Softball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Canopying",
      "B. Billiards",
      "C. Golf",
      "D. Softball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the  people on the first cover of Sports Illustrated?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eddie Mathews, Wes Westrum and Augie Donatelli",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Mathews, Wes Westrum and Augie Donatelli",
      "B. Ben Hogan, Bobby Jones, and Sam Snead",
      "C. Ted Williams and Joe DiMaggiio",
      "D. President Dwight David Eisenhower and his caddy, Mitch MacKenzie"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first NFL team to have an insignia put on its helmets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bears",
      "B. Redskins",
      "C. Rams",
      "D. Eagles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NFL Super Bowl MVP who was not born in the USA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark Rypien",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kurt Warner",
      "B. Len Dawson",
      "C. Mark Rypien",
      "D. Fred Biletnikoff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement regarding the 1959 season is false?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Robinson was the American League manager.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Robinson was the American League manager.",
      "B. Orlando Cepeda and Stan Musial were the starting All-Star first basemen.",
      "C. The American League lost the All-Star Game on July 7 5 to 4.",
      "D. The National League lost the All Star Game on August 3  5 to 3."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first switch hitter in the Baseball Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frankie Frisch",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mickey Mantle",
      "B. Eddie Murray",
      "C. Rogers Hornsby",
      "D. Frankie Frisch"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Stella Walsh was a Polish-born athlete residing in Cleveland, Ohio. She won an Olympic gold medal in  the 1932 Olympic (100 meters) and a silver medal in the 1936 Olympics (100 meters). Which statement is untrue about Stella Walsh?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She had female genitalia",
    "choices": [
      "A. She had female genitalia",
      "B. She had male genitalia",
      "C. She had XY-chromosomes",
      "D. She had XX-chromosomes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who built the tennis court that is in the Hampton Court in England?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "King Henry VIII",
    "choices": [
      "A. Winston Churchill",
      "B. Christopher Wren",
      "C. Ben Franklin",
      "D. King Henry VIII"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the incorrect statement about sportsman Yuichiro Miura.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was the first seventy-year old person to climb Mount Fuji.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was the first seventy-year old person to climb Mount Fuji.",
      "B. He skied Mount Everest.",
      "C. He climbed Mount Everest at the age of 75 years 7 months.",
      "D. He was the first seventy-year old person to climb Mount Everest."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jerome Holtzman was a sports journalist of some repute. Which statement is true about him?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He invented the statistic Saves by a relief pitcher.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He and Bill James wrote many books using statistics to evaluate players.",
      "B. He was the writer who wrote the original expose on steroids in baseball.",
      "C. He was President of the Baseball Hall of Fame from 1999 to his death in 2008.",
      "D. He invented the statistic Saves by a relief pitcher."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first person to hold the worlds record for running 50 yards, 75 yards and 100 yards backwards.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Robinson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Hayes",
      "B. Jim Thorpe",
      "C. Bill Robinson",
      "D. R.P. Williams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before the Bobcats, what NBA team played in Charlotte?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Orleans Hornets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miami Heat",
      "B. Dallas Mavericks",
      "C. New York Knicks",
      "D. New Orleans Hornets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "With the 2nd overall pick in the 2004 NBA draft, the Charlotte Bobcats selected what former UConn player?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Emeka Okafor",
    "choices": [
      "A. Emeka Okafor",
      "B. Jahidi White",
      "C. Bernard Robinson",
      "D. Dwight Howard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Charlotte Bobcats first head coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bernie Bickerstaff",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dan Scwartzer",
      "B. Lou Hollins",
      "C. Bernie Bickerstaff",
      "D. Michael Jordan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the Charlotte Bobcats record for their very 1st season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "18-64",
    "choices": [
      "A. 18-64",
      "B. 25-57",
      "C. 23-59",
      "D. 14-68"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When the Charlotte Bobcats first came into the NBA, how many NBA players did they pick to be on the inaugural roster in their expansion draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "19",
    "choices": [
      "A. 17",
      "B. 19",
      "C. 21",
      "D. 15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Charlotte Bobcats lost their very first regular season game to what team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington Wizards",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington Wizards",
      "B. Detroit Pistons",
      "C. Atlanta Hawks",
      "D. Miami Heat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the last Negro League baseball player to play in the major leagues.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Newcombe",
      "B. Willie Mays",
      "C. Hank Aaron",
      "D. Vic Power"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Select the one who does not  fit.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brian Leetch (NHL)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lance Allred (NBA)",
      "B. Bonnie Sloan (NFL)",
      "C. Brian Leetch (NHL)",
      "D. William E. Hoy (MLB)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1952 Pete and Jerry Cusimano did this at a hockey game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They threw an octopus on the ice at an NHL game.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were the first fans to jump onto the ice to protest a penalty on their team.",
      "B. They were the first to place plexiglass to separate the fans from the players and ice rink.",
      "C. They were the first to throw their hats onto the ice when a player scored three goals in one game.",
      "D. They threw an octopus on the ice at an NHL game."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first indoor NCAA Football Bowl game played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1964",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1939",
      "B. 1964",
      "C. 1955",
      "D. 1976"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the national sport of Bangladesh?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kabaddi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rugby",
      "B. Kabaddi",
      "C. Kho Kho",
      "D. Field Hockey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sport is most unlike the others?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Klootschieten",
    "choices": [
      "A. Varpa",
      "B. Bocce",
      "C. Klootschieten",
      "D. Boules"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally accepted that polo was first played in this part of the world.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Northeastern India",
    "choices": [
      "A. Berkshire, England",
      "B. Northeastern India",
      "C. Mongolia",
      "D. Central Peru"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Zorbing is a sport that was developed in the 1990s. What is a zorb?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A large, clear plastic ball",
    "choices": [
      "A. A ten-foot wall on which large amounts of velcro are mounted",
      "B. A tandem skydiving rig which can be easily undone",
      "C. A large, clear plastic ball",
      "D. A long, plastic sheet that has very little friction when wet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Vale-tudo has become a very popular international sport. What other term refers to this sport?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mixed martial arts",
    "choices": [
      "A. Snowboarding",
      "B. Golf",
      "C. Surfing",
      "D. Mixed martial arts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Six brothers from one family played during the NHL 1982-1983 season. What was the familys last name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sutter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Howe",
      "B. Sutter",
      "C. Lemieux",
      "D. Hall"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This was the first U.S. college to win the NCAA basketball championship in both the mens and womens divisions in the same season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Connecticut",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rutgers",
      "B. Tennessee",
      "C. Connecticut",
      "D. North Carolina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jim Brown was a great back for the Cleveland Browns. Jay Silverheels was a movie actor. What do they have in common?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They are in the same Hall of Fame.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They are in the same Hall of Fame.",
      "B. They were both in the movie The Dirty Dozen.",
      "C. They were bornon the same date.",
      "D. They were both in the  movie The Longest day."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This was basketball player Kareem Abdul-Jabbarâs name at birth.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ferdinand Lewis Alcondor, Jr.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ferdinand Lewis Alcondor, Jr.",
      "B. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "C. Dennis Kucinich",
      "D. Robert Earl  Moore"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first World Series Most Valuable Player.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Podres",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Larsen",
      "B. Johnny Podres",
      "C. Sandy  Amoros",
      "D. Yogi Berra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This is the nickname of the first NBA players to play in over 1610 games.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Chief",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Stilt",
      "B. Air Jordan",
      "C. Ice Man",
      "D. The Chief"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After the Washington Redskins drafted Ernie Davis, Art Modell of the Browns traded this player for him.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Mitchell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Mitchell",
      "B. Marion Motley",
      "C. leroy kelly",
      "D. Jim Kelly"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob Gibson was a great pitcher for the St. Louis Cardinals. What was his real first name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pack",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pack",
      "B. Omaha",
      "C. Bob",
      "D. Earl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which sportsmans nickname was The Bayonne Bleeder?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Wepner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Wepner",
      "B. Ray Mancini",
      "C. Gerry Cooney",
      "D. Archie Moore"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "William G. Morgan, Flo Hyman, Dimitar Zlatanov, Bernie Holtzman, and Karch Kiraly are in a Hall of Fame in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mt. Holyoke, Massachusetts",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mexico City",
      "B. Mt. Holyoke, Massachusetts",
      "C. Charleston, South Carolina",
      "D. Moscow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the director of first martial arts movie to win an Oscar?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ang Lee",
    "choices": [
      "A. Koki  Mitani",
      "B. Zho Yeng",
      "C. Akira Kurosawa",
      "D. Ang Lee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the last name of the great shortstop whose nickname was Little Louie?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Aparicio",
    "choices": [
      "A. Appling",
      "B. Aparicio",
      "C. Brock",
      "D. Banks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The nickname of this hockey great was The pocket rocket.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Henri Richard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Louis Richard",
      "B. Henri Richard",
      "C. Maurice  Richard",
      "D. Jean Richard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This sports great was called The Wizard of Dribble and The Magician.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stan Matthews",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marcus Haynes",
      "B. Bob Cousy",
      "C. Curly Neal",
      "D. Stan Matthews"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the location of the International Table Tennis Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Switzerland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Taiwan",
      "B. Norway",
      "C. China",
      "D. Switzerland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first U.S. college to win back-to-back NCAA basketball championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oklahoma AM",
    "choices": [
      "A. North Carolina",
      "B. Oklahoma AM",
      "C. UCLA",
      "D. Duke"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the period 1984-1989, how many times did the Edmonton OIlers win the NHL championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 0",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Georgi Asparuhov, Magdalena Maleeva, Dan Kolov and Tanya Bogomilova are all great athletes from this nation.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bulgaria",
    "choices": [
      "A. Romania",
      "B. Serbia",
      "C. Hungary",
      "D. Bulgaria"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe Tinker (shortstop), John Evers (second baseman), and Frank Chance (first baseman) were the two from the famous double play combination for the Cubs. Who was the third baseman?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harry Steinfeldt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Santo",
      "B. Rogers Hornsby",
      "C. Harry Steinfeldt",
      "D. Hack Wilson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the first two numbers officially retired by the Toronto Maple Leafs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5  6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6  27",
      "B. 6  9",
      "C. 6  99",
      "D. 5  6"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Harford Whaler and Carolina Hurricane had his number retired on January 28, 2006. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Francis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Francis",
      "B. Mario Lemieux",
      "C. Steve Yzerman",
      "D. Chris Pronger"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you ever get drafted by the Detroit Red Wings and you want to wear #19 you are out of luck. # 19 was retired to honor this former Red Wings captain on January 2, 2007.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Yzerman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ted Lindsay",
      "B. Chris Chelios",
      "C. Gordie Howe",
      "D. Steve Yzerman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first number retired by the Montreal Canadiens on November 2, 1932 belonged to Howie Morenz. What number did he wear?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "7",
    "choices": [
      "A. 9",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 7"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Canadian political figure had his #29 retired by the Montreal Canadiens on January 29, 2007.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ken Dryden",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brian Mulroney",
      "B. Guy Lafleur",
      "C. Ken Dryden",
      "D. Steven Harper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had the longest hitting streak until 1941?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie Keeler",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Sisler",
      "B. Ty Cobb",
      "C. Willie Keeler",
      "D. Pete Rose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a line in Lou Gehrigs famous farewell speach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "But today I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the Earth.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Today I am the luckiest man on Earth.",
      "B. I consider myself the luckiest man in the whole world.",
      "C. Today I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the Earth.",
      "D. But today I consider myself the luckiest man on the face of the Earth."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many pitchers threw perfect games in the 20th century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 8",
      "C. 14",
      "D. 15"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the home run record until 1879?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Jack Quinn when he hit a home run on June 27, 1932?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "49 years 357 days",
    "choices": [
      "A. 49 years 357 days",
      "B. 47 years 322 days",
      "C. 42 years 12 days",
      "D. 48 years 214 days"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Derek Jeter was selected by the Yankees 6th overall in the 1992 draft. The first pick went to the Houston Astros, but they drafted this player instead.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phil Nevin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johnny Damon",
      "B. Paul Shuey",
      "C. Brad Lidge",
      "D. Phil Nevin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Colorado Rockies star left fielder Matt Holiday earned All-American honors in two sports during his senior year of high school. What were these sports?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Baseball and football",
    "choices": [
      "A. Baseball and basketball",
      "B. Football and basketball",
      "C. Baseball and hockey",
      "D. Baseball and football"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On what day was baseball commissioner Bud Selig born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "July 30, 1934",
    "choices": [
      "A. July 30, 1934",
      "B. May 22, 1935",
      "C. June 2, 1933",
      "D. December 16, 1932"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John Patrick McEnroe was born on February the 16th 1959 in which European country ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "West Germany",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. East Germany",
      "C. Italy",
      "D. West Germany"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did a young John McEnroe first qualify and amazingly reach the semi finals at Wimbledon ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1977",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1977",
      "B. 1975",
      "C. 1976",
      "D. 1978"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During his first participation in Wimbledon, McEnroe was defeated in the semi finals by this player.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmy Connors",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Connors",
      "B. Bjorn Borg",
      "C. Arthur Ashe",
      "D. Vitas Gerulatis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which year and what grand slam did John McEnroe first claim ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1979, US Open",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1980, Wimbledon",
      "B. 1979, Australian Open",
      "C. 1979, US Open",
      "D. 1978, US Open"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1983 John McEnroe won Wimbledon for the 2nd time. Who was McEnroes opponent on that occasion ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Lewis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pat Cash",
      "B. Chris Lewis",
      "C. Chris Curren",
      "D. Jimmy Connors"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1978 John McEnroe won both singles rubbers in the Davis Cup final to help the U.S.A cleam the Davis Cup for the 1st time since 1972.  Which country did the U.S.A defeat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "United Kingdom",
    "choices": [
      "A. Argentina",
      "B. West Germany",
      "C. Australia",
      "D. United Kingdom"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what month and year did John McEnroe become the worlds number 1 player according to the association of tennis professionals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "March 1980",
    "choices": [
      "A. February 1979",
      "B. March 1982",
      "C. February 1981",
      "D. March 1980"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All good things must come to an end; which title and what year did John McEnroe win his last grand slam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "US Open, 1984",
    "choices": [
      "A. US Open, 1984",
      "B. US Open, 1985",
      "C. Wimbledon, 1985",
      "D. Australian Open, 1986"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the highest score in the UEFA Champions League history from 1991/1992 until 2006/2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Liverpool - Besiktas 8:0",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ajax Amsterdam - FA Red Boys Differdange 14:0",
      "B. Arsenal - Slavia Prague 7:0",
      "C. Liverpool - Besiktas 8:0",
      "D. Dinamo Bucharest - Crusaders 11-0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which club has won most UEFA Champions League competitions between 1991/1992 and 2006/2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "AC Milan and Real Madrid, 3 times each",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barcelona, 3 times",
      "B. Liverpool, 4 times",
      "C. Real Madrid, 4 times",
      "D. AC Milan and Real Madrid, 3 times each"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams won the UEFA Champions League trophy after trailing 0:3 at half-time during the final match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Liverpool",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bayern Munich",
      "B. Liverpool",
      "C. AC Milan",
      "D. Real Madrid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these countries was never represented in the UEFA Champions League from 1991 to 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ireland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bulgaria",
      "B. Finland",
      "C. Ireland",
      "D. Poland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams played in the 2006 edition of the UEFA Champions League?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "32",
    "choices": [
      "A. 24",
      "B. 16",
      "C. 48",
      "D. 32"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why finishing third in the group stage is important in the UEFA Champions League?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The third team of each group goes to UEFA Cup.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The third team of each group goes to UEFA Cup.",
      "B. The team only gains prestige.",
      "C. One of the 8 teams that finished third can play in play-offs.",
      "D. It guarantees qualification to the following season competition."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum number of teams from one country that can participate in the UEFA Champions League?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. There is no limit.",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following teams did not win the UEFA Champions League in the period 1991/1992-2006/2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Valencia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Valencia",
      "B. FC Porto",
      "C. Olimpique Marseilles",
      "D. Borussia Dortmund"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which UEFA member cannot have a team in the Champions League?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Liechtenstein",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Marino",
      "B. Bosnia and Herzegovina",
      "C. Andorra",
      "D. Liechtenstein"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If the final match in the UEFA Champions League ends in a tie, how is the winner decided?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Extra time is played and if the winner is not decided, penalties are held.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Extra time is played and if the winner is not decided, penalties are held.",
      "B. Penalties shootout",
      "C. By drawing",
      "D. Extra time with a golden goal (the first team to score is the winner)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "WWE superstar Edge is the former brother-in-law of this wrestler.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Val Venus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Christian",
      "B. Hardcore Holly",
      "C. Brian Kendrick",
      "D. Val Venus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This wrestlers father is a former National Hockey League forward.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Jericho",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rick Martel",
      "B. Chris Jericho",
      "C. Edge",
      "D. Christian"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After graduating college and before becoming a pro wrestler he worked as a junior high school substitute teacher.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mick Foley",
      "B. Kane",
      "C. Arn Anderson",
      "D. Matt Striker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This wrestler played minor youth hockey with and against an NHL tough guy.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edge",
    "choices": [
      "A. Christian",
      "B. John Cena",
      "C. Edge",
      "D. Chris Jericho"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This well known tag team wrestlers son was drafted by the St. Louis Rams in the 2nd Round as the 35th overall pick in the 2009 NFL draft.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Road Warrior Animal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Demolitions Smash",
      "B. Harlem Heats Stevie Ray",
      "C. Jim The Anvil Neidhart",
      "D. Road Warrior Animal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This old time wrestler was a football coach at Madison High School in Madison Heights, MI where he would eventually become a member of the Michigan Coaches Hall of Fame.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George The Animal Steele",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Garea",
      "B. Dean Malenko",
      "C. George The Animal Steele",
      "D. Bob Backlund"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This pro wrestler signed with the Los Angeles Raiders of the NFL but was released before the season began.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Bradshaw Layfield",
    "choices": [
      "A. Batista",
      "B. The Big Show",
      "C. John Bradshaw Layfield",
      "D. Bill Goldberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Prior to becoming a pro wrestler this man played for various professional European basketball teams. When his career ended due to injury he enlisted in the 202nd Military Police Company in Germany and served in a NATO facility for two years.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kevin Nash",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kevin Nash",
      "B. Davey Boy Smith",
      "C. Barry Windham",
      "D. William Regal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former pro wrestler made news headlines in 2004 for causing an anthrax scare at Bostons Downtown Crossing MBTA station.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brutus The Barber Beefcake",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Patera",
      "B. Macho Man Randy Savage",
      "C. Brutus The Barber Beefcake",
      "D. Jake The Snake Roberts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This pro wrestler was a member of The Cherokee County School District but was disqualified from entering the primary for the 2006 term due to the fact that he did not use his legal name.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rick Steiner",
    "choices": [
      "A. Diamond Dallas Page",
      "B. Charlie Haas",
      "C. Rick Steiner",
      "D. Bubba Ray Dudley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What former football player co-starred in the 80s TV series Webster?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alex Karras",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lyle Alzado",
      "B. Mike Golic",
      "C. Jack Youngblood",
      "D. Alex Karras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of NFL Hall of Famer Reggie White?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Minister of Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Preacher of Pressure",
      "B. The Reverend of Defense",
      "C. The Minister of Defense",
      "D. The Pastor of Pressure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What college did Nick Buoniconti attend?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Notre Dame",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rutgers",
      "B. Notre Dame",
      "C. Michigan",
      "D. Penn State"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many NFL teams did Pete Carroll coach for prior to coaching at USC?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Mean Joe Greenes Coke commercial first air on TV?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "October 1979",
    "choices": [
      "A. September 1979",
      "B. October 1980",
      "C. October 1979",
      "D. September 1980"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the date for the first induction class into the Pro Football Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "September 7, 1963",
    "choices": [
      "A. October 9, 1961",
      "B. July 15, 1962",
      "C. August 30, 1964",
      "D. September 7, 1963"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Greenbay Packers first round draft pick in 1961?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Herb Adderly",
    "choices": [
      "A. Herb Adderly",
      "B. Paul Dudley",
      "C. Phil Nugent",
      "D. Ron Kostelnik"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Yogi Berra born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "St. Louis, Missouri",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montclair, New Jersey",
      "B. Brooklyn, New York",
      "C. Milan, Italy",
      "D. St. Louis, Missouri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two famous baseball personalities grew up on the same street as Yogi Berra?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Garagiola and Joe Buck",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Garagiola and Phil Rizzuto",
      "B. Phil Rizzuto and Pete Gray",
      "C. Joe Garagiola and Joe Buck",
      "D. Joe Buck and Pete Gray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Lawrence Peter Berra get the nickname Yogi?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He looked like a  character in a movie.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It is short for an affectionate Italian expression.",
      "B. It was the name of a popular cartoon character.",
      "C. He licked yogurt.",
      "D. He looked like a  character in a movie."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1942 Yogi Berra was not signed by the team he wanted to play for. Which team was his first choice?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The St. Louis Cardinals",
    "choices": [
      "A. The New York Yankees",
      "B. The St. Louis Cardinals",
      "C. The New York Mets",
      "D. The Brooklyn Dodgers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When Yogi Berra first joined the Yankees, they already had a great catcher. Who was he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Dickey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gus Triandos",
      "B. Sherm Lollar",
      "C. Bill Dickey",
      "D. Roy Campanella"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1972 the Yankees retired Yogi Berras uniform number. What was the number?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 32",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about Yogi Berras military service?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi served in the US Navy.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yogi never served in the military.",
      "B. Yogi served in the US Navy.",
      "C. Yogi served in the Us Air Force.",
      "D. Yogi served in the US Army."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The great manager Paul Richards once said that Yogi Berra was the best bad pitch hitter. What was Yogis response?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "If I can hit it, its a good pitch.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They just dont throw it good-I hit it good.",
      "B. They dont call it good, but its a good pitch.",
      "C. If its a bad pitch, why did they throw it?",
      "D. If I can hit it, its a good pitch."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After Elston Howard took over most of the catching duties with the Yankees, what position did Yogi Berra learn to play?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leftfield",
    "choices": [
      "A. Centerfield",
      "B. Secondbase",
      "C. Leftfield",
      "D. Shortstop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1956 World Series  against the Brooklyn Dodgers, Yogi Berra caught a very special game. What is untrue about the game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yogi hit a grand slam in the second  inning.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Yogi hit a grand slam in the second  inning.",
      "B. Sal Maglie pitched for the Dodgers.",
      "C. Don Larson pitched for the Yankees.",
      "D. There is a famous photo of Yogi jumping into the arms of the Yankee pitcher."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When Yogi Berra was the Yankee manager, there was a famous incident on a bus that made headlines. What was involved?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "a harmonica",
    "choices": [
      "A. a Playboy Magazine",
      "B. a pea shooter",
      "C. a harmonica",
      "D. a straw hat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1972 Yogi Berra became manager of  this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The New York Mets",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Washington Senators",
      "B. The Los Angeles Dodgers",
      "C. The New York Mets",
      "D. The Pittsburgh Pirates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which organization gave Yogi Berra the Silver Buffalo Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Boy Scouts of America",
    "choices": [
      "A. The American Legion",
      "B. The Elks Club",
      "C. The Boy Scouts of America",
      "D. The Daughters of  the American Revolution"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Yogi Berra is famous for his Yogisms. Which of the following is NOT a Yogi quote?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Man this is a long game... were two hours into the sixth inning.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Its tough making predictions especially about the future.",
      "B. Ninety percent of this game is half mental.",
      "C. When you come to a  fork in the road , take it.",
      "D. Man this is a long game... were two hours into the sixth inning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Olympic great was one of Robert F. Kennedys personal bodyguards.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rafer Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rosey Grier",
      "B. Al Oerter",
      "C. Ray Ewry",
      "D. Rafer Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Coroebus?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The first winner of an Olympic event in 776 b.c.e.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Greek god of sports and the Olympic Games",
      "B. The man who invented the Olympic Games in 776 b.c.e.",
      "C. The first winner of an Olympic event in 776 b.c.e.",
      "D. The man who raced from Marathon to Athens."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first male athlete to win the decathlon and pentathlon at Olympics Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Thorpe",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rafer Johnson",
      "B. Jim Thorpe",
      "C. Michael Johnson",
      "D. Ray Ewry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first man to win gold medals in three straight Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ray Ewry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ray Ewry",
      "B. Jim Thorpe",
      "C. Rafer Johnson",
      "D. Michael Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Olympian to win gold in the same event in four straight Olympics.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Al Oerter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Johnson",
      "B. Jim Thorpe",
      "C. Rafer Johnson",
      "D. Al Oerter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the first event in the first modern Olympics in 1896?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "James  B. Connolly",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rafer Johnson",
      "B. Pierre de Coubertin",
      "C. James  B. Connolly",
      "D. Jim Thorpe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Eddie Eagan?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The first person to win gold in the Winter Olympic Games and in the Summer Olympic Games",
    "choices": [
      "A. The first President of the International Olympic Committee",
      "B. The first person to win gold in the Winter Olympic Games and in the Summer Olympic Games",
      "C. Eddie The Eagle was a British skier who won a silver medal at the 1984 Olympic Games.",
      "D. The first American to win an Olympic medal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tommie Smith won the 200-meter dash in the 1968 Olympics. In that same year, John Carlos came in third in that event. Why were Carlos and Smith banned from the Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They made a political gesture on the medal stage.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They refused to accept the medals.",
      "B. They tested positive for steroids.",
      "C. They refused to take a blood  test.",
      "D. They made a political gesture on the medal stage."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Herman Blix, John Weissmuller, Clarence Crabbe, and Glenn Morris were all Americans who won Olympic medals. What else did they have in common?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They all became actors and played the same part in different movies.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were all given special medals by President Herbert Hoover.",
      "B. They all had their pictures on Wheaties boxes.",
      "C. They all died in abject poverty.",
      "D. They all became actors and played the same part in different movies."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first year Olympians marched into the stadium behind their countrys flag?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1908-London",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1900-Paris",
      "B. 1944-Chicago",
      "C. 1936-Berlin",
      "D. 1908-London"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Margret Abbott was the first female American to win an Olympic event. What was her event?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Golf",
    "choices": [
      "A. 100 meters",
      "B. Tennis",
      "C. Golf",
      "D. diving"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Complete, live color TV broadcasts of the Olympics were featured first in this Olympic year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1960",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1960",
      "B. 1956",
      "C. 1936",
      "D. 1968"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following was the first Olympic Games mascot?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "a cartoon character",
    "choices": [
      "A. a panda",
      "B. a cartoon character",
      "C. an eagle",
      "D. a kangaroo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first woman to run 100 meters in under 11 seconds in the Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Evelyn Ashford",
    "choices": [
      "A. Margaret Abbott",
      "B. Asaffa Powell",
      "C. Ingrid Swednersen",
      "D. Evelyn Ashford"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Olympian to run the 100 meters in under 10 seconds?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim Hines",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Johnson",
      "B. John Carlos",
      "C. Bob Hayes",
      "D. Jim Hines"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following occurred in the 1984 Winter Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Two brothers came in 1-2 in the Alpine Slalom.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The USA won no gold medals.",
      "B. American figure skaters came in 1-2.",
      "C. Two brothers came in 1-2 in the Alpine Slalom.",
      "D. Russia lead with 112 gold medals."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the length of a cricket pitch?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "22 yards",
    "choices": [
      "A. 22 yards",
      "B. 1/2 furlong",
      "C. 25 metres",
      "D. 100 feet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the maximum length of a modern day cricket test match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5 days",
    "choices": [
      "A. 150 minutes",
      "B. 1 week",
      "C. 6 hours",
      "D. 5 days"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many balls make up an over in a cricket match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. 12",
      "C. 6",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the abbreviation L.B.W stand for in cricket?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leg Before Wicket",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luck Beyond Wonder",
      "B. Leg Before Wicket",
      "C. Lost Behind Winner",
      "D. Last Ball Went"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What word refers to the match officials in a cricket match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Umpire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Referee",
      "B. Umpire",
      "C. Sir",
      "D. Line Judge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wickets must fall (barring retirement or injury) for a cricket team to be all out?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 11",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What slang term is applied to a batsmans score of 0 in cricket?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duck",
    "choices": [
      "A. Turkey",
      "B. Quail",
      "C. Goose",
      "D. Duck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many runs does a cricket batsman score by clearing the boundary of the playing field in a single hit?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the bi-annual Cricket Series played between England and Australia?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Ashes",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Ashes",
      "B. Churchill Trophy",
      "C. The Bradman Series",
      "D. Admirals Cup"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Brazilian team signed a contract with soccer legend Edson Arantes do Nascimento, PelÃ©, when he was just 15 years old?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Santos/SP",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sport/PE",
      "B. Santos/SP",
      "C. Santo Andre/SP",
      "D. Vasco/RJ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Brazilian team made a 10-year agreement in 2004 with the international fund of investors Media Sports Investment (MSI)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Corinthians/SP",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fortaleza/CE",
      "B. CFA/RO",
      "C. Ceara/CE",
      "D. Corinthians/SP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team had Manuel Francisco dos Santos, the legendary Garrincha, playing for them for 45 minutes in a game against the Fluminense/RJ in the 1960s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fortaleza/CE",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fortaleza/CE",
      "B. Mirassol/SP",
      "C. Princesa Solimoes/AM",
      "D. Botafogo/RJ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team of Brazil won the first Club World Championship organized by FIFA?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Corinthians/SP",
    "choices": [
      "A. Corinthians/SP",
      "B. Sao Paulo/SP",
      "C. Santos/SP",
      "D. Flamengo/RJ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2002, the team of Brazil became a FIFA World Cup winner beating the team of which country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Germany",
    "choices": [
      "A. Italy",
      "B. France",
      "C. Germany",
      "D. Sweden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the Brazilian Championship in 1978, beating Sao Paulo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Guarani/SP",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atletico/PR",
      "B. Guarani/SP",
      "C. Coritiba/PR",
      "D. Bahia/BA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player scored six goals at the 1997 match between Vasco/RJ and Uniao Joao de Araras, thus breaking the record for the most goals in a single game in the Brazilian Championship.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edmundo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dude",
      "B. Pele",
      "C. Edmundo",
      "D. Ronaldo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Brazilian football player is one of the most famous Vasco da Gama players and one of the best goal scorers in the history of Brazilian football, with a total of 744 goals in his professional career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roberto Dinamite",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pele",
      "B. Ronaldo",
      "C. Roberto Dinamite",
      "D. Edmundo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2004 Brazilian championship season, this player broke the record for most goals in a single season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington",
    "choices": [
      "A. Edmundo",
      "B. Pele",
      "C. Roberto Dinamite",
      "D. Washington"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of these Brazilian championships soccer legend PelÃ© never played in a team which finished first?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Campeonato Brasileiro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sao Paulo championship",
      "B. Internacional Costa Rica championship",
      "C. World Cup",
      "D. Campeonato Brasileiro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pitcher had the most  victories with the 1980 Philadelphia Phillies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Lefty Carlton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marty Bystrom",
      "B. Bob Walk",
      "C. Steve Lefty Carlton",
      "D. Ron Reed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Phillies player led the team in stolen bases in 1980?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lonnie Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Rose",
      "B. Lonnie Smith",
      "C. Larry Bowa",
      "D. Garry Maddox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the manager of the 1980 Philadelphia Phillies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Green",
    "choices": [
      "A. Danny Ozark",
      "B. Joe Altobelli",
      "C. Dallas Green",
      "D. Jim Fregosi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player is considered one of the greatest Philadelphia Phillies players of all time. He played third base for the world champion Phillies in 1980.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Schmidt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Schmidt",
      "B. Garry Maddox",
      "C. Pete Rose",
      "D. Richie Hebner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1979, she became the first person to swim from the Bahamas to Florida.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Diane Nyad",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michelle Yu",
      "B. Diane Nyad",
      "C. Tracy Caulkins",
      "D. Gertrude Ederle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Miklos Szabados, Cai Zhenhua, and Michael Maze are prominent players in this sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Table tennis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Slalom skiing",
      "B. Speed skating",
      "C. Table tennis",
      "D. Gymnastics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first player to score over 1000 goals in soccer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pele",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pele",
      "B. David Beckham",
      "C. Johann De Gruyff",
      "D. Rinaldo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was  he first man to win the tennis Grand Slam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Budge",
    "choices": [
      "A. Spencer W. Gore",
      "B. Rene Lacoste",
      "C. Rod Laver",
      "D. Don Budge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first National Hockey League team in the USA was from this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston",
      "B. Buffalo",
      "C. Detroit",
      "D. Fargo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the first organized soccer team formed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sheffield, England",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sheffield, England",
      "B. Madrid, Spain",
      "C. Milan, Italy",
      "D. Munich, Germany"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the Federation Internationale de Football Association formed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1904",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1934",
      "B. 1914",
      "C. 1924",
      "D. 1904"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1960s the Brunswick Sporting Goods Company made a Snurfer, water ski with a rope in the front. This toy led to the development of which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Snowboarding",
    "choices": [
      "A. Snowboarding",
      "B. Halfpipe skiing",
      "C. Skateboarding",
      "D. Inline Skating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1963 a sports contest was held in Hermosa, California. Why was it significant?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was the first skateboarding championship.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was the first baseball game between the Peoples Republic of China and the USA.",
      "B. It was the last time Miami of Ohio played Miami of Florida on TV.",
      "C. It was the first time the NFL played the AFL on television.",
      "D. It was the first skateboarding championship."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1874 Major Clopton Wingfield revolutionized this sport.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tennis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rugby",
      "B. Cricket",
      "C. Tennis",
      "D. Soccer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This sport, which evolved from the medieval sports of  caid and cnapean, is played with either 13 or 15 players. (There are two modern variants.)",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rugby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Soccer",
      "B. Croquet",
      "C. Curling",
      "D. Rugby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NHL player to score 50 goals in a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Richard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Esposito",
      "B. Richard",
      "C. Gretsky",
      "D. Howe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NHL player to score 100 points in a season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Esposito",
    "choices": [
      "A. Esposito",
      "B. Gretsky",
      "C. Richard",
      "D. Howe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Patty Berg was quite a fine golfer. She won the first US Womans Open in 1946. What significant accomplishment did she make in 1959?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She scored a hole-in-one.",
    "choices": [
      "A. She wore a very revealing outfit.",
      "B. She scored a hole-in-one.",
      "C. She won the event and the tennis Grand Slam.",
      "D. She won the event left-handed."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Find the incorrect statement about Tiger Woods.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He won four straight US Amateur titles.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He won four straight US Amateur titles.",
      "B. He has two half-brothers and one half-sister.",
      "C. He was the first 15 year-old to win the US Junior Amateur Championship.",
      "D. He was the youngest golfer to win all four majors in one year."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the first golfer to earn more than $100,000 in one year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arnold Palmer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Nickolas",
      "B. Sam Snead",
      "C. Arnold Palmer",
      "D. Tiger Woods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what state was the first American golf course opened?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vermont",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tennessee",
      "B. New York",
      "C. Vermont",
      "D. Georgia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1963 the National Football League suspended these two players for gambling.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Hornung and Alex Karras",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Hornung and Pete Rose",
      "B. Art Schlichter and Mike Lucci",
      "C. Paul Hornung and Mike Lucci",
      "D. Paul Hornung and Alex Karras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1886, Ab Smith added this term to sports vocabulary.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "birdie",
    "choices": [
      "A. hole-in-one",
      "B. birdie",
      "C. grand slam",
      "D. ace"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Fred Gehrke was a running back for the then Los Angeles Rams. Which of the following did he do in 1948?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Painted horns on his helmet",
    "choices": [
      "A. Scored a touchdown running, receiving and throwing.",
      "B. Ran 100 yards the wrong way",
      "C. Played all eleven positions in one game",
      "D. Painted horns on his helmet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team won the first college bowl game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michigan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Penn State",
      "B. Bucknell",
      "C. Tulane",
      "D. Michigan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former NFL player is given credit for the first spike in the NFL.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Homer Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Homer Jones",
      "B. Abner Haynes",
      "C. Paul Hornung",
      "D. Max McGee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team won the World Series in 1980?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Phillies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Phillies",
      "B. Royals",
      "C. Dodgers",
      "D. Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What pitcher pitched a no hitter on July 4th 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dave Righetti",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Sudakis",
      "B. John Tudor",
      "C. Bob Stanley",
      "D. Dave Righetti"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the manager of the 1986 New York Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Davey Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hal Lanier",
      "B. Davey Johnson",
      "C. Gene Mauch",
      "D. John McNamera"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the last shortstop to start for the Baltimore Orioles before Cal Ripken stepped in and played 2,632 consecutive games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Floyd Rayford",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jose Uribe",
      "B. Floyd Rayford",
      "C. Razor Shines",
      "D. Boots Day"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player collected his 3000th hit in 1985. Who was this California Angels player ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rod Carew",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rod Carew",
      "B. Reggie Jackson",
      "C. Bert Campaneris",
      "D. Don Baylor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two teams played in the 1989 World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "As vs. Giants",
    "choices": [
      "A. As vs. Dodgers",
      "B. Twins vs. Cardinals",
      "C. As vs. Giants",
      "D. As vs. Reds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the 1984 World Series MVP award ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alan Trammell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Howard Johnson",
      "B. Alan Trammell",
      "C. Willie Hernandez",
      "D. Kirk Gibson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This teenager was the Mets starting shortstop in 1983.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jose Oquendo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kelvin Chapman",
      "B. Wally Backman",
      "C. Jose Oquendo",
      "D. Ron Gardenhire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "I was the third baseman for the Yankees when Dave Righetti threw his no hitter in 1983. Who am I?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bert Campaneris",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fred Stanley",
      "B. Bert Campaneris",
      "C. Graig Nettles",
      "D. Mike Pagliarulo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although Kung Fu is often used in English as a collective term for Chinese martial arts, what is the more precise term for them?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wushu",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Soo",
      "B. Kendo",
      "C. Hung Fut",
      "D. Wushu"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term Kung Fu refer to, apart from Chinese martial arts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Individual accomplishment or skill",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sense of superiority",
      "B. Individual accomplishment or skill",
      "C. Physical strength",
      "D. Knowledge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is believed to have introduced martial arts in China?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Yellow Emperor",
    "choices": [
      "A. The First Emperor Qin Shi Huangdi",
      "B. Sima Qian",
      "C. Li Bai",
      "D. The Yellow Emperor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What style of Kung Fu is not a Southern one?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eagle Claw",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wing Chun",
      "B. Five Ancestors",
      "C. Eagle Claw",
      "D. Dragon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the meaning of the concept of Chi, that plays a crucial role in the basic training of a student in Kung Fu?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Breath",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stance",
      "B. Heart",
      "C. Body",
      "D. Breath"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In Chinese martial arts, the series of movements that are combined so they can be practiced as one set of movements are grouped in how many general types?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Two",
    "choices": [
      "A. Three",
      "B. Two",
      "C. Four",
      "D. Six"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a dao?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sword",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sword",
      "B. Stance",
      "C. Martial art",
      "D. Form"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Chinese literary genre is based on Chinese martial arts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wuxia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Baihua",
      "B. Shi",
      "C. BushidÅ",
      "D. Wuxia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the main character in the American series Kung Fu (1972-1975)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kwai Chang Caine",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Carradine",
      "B. Master Po",
      "C. Master Kan",
      "D. Kwai Chang Caine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Southern martial art did the Chinese American martial artist and actor Bruce Lee practise?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wing Chun",
    "choices": [
      "A. Leopard Kung Fu",
      "B. Black Tiger Kung Fu",
      "C. Duan Quan",
      "D. Wing Chun"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following refers to the mechanics that work on the go kart?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pit Crew",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pit Crew",
      "B. Timers",
      "C. Secret Agents",
      "D. Handy Men"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A go kart will go faster but handle worse, if you do which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Go up on the air pressure in the tires",
    "choices": [
      "A. Crash",
      "B. Go down on the air pressure in the tires",
      "C. Go up on the air pressure in the tires",
      "D. Cut a whole in the front of the go kart"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does WKA stand for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "World Karting Association",
    "choices": [
      "A. World Karting Association",
      "B. Witfield Karting Association",
      "C. World Kangaroo Association",
      "D. Willowbrook Kart Alignment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On what part of a kart  can you place a shield to improve aerodynamics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "steering column",
    "choices": [
      "A. wheels",
      "B. steering column",
      "C. bar",
      "D. motor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1975-76 season, Darryl Sittler set the NHL record for most points scored in one game when he recorded this many points against the Boston Bruins.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wayne Gretzky broke the record for most points in a season in 1985-86 by getting how many points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "215",
    "choices": [
      "A. 216",
      "B. 217",
      "C. 215",
      "D. 214"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wins did Patrick Roy have at the end of his 19-season career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "551",
    "choices": [
      "A. 548",
      "B. 550",
      "C. 549",
      "D. 551"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many points did the rookie Teemu Selanne get in the 1992-1993 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "132",
    "choices": [
      "A. 120",
      "B. 136",
      "C. 132",
      "D. 128"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many shutouts did Terry Sawchuk get in his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "103",
    "choices": [
      "A. 103",
      "B. 102",
      "C. 104",
      "D. 105"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country hosted the 2000 Summer Olympics, also known as the Games of the New Millennium, and officially called the Games of the XXVII Olympiad?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Australia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australia",
      "B. China",
      "C. Greece",
      "D. United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1896 Summer Olympics, or the Games of the I Olympiad, were hosted by this European country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Greece",
    "choices": [
      "A. Germany",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. Sweden",
      "D. France"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country hosted the 1992 Summer Olympic Games, officially called the Games of the XXV Olympiad?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Spain",
      "B. Brazil",
      "C. South Korea",
      "D. United Kingdom"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This country was the host of the 1932 Summer Olympics, or the Games of the X Olympiad.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The United States",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australia",
      "B. Belgium",
      "C. Japan",
      "D. The United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country hosted the 1948 Summer Olympics, officially known as the Games of the XIV Olympiad?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "United Kingdom",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil",
      "B. China",
      "C. United Kingdom",
      "D. United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1988 Summer Olympics, officially called Games of the XXIV Olympiad, were hosted by this Asian country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Korea",
    "choices": [
      "A. Japan",
      "B. India",
      "C. South Korea",
      "D. China"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What country was the host of the 1968 Summer Olympics, or Games of the XIX Olympiad?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mexico",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil",
      "B. Norway",
      "C. France",
      "D. Mexico"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This country hosted the 1924 Summer Olympics, officially known as the Games of the VIII Olympiad.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "France",
    "choices": [
      "A. Canada",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. France",
      "D. Japan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the 1928 Summer Olympics, or the Games of the IX Olympiad, take place?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Netherlands",
    "choices": [
      "A. Argentina",
      "B. The Netherlands",
      "C. South Korea",
      "D. Spain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1980 Summer Olympics, officially known as the Games of the XXII Olympiad, were held in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Soviet Union",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Soviet Union",
      "B. Australia",
      "C. Finland",
      "D. Italy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of these years did The Miami Hurricanes not win a national title in football?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1991",
      "B. 1987",
      "C. 1983",
      "D. 2000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What school did Miami lose to in the 1992 Sugar Bowl, halting their efforts of winning back-to-back national titles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Alabama",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Alabama",
      "B. Ohio State",
      "C. Oklahoma",
      "D. Nebraska"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these defensive players did not play linebacker for The  Miami Hurricanes?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Al Blades",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Barrow",
      "B. Al Blades",
      "C. Jonathan Vilma",
      "D. Dan Morgan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the fourth former Miami Hurricanes player to be inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Irvin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Kelly",
      "B. Ted Hendricks",
      "C. Jim Otto",
      "D. Michael Irvin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these coaches was the first one to win two national titles as head coach of The Miami Hurricanes?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis Erickson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Johnson",
      "B. Dennis Erickson",
      "C. Larry Coker",
      "D. Howard Schellenberger"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the MVP of the 1969 World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Clendenon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Koosman",
      "B. Don Clendenon",
      "C. Cleon Jones",
      "D. Al Weis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wins did Tom Seaver accumulate in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "25",
    "choices": [
      "A. 27",
      "B. 19",
      "C. 25",
      "D. 22"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pitcher was not on the Mets staff in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jon Matlack",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gery Gentry",
      "B. Jon Matlack",
      "C. Jerry Koosman",
      "D. Nolan Ryan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Mets starting third baseman in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ed Charles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Weis",
      "B. Ed Charles",
      "C. Bud Harrelson",
      "D. Wayne Garrett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the winning pitcher in game five of the 1969 World Series, clinching the Series for the Mets?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerry Koosman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Koosman",
      "B. Tug McGraw",
      "C. Gary Gentry",
      "D. Tom Seaver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Mets manager in 1969?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gil Hodges",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Steinbrenner",
      "B. Yogi Berra",
      "C. Gil Hodges",
      "D. Casey Stengel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was not one of the starting outfielders for the Mets in the 1969 World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Don Hahn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Swaboda",
      "B. Cleon Jones",
      "C. Tommy Agee",
      "D. Don Hahn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The year 1969 was a championship season for all of these New York teams, except this one.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rangers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Knicks",
      "B. Jets",
      "C. Rangers",
      "D. Mets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Oriole made the final out of the 1969 World Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Davey Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brooks Robinson",
      "B. Davey Johnson",
      "C. Frank Robinson",
      "D. Boog Powell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the main animals used in a rodeo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "horses and cattle",
    "choices": [
      "A. horses and buffalo",
      "B. horses and goats",
      "C. cattle and pigs",
      "D. horses and cattle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The image of a bucking horse and rider is a registered trademark of which state?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wyoming",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wyoming",
      "B. Texas",
      "C. Colorado",
      "D. Nevada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what state is the Sikeston Jaycee Bootheel Rodeo held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Missouri",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michigan",
      "B. Montana",
      "C. Missouri",
      "D. Mississippi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the U.S. the largest number of rodeos are held on which weekend?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4th of July",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4th of July",
      "B. Veterans Day",
      "C. Labor Day",
      "D. Memorial Day"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the PRCA Wrangler National Finals Rodeo held ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nevada",
    "choices": [
      "A. Texas",
      "B. Missouri",
      "C. Wyoming",
      "D. Nevada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following events are men and women allowed to compete together?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Team Roping",
    "choices": [
      "A. Breakaway Roping",
      "B. Calf Roping",
      "C. Steer Roping",
      "D. Team Roping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams are there in the NHL?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "30",
    "choices": [
      "A. 30",
      "B. 25",
      "C. 15",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What hockey team plays in Calgary?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Flames",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hurricanes",
      "B. Tornadoes",
      "C. Flames",
      "D. Avalanche"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How may periods are there in a regular ice hockey game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following players scored 76 goals in his rookie season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Teemu SelÃ¤nne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jagomir Jagr",
      "B. Teemu SelÃ¤nne",
      "C. Wayne Gretzky",
      "D. Brett Hull"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Washington Capitals player was the first overall selection in the 2004 NHL Entry Draft.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alexander Ovechkin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jaromir Jagr",
      "B. Alexander Ovechkin",
      "C. Mark Messier",
      "D. Wayne Gretzky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which goaltender has the nickname King Henrik?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Henrik Lundqvist",
    "choices": [
      "A. Henrik Lundqvist",
      "B. Henrik Nittymaki",
      "C. Henrik Park",
      "D. Henrik Suave"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many goaltenders must a team have on their roster according to the NHL rules?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 2",
      "D. As many as they want"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many teams participated in the first ICC World Cup tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 12",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the Cricket World Cup inaugurated?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "England",
    "choices": [
      "A. England",
      "B. West Indies",
      "C. Australia",
      "D. Ireland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country won the inaugural ICC World Cup of 1975 (aka Prudential Cup 1975)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "West Indies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australia",
      "B. England",
      "C. India",
      "D. West Indies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the inaugural ICC World Cup final played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lords, London",
    "choices": [
      "A. Edgbaston Cricket Ground, Birmingham",
      "B. The Oval, London",
      "C. Trent Bridge, Nottingham",
      "D. Lords, London"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country stood runner-up in the final of the inaugural ICC World Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Australia",
    "choices": [
      "A. England",
      "B. India",
      "C. Pakistan",
      "D. Australia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the winning captain of the inaugural ICC World Cup tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Clive Lloyd",
    "choices": [
      "A. AIvin Kallicharran",
      "B. Garry Gilmour",
      "C. Clive Lloyd",
      "D. Vivian Richards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Man of the Series in the inaugural ICC World Cup of 1975?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "none",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ian Chappell",
      "B. none",
      "C. Vivian Richards",
      "D. Clive Lloyd"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which nation was banned from the first Cricket World Cup tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "South Africa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pakistan",
      "B. Australia",
      "C. South Africa",
      "D. Sri Lanka"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following MLB teams hit the most home runs in one major league season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "97 Seatle Mariners",
    "choices": [
      "A. 76 Cincinnati Reds",
      "B. 04 Boston Red Sox",
      "C. 97 Seatle Mariners",
      "D. 61 New York Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Three of these MLB players have hit at least 400 home runs in one single decade. Who does not belong to the group?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Williams",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mark McGwire",
      "B. Ted Williams",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Jimmie Fox"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Three of these MLB players have hit a home run in at least 8 consecutive games. Which of the listed players did not accomplish this feat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Robin Ventura",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dale Long",
      "B. Robin Ventura",
      "C. Don Mattingly",
      "D. Ken Griffey Jr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ever since the MLBs live ball era, which began in 1920, home runs have become more popular and more abundant. Which of the following is the only decade that has not had a player hit for at least 50 home runs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1980",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1940",
      "B. 1920",
      "C. 1980",
      "D. 1960"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following sluggers never hit 50 home runs in a single season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Cecil Fielder",
      "C. Willie Mays",
      "D. Mickey Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following MLB veterans hit over 20 home runs in a single season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "J.T. Snow",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tim Raines",
      "B. Keith Hernandez",
      "C. Mark Grace",
      "D. J.T. Snow"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following players hit for more than 40 home runs during any season throughout his MLB career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Dimaggio",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roberto Clemente",
      "B. Bo Jackson",
      "C. Joe Torre",
      "D. Joe Dimaggio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following MLB players has ever hit over 40 or more home runs in a single season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Reggie Jackson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eddie Murray",
      "B. Reggie Jackson",
      "C. Joe Carter",
      "D. Fred McGriff"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the NBA Champions in 1990?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Detroit Pistons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "B. Los Angeles Lakers",
      "C. Chicago Bulls",
      "D. Detroit Pistons"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the NBA Champions of 1991.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Phoenix Suns",
      "B. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "C. Chicago Bulls",
      "D. Los Angeles Lakers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 1992 NBA Championship was won by this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Portland Trail Blazers",
      "B. Los Angeles Lakers",
      "C. Chicago Bulls",
      "D. New York Knicks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the NBA Championship in 1995?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Houston Rockets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Utah Jazz",
      "B. Orlando Magic",
      "C. Houston Rockets",
      "D. New York Knicks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1996, the NBA Championship was won by this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seattle SuperSonics",
      "B. Orlando Magic",
      "C. Houston Rockets",
      "D. Chicago Bulls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This team won the NBA Championship in 1999.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Antonio Spurs",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Knicks",
      "B. Los Angels Lakers",
      "C. Chicago Bulls",
      "D. San Antonio Spurs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first coach to win four Super Bowls?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chuck Noll",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Shula",
      "B. Bill Walsh",
      "C. Chuck Noll",
      "D. Bill Parcells"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams won three Super Bowls during the 1990s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Cowboys",
    "choices": [
      "A. Denver Broncos",
      "B. San Francisco 49ers",
      "C. Dallas Cowboys",
      "D. Pittsburgh Steelers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This kickers 32-yard field goal won Super Bowl V with five seconds left in the game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jim OBrien",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim OBrien",
      "B. Jim Turner",
      "C. Tom Matte",
      "D. Tom Dempsey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these running backs did not rush for 100+ yards in a Super Bowl game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Duane Thomas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duane Thomas",
      "B. Larry Csonka",
      "C. Ottis Anderson",
      "D. John Riggins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first quarterback to start for two different losing Super Bowl teams?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Craig Morton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Trent Dilfer",
      "B. Craig Morton",
      "C. Fran Tarkenton",
      "D. John Unitas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team beat the Patriots in Super Bowl XX?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bears",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bears",
      "B. Rams",
      "C. Panthers",
      "D. Eagles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which golf course is commonly referred to as the home of golf?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "St. Andrews",
    "choices": [
      "A. Royal Birkdale",
      "B. Turnberry",
      "C. Pebble Beach",
      "D. St. Andrews"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do golfers Adam Scott, Greg Norman and Geoff Ogilvy have in common?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They were all born in Australia.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They were all born in Australia.",
      "B. They have never won majors championships.",
      "C. They were all born in New Zealand.",
      "D. They were all born in 1980."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A golf player hits the ball from the tee onto the green and in the hole all in one shot. What is this called?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hole-in-one",
    "choices": [
      "A. Birdie",
      "B. Holed",
      "C. Hole-in-one",
      "D. Bogey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A golf player, on a par 5, hits their drive O.B. (Out of Bounds). What should he/she do after that?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "take a stroke-and-distance penalty and play the ball from the tee again, as stroke 3",
    "choices": [
      "A. take a stroke-and-distance penalty and play the ball from the tee again, as stroke 3",
      "B. take a stroke penalty and drop a new ball from where the original ball entered the O.B. area",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. replay the stroke without a penalty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In theory, a foursome should get around all 18 holes of a golf course in how many hours?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4 hours",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4 hours",
      "B. 6 hours",
      "C. 7 hours",
      "D. 2 hours"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Football player Edison Arantes do Nascimento, known as Pele, was nicknamed after which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A football player",
    "choices": [
      "A. A meal",
      "B. A cartoon character",
      "C. A hurricane",
      "D. A football player"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which football team did Ronaldo de Assis Moreira, known as Ronaldinho, make his European debut in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paris Saint-Germain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paris Saint-Germain",
      "B. Barcelona",
      "C. Milan",
      "D. Nantes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of what descent is football player Zinedine Zidane?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Algerian",
    "choices": [
      "A. Moroccan",
      "B. Algerian",
      "C. Egyptian",
      "D. South African"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For what U.S. football team did David Beckham start playing in 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Galaxy",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Red Bulls",
      "B. Los Angeles Galaxy",
      "C. Columbus Crew",
      "D. D.C. United"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of injury put the end of Marco van Bastens career in 1995?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ankle injury",
    "choices": [
      "A. Back injury",
      "B. Knee injury",
      "C. Ankle injury",
      "D. Head injury"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of these European football teams hasnt Diego Maradona played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Real Madrid",
    "choices": [
      "A. Napoli",
      "B. Sevilla",
      "C. Barcelona",
      "D. Real Madrid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What interesting nickname was given to football player Ronaldo Luis Nazario de Lima, better known simply as Ronaldo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Phenomenon",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Phenomenon",
      "B. The Magician",
      "C. The Unbelievable",
      "D. The Miracle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which U.S. football team has Franz Beckenbauer played between 1977 and 1980, and again in 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York Cosmos",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Cosmos",
      "B. Columbus Crew",
      "C. D.C. United",
      "D. New York Red Bulls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what position did football star Romario play throughout his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Striker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Defender",
      "B. Striker",
      "C. Sweeper",
      "D. Midfielder"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what football team hasnt Johan Cruyff played throughout his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Milan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barcelona",
      "B. Los Angeles Aztecs",
      "C. Washington Diplomats",
      "D. Milan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which American chess player was called The Pride and Sorrow of Chess?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Morphy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Keres",
      "B. Paul Morphy",
      "C. Emmanuel Lasker",
      "D. Mikhail Botvinnik"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess player, originally from Armenia, was the chess champion of the world from 1985 to 2000, when he lost the title to Vladimir Kramnik. He is also known in the chess world for his numerous and titanic struggles with Anatoly Karpov.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Garry Kasparov",
    "choices": [
      "A. Akiba Rubinstein",
      "B. Mikhail Tal",
      "C. Garry Kasparov",
      "D. Victor Korchnoi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess player, famous for his Anti-Semitism and his reclusiveness, became the first American to win the official world chess championship.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Fischer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Morphy",
      "B. Frank Marshall",
      "C. William Steinitz",
      "D. Bobby Fischer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which famous artist also went to try his hand at chess?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Marcel Duchamp",
    "choices": [
      "A. Man Ray",
      "B. Pablo Picasso",
      "C. Marcel Duchamp",
      "D. Henri Matisse"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Russian chess player played during the 1960s and was one of the first to analyze his opponents earlier games. He is also one of the few players to hold a full-time job as an engineer.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mikhail Botvinnik",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Keres",
      "B. Tigran Petrosian",
      "C. Mikhail Tal",
      "D. Mikhail Botvinnik"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Russian grandmaster was known for his intimidating stare. He was considered extremely good at sacrificing pieces. However, poor health caused him to never play to his full potential.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mikhail Tal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harry Nelson Pillsbury",
      "B. Mikhail Tal",
      "C. Paul Keres",
      "D. Salo Flohr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Russian-French grandmaster was world chess champion from 1927-1935, and then promptly lost the title to Max Euwe?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alexander Alekhine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Salo Flohr",
      "B. Alexander Alekhine",
      "C. Jose Raul Capablanca",
      "D. Aron Nimzovitch"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This was the year the Pittsburgh Penguins hockey team was founded. The same year the NHL doubled in size from the Original Six to twelve teams.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1967",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1970",
      "B. 1966",
      "C. 1968",
      "D. 1967"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Pittsburgh Penguins win their first Playoff Series?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1970",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1968",
      "B. 1970",
      "C. 1967",
      "D. 1972"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What were the original team colors of the Pittsburgh Penguins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "blue and white",
    "choices": [
      "A. They have always worn black and gold.",
      "B. blue and white",
      "C. black and gold",
      "D. gold and white"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the Pittsburgh Penguins win their first Stanley Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1991",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1989",
      "B. 1991",
      "C. 1992",
      "D. 1990"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Goalie acquired from the Buffalo Sabres who played for the Pittsburgh Penguins in their first two Stanley Cup victories?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Barrasso",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wendell Young",
      "B. Bruce Racine",
      "C. Frank Pietrangelo",
      "D. Tom Barrasso"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Pittsburgh Penguin became the first player/owner in NHL history in the year 2000.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mario Lemieux",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jaromir Jagr",
      "B. Ron Francis",
      "C. Mario Lemieux",
      "D. Scotty Bowman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the famed Alabama football coach Paul Bryant born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Moro Bottom, Ark.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Moro Bottom, Ark.",
      "B. Junction, TX",
      "C. Louisville, Ky",
      "D. Chicago, IL"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Paul Bryant become head coach for the University of Alabama?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1958",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1973",
      "B. 1958",
      "C. 1966",
      "D. 1956"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Paul Bryant die?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1983",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1987",
      "B. 1982",
      "C. 1983",
      "D. 1990"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A record for the fastest goal was set at the start of an NHL playoff game on April 17, 1972. How long after the start of the playoff game was it scored?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6 seconds",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6 seconds",
      "B. 4 seconds",
      "C. 3 seconds",
      "D. 5 seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened during the second period of Game 4 of the 1988 Stanley Cup Finals between the Boston Bruins and the Edmonton Oilers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The lights went out.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The refs never showed up for the second period.",
      "B. The coaches had a fight on the ice.",
      "C. The lights went out.",
      "D. There was a bomb threat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When the New Jersey Devils won the Stanley Cup in 2003, where did goaltender, Martin Brodeur take the Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "to a movie theatre",
    "choices": [
      "A. to a diner",
      "B. to the bathroom",
      "C. to a car show",
      "D. to a movie theatre"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the Stanley Cup made?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "London, England",
    "choices": [
      "A. France",
      "B. London, England",
      "C. Canada",
      "D. New York, New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Jim Brown when he retired from the Cleveland Browns?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "30",
    "choices": [
      "A. 33",
      "B. 45",
      "C. 30",
      "D. 31"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the Cleveland Browns win their first NFL Championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1950",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1964",
      "B. 1954",
      "C. 1950",
      "D. 1955"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2009, this Cleveland Browns player was involved in a car accident that left a pedestrian dead.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Donte Stallworth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Donte Stallworth",
      "B. Joe Thomas",
      "C. Brady Quinn",
      "D. Braylon Edwards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shaun Rodgers, who joined the Cleveland Browns in 2008, plays what position?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "LB",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wr and QB",
      "B. Wr",
      "C. LB",
      "D. Wr, Db"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What jersey number has Jamal Lewis worn for the Cleveland Browns?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "31",
    "choices": [
      "A. 17",
      "B. 92",
      "C. 3",
      "D. 31"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was the NCAA Mens Basketball Tournament founded?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1939",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1907",
      "B. 1917",
      "C. 1939",
      "D. 1956"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What NCAA Mens Basketball team has won the most National Titles from 1939-2009?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "UCLA",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kentucky",
      "B. Kansas",
      "C. North Carolina",
      "D. UCLA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which league does not hold a post season tournament to determine who their automatic bid is to the NCAA Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ivy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Big East",
      "B. Ivy",
      "C. Mid West Conference",
      "D. Sunbelt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The NCAA started seeding mens basketball teams in 1979 and 2008 marked the first time when all #1 seeds made it to the Final Four. Name the teams that made it.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas, North Carolina, UCLA, Memphis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kansas, North Carolina, UCLA, Memphis",
      "B. Kansas, North Carolina, UCLA, UNLV",
      "C. Kansas, North Carolina, Duke, Memphis",
      "D. Kentucky, North Carolina, UCLA, Memphis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Since the beginning of the NCAA Mens Basketball tournament until 2009, what team had the most tournament appearances without ever having gone to the Championship game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "BYU",
    "choices": [
      "A. Missouri",
      "B. Texas Tech",
      "C. Yale",
      "D. BYU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1941 this NCAA Mens basketball team set the record for lowest points scored in a Championship appearance.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "North Carolina",
    "choices": [
      "A. North Carolina",
      "B. Mississippi Valley St.",
      "C. North Texas University",
      "D. Yale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former basketball players has the most NCAA Championship wins and NBA Championship wins combined?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Russell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Jordan",
      "B. Kareem Abdul Jabbar",
      "C. Bill Russell",
      "D. Sam Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The true origin of racquetball is questionable, but which decade did the shortened racquet appear?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1930s",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1900s",
      "B. 1930s",
      "C. 1970s",
      "D. 1950s"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In racquetball a player must win by at least how many points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two basic types of serves in racquetball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Drive serve and Lob serve",
    "choices": [
      "A. Drive serve and Lob serve",
      "B. Stoop serve and Straight serve",
      "C. Pure serve and Fake serve",
      "D. Stick serve and Flick serve"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the official rules of the United States Racquetball Association a match may be forfeited by the referee in which of the following cases?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. All of these",
      "B. Any player for a singles match, or any team for a doubles match, fails to report to play. Normally, 20 minutes from the scheduled game time will be allowed before forfeiture.",
      "C. Any player refuses to abide by the referees decision, or engages in unsportsmanlike conduct.",
      "D. Any player leaves the court without permission of the referee during a game"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The racquetball term avoidable hinder refers to which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Interference, not necessarily intentional",
    "choices": [
      "A. Illegal placement of a foot before or during the serve",
      "B. Serve that hits the ceiling",
      "C. Interference, not necessarily intentional",
      "D. Intimidating the opponent by playing too close"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following court types are allowed in racquetball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. It is played outdoors",
      "B. All of these",
      "C. Three-walled courts",
      "D. One-walled courts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first NFL player to intercept 14 passes in one season. He did this in his rookie year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dick Lane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Emlenn Tunnel",
      "B. Dick Lane",
      "C. J.C.Caroline",
      "D. Jerry Gray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was a seventeenth round draft choice of the New York Giants out of the University of Iowa. He played for the Giants from 1948-1958. He then played  for the Green Bay Packers from 1959-1961.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Emlen Tunell",
    "choices": [
      "A. J.C.Caroline",
      "B. Dick Lane",
      "C. Emlen Tunell",
      "D. Jerry Gray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Philadelphia-born athlete was in five Pro Bowls, and in the 1960s All-Decade Team. In 1980, he was inducted into the Pro Football Hall of Fame.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Herb Adderley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johnny Sample",
      "B. Dennis Smith",
      "C. Lem Barney",
      "D. Herb Adderley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great player was in seven Pro Bowls, and was a seven time All-League Cornerback. He played from 1967-1977 for the Detroit Lions.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lem Barney",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dennis Smith",
      "B. Ken Riley",
      "C. Lem Barney",
      "D. J.C.Caroline"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He began his career before the merger of the NFL and AFL. He played for the Broncos and Raiders. He was an integral part of the Raider defense for many years. He played from 1963-1978. He was voted to the AFL All-Time Team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie Brown",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dennis Smith",
      "B. J.C.Caroline",
      "C. Willie Wood",
      "D. Willie Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He played in the NFL from 1987-2003 after his college career at Purdue. Throughout most of his defensive backs career he played in Pittsburgh. He became a TV analyst for ESPN.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rod Woodson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Herb Adderley",
      "B. Rod Woodson",
      "C. Terry Bradshaw",
      "D. Jack Youngblood"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Hall of Famer played corner back for New England from 1972-1986 and for Oakland from 1983-1989. He played his college ball at Arizona State.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Haynes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Haynes",
      "B. Adalius Thomas",
      "C. Willie Wood",
      "D. Mike Woodson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This defensive back played for San Francisco from 1961-1976. He was All-Pro four times. His brother was a great decathlon athlete and one of Robert Kennedys bodyguards.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jimmy Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Johnson",
      "B. Rod Woodson",
      "C. Dallas Thompson",
      "D. Elroy OBrien"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This great defensive back played from 1964-1977 for the Dallas Cowboys after a great career at Oregon. He was selected to the Pro Bowl 10 times.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mel Renfro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chuck Healey",
      "B. Deion Sanders",
      "C. Herb Adderley",
      "D. Mel Renfro"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This defensive back played for Detroit from 1952-1953 and 1956-1964. Not only was he a starting defensive back but he was also the teams punter.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yale Larry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dick Lane",
      "B. Dick Lebeau",
      "C. Ray Guy",
      "D. Yale Larry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first US auto race held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1895",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1925",
      "B. 1905",
      "C. 1910",
      "D. 1895"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who said Driving a race car is like dancing with a chain saw.?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cale Yarborough",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brian Vickers",
      "B. Richard Petty",
      "C. Jeff Gordon",
      "D. Cale Yarborough"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of engine uses a combustion chamber that is shaped like half a sphere?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hemi",
    "choices": [
      "A. DECT-8",
      "B. V-Tech",
      "C. V-12",
      "D. Hemi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On July 2, 2008 the NHRA ruled  that Top Fuel and Funny Car races can not be longer than 1000  feet. This ruling was spurred by the accidental racetrack death of this driver.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scott Kalitta",
    "choices": [
      "A. Scott Kalitta",
      "B. Robert Hight",
      "C. Red Brundige",
      "D. John Maintrop"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What race is often referred to as The Grand Prix of Endurance?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "24 Hours of Le Mans",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Grand prix of Monaco",
      "B. 24 Hours of Le Mans",
      "C. The Indianapolis 500",
      "D. The  Milan Grand Prix"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bill France, Sr. is usually considered the founder of NASCAR. Which race course did Bill France Sr. and Bill France Jr. promote?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Daytona, Florida",
    "choices": [
      "A. Martinsville, Virginia",
      "B. Daytona, Florida",
      "C. Darlington, South Carolina",
      "D. Talladega, Alabama"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first man to drive a car at at least 60 miles per hour?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barney Oldfield",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cale Yarborough",
      "B. Barney Oldfield",
      "C. Carl G. Fisher",
      "D. Bob Burman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the first NASCAR-sanctioned race held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Daytona, Florida",
    "choices": [
      "A. Indianapolis, Indiana",
      "B. Daytona, Florida",
      "C. Martinsville, Virginia",
      "D. Talladega, Alabama"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Top Fuel race cars run on this type of fuel.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nitromethane and Methanol",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nitromethane and Methanol",
      "B. Ethanol and Nitropropane",
      "C. Nitroglycerin and Methanol",
      "D. Propane and Methane"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which NASCAR race was formerly called The World 600?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Coca Cola 600",
    "choices": [
      "A. Food Yard 600",
      "B. Aarons 600",
      "C. Coca Cola 600",
      "D. Southern 600"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first NASCAR driver with 100 career victories, as well as the first one with 200 career victories.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Richard Petty",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kyle Petty",
      "B. Dale Earnhardt",
      "C. Richard Petty",
      "D. Bobby Allison"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first Virginia 500 held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1949.",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1949.",
      "B. 1938",
      "C. 1950",
      "D. 1946"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first Daytona 500 held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1959",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1959",
      "B. 1949",
      "C. 1946",
      "D. 1955"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the first Brickyard 400 held?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Indianapolis, Indiana",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jackson, Mississippi",
      "B. Bristol, Tennessee",
      "C. Charlotte, North Carolina",
      "D. Indianapolis, Indiana"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tracy Chapmans song Fast Car became an international hit when she performed it at the 70th Birthday Tribute to this famous man.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nelson Mandela",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Newman",
      "B. Paul Simon",
      "C. Nelson Mandela",
      "D. Richard Petty, Sr."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Ray Harroun win the first Indianapolis 500?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1911",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1931",
      "B. 1941",
      "C. 1911",
      "D. 1925"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first female driver at the Indianapolis 500?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Janet Guthrie",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sally Rider",
      "B. Lyn St. James",
      "C. Wanda Montgomery",
      "D. Janet Guthrie"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the original version of the game of volleyball called?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mintonette",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mintonette",
      "B. Ballonette",
      "C. Setball",
      "D. Netball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was volleyball invented?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil",
      "B. the USA",
      "C. Cuba",
      "D. Canada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first official ball used in volleyball was created in the beginning of the 20th century by this company.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spalding",
    "choices": [
      "A. Spalding",
      "B. Molten",
      "C. Wilson",
      "D. Gala"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the second country after the United States to adopt volleyball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Canada",
    "choices": [
      "A. Canada",
      "B. Brazil",
      "C. Mexico",
      "D. Russia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not a stroke in volleyball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "palm",
    "choices": [
      "A. spike",
      "B. bump",
      "C. palm",
      "D. dip"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these volleyball players wears a jersey in a contrasting color to the jerseys of his/her teammates?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "libero",
    "choices": [
      "A. outside hitter",
      "B. libero",
      "C. opposite hitter",
      "D. setter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What part of the body are volleyball players permitted to contact the ball with?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "all parts of the body",
    "choices": [
      "A. hands and head",
      "B. hands and arms only",
      "C. hands and legs",
      "D. all parts of the body"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is different in the two variations of volleyball - beach and indoor?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "all of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. number of sets in a match",
      "B. size of court",
      "C. all of these",
      "D. number of players in a team"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1987 the first World Beach Volleyball Championships was played in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brazil",
    "choices": [
      "A. Russia",
      "B. the Netherlands",
      "C. Brazil",
      "D. the USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the tragic fire that killed Kane and the Undertakers parents occur according to a WrestleMania storyline?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "November 7 1977",
    "choices": [
      "A. November 8 1977",
      "B. November 6 1977",
      "C. November 7 1977",
      "D. November 9 1977"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many foster homes was the Undertaker put in after his parents were killed according to a WrestleMania storyline?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 0",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the professional wrestling tag team consisting of The Undertaker and Kane?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Brothers of Destruction",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Brothers of Death",
      "B. The Brothers of Destruction",
      "C. The Brothers of Pain",
      "D. The Brothers of Damage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The tattoo around the Undertakers neck reads Sara. Who is Sara?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "His wife",
    "choices": [
      "A. His wife",
      "B. His niece",
      "C. His cousin",
      "D. His daughter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many points are awarded to the winner of a ski jumping competition in the World Cup circuit?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "100",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 100",
      "C. 50",
      "D. 25"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first ski jumper ever to win the World Cup 3 times in a row?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Adam MaÅysz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Andreas Goldberger",
      "B. Adam MaÅysz",
      "C. Jens Weissflog",
      "D. Matti NykÃ¤nen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former Finnish ski jumper is one of the best in the history of the sport with his five Olympic medals (four Golds), nine World championships medals (five Golds) and 22 Finnish championships medals (13 Golds).",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Matti NykÃ¤nen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Janne Ahonen",
      "B. Matti NykÃ¤nen",
      "C. Jens Wessflog",
      "D. Adam MaÅysz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ski jumpers used to jump with the skis positioned parallelly. Nowadays the skis are V-shaped during the jump. Who introduced this manner of jumping in 1988?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jan BoklÃ¶v",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jan BoklÃ¶v",
      "B. Dieter Thoma",
      "C. Matti NykÃ¤nen",
      "D. Jens Weissflog"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ski jumper was badly injured in a training session in 2002, but recovered in a month to win 2 gold medals at the Salt Lake City Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Simon Ammann",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sven Hannavald",
      "B. Matti Hautamaeki",
      "C. Adam MaÅysz",
      "D. Simon Ammann"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why  was the 2005/06 Four Hills Ski Jumping Tournament unique?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was won ex equo by Janne Ahonen and Jakub Janda.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was won ex equo by Janne Ahonen and Jakub Janda.",
      "B. The winner, Sven Hannawald, won all four competitions.",
      "C. The winner was disqualified.",
      "D. The winner, Andreas Jacobsen, was the youngest ever in the history of the tournament ."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On which hill does the World Cup ski jumping season traditionally end?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Letalnica (formerly Velikanka) in Planica, Slovenia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Letalnica (formerly Velikanka) in Planica, Slovenia",
      "B. Hollmenkollen in Oslo, Norway",
      "C. Gross Olympiaschanze in Garmisch-Partenkirchen, Germany",
      "D. Wielka Krokiew in Zakopane, Poland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which ski jumper broke the world record in ski jump length (239m) in 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bjoern Einar Romoeren",
    "choices": [
      "A. Adam MaÅysz",
      "B. Janne Ahonen",
      "C. Bjoern Einar Romoeren",
      "D. Roar LjÃ¸kelsÃ¸y"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about the British ski jumper Eddie Eagle Edwards?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was unfit for the sport, had no financial support, but yet kept on jumping.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was actually a woman after a sex-change operation.",
      "B. He was unfit for the sport, had no financial support, but yet kept on jumping.",
      "C. He was the first black man in the sport.",
      "D. He has won the most medals at the Olympics."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which hill is called the Mecca of ski jumping?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Holmenkollen in Oslo, Norway",
    "choices": [
      "A. Letalnica in Planica, Slovenia",
      "B. Bergisel in Innsbruck, Austria",
      "C. Okurayama in Sapporr, Japan",
      "D. Holmenkollen in Oslo, Norway"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nationality of Adam MaÅysz, one of the greatest stars of ski jumping?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Polish",
    "choices": [
      "A. Finnish",
      "B. German",
      "C. Polish",
      "D. Norwegian"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Soviet Union pair to win the Winter Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Protopopovs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mishkatanuk  Dmitriev",
      "B. Gordeeva  Grinkov",
      "C. Rodnina  Zaitsev",
      "D. The Protopopovs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This figure skater made history in 1998 when he won his second Olympic Gold Medal with a different partner, who was going for her first Olympic Gold. Name the first man to win the Olympics twice with two different partners?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Artur Dmitriev",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maxim Marinin",
      "B. Anton Sikharulidze",
      "C. Artur Dmitriev",
      "D. Alexei Tikhonov"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Coached by Yao Bin, this Chinese pair team have a lot of firsts under their belts. They were the first Chinese team to stand on the podium at the World Figure Skating Championships, earning silver in 1999. They later became the first Chinese team to medal at the Winter Olympics in 2002, earning the bronze, and in March of 2002 they were the first to win gold at the World Championships. Who are they?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Xue Shen  Hongbo Zhao",
    "choices": [
      "A. Xue Shen  Hongbo Zhao",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Qing Pang  Jion Tong",
      "D. Dan  Hao Zhang"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pair became the first to do a ratified quadruple twist?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Julia Obertas  Sergei Slavnov",
    "choices": [
      "A. Julia Obertas  Sergei Slavnov",
      "B. Dan Zhang  Hao Zhang",
      "C. Ekaterina Gordeeva  Sergei Grinkov",
      "D. Xue Shen  Hongbo Zhao"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In January of 2006, Rene Inoue and John Baldwin, Jr. made history at the United States National Championships. What was their historic achievement?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They successfully executed the first throw triple Axel.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They successfully executed the first throw quadruple Salchow.",
      "B. They invented a lift never done before.",
      "C. They successfully executed the first throw triple Axel.",
      "D. They became the first Japanese-Americans to win the National Championships."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first death spiral was performed by this legendary couple.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Protopopovs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kitty  Peter Caruthers",
      "B. Babilonia  Gardner",
      "C. Gordeeva  Grinkov",
      "D. The Protopopovs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As a child, this male pairs skater skated singles. Upon losing to a younger skater from the same town, he switched to pairs. He later became a 2-time World Champion and Olympic Champion with his partner, after overcoming a near-fatal accident. Who is he?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maxim Marinin",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jason Dunjeon",
      "B. Lloyd Eisler",
      "C. Maxim Marinin",
      "D. Peter Caruthers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first American pair to win a World Figure Skating Championship Gold Medal?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Karol  Michael Kennedy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Karol  Michael Kennedy",
      "B. Kyoko Ina  Jason Dunjeon",
      "C. Babilonia  Gardner",
      "D. Kitty  Peter Caruthers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the first ice dance competition held at the World Championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1952",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1975",
      "B. 1896",
      "C. 1952",
      "D. 1901"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country did the first World Champions in ice dance represent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Great Britain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Soviet Union",
      "B. France",
      "C. Great Britain",
      "D. Soviet Union"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did the legendary Jayne Torvil and Christopher Dean win their first World Championship Gold?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1981",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1981",
      "B. They never won a World Championship.",
      "C. 1984",
      "D. 1982"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Frances Marina Anissina and Gwendal Peizerat are famous for what incredible move?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A lift in which Marina lifts Gwendal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dance spin",
      "B. A lift in which Marina lifts Gwendal",
      "C. Hydroblade",
      "D. Twizzles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What bull was commonly referred to as âThe Worldâs Most Dangerous Bullâ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bodacious",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bodacious",
      "B. Yellow Jacket",
      "C. Grasshopper",
      "D. Wolf Man"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What World Champion bull rider had his face crushed by a bull named Bodacious?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tuff Hedeman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerome Davis",
      "B. Ty Murray",
      "C. Lane Frost",
      "D. Tuff Hedeman"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the rodeo event called calf roping, riders have a rope woven within their belts. What is it called?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerk line",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerk line",
      "B. Piggin string",
      "C. Tie wrap",
      "D. Spare rope"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the piece of rope used by a calf roper?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is used to tie the calf.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It makes the horse stop.",
      "B. It makes the horse back up.",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. It is used to tie the calf."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which word refers to the bull doggers partner in the rodeo discipline known as steer wrestling?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hazer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Header",
      "B. Hazer",
      "C. Flanker",
      "D. Heeler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What penalty does a barrel racer get for knocking down a barrel?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5 seconds",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10 seconds",
      "B. 20 seconds",
      "C. Disqualification",
      "D. 5 seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How must the calf be caught in the event known as calf roping?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "With rope only",
    "choices": [
      "A. By tripping it up",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. With rope only",
      "D. By two feet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is considered the most common foul in timed roping rodeo events?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Breaking the barrier",
    "choices": [
      "A. Improper roping",
      "B. Breaking the barrier",
      "C. Animal abuse",
      "D. Improper equipment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many ropes is a calf roper allowed to use in the rodeo event calf roping?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Two",
    "choices": [
      "A. There is no restriction.",
      "B. Three",
      "C. Two",
      "D. One"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary role of a bullfighter in the rodeo event bull riding?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Protect the rider from harm",
    "choices": [
      "A. Protect the rider from harm",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Tease the bull",
      "D. Entertain the audience"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What New York Mets slugger won Rookie of the Year in 1983?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Darryl Strawberry",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Foster",
      "B. Darryl Strawberry",
      "C. David Wright",
      "D. Mookie Wilson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When the New York Mets traded Rick Ownbey and Neil Allen to the St. Louis Cardinals in 1983 who did they get in return?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Keith Hernandez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Darling",
      "B. Keith Hernandez",
      "C. Kevin Mitchell",
      "D. Ray Knight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "in Game 6 of the 1986 World Series, which hitter was on deck when Mookie Wilson hit that infamous  groundball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Howard Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Darryl Strawberry",
      "B. Howard Johnson",
      "C. Kevin Elster",
      "D. Lee Mazzili"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the New York Mets player who hit 3 home runs in one game in the 1999 National League Division Series held at Shea Stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It never happened.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It never happened.",
      "B. Carlos Delgado",
      "C. Darryl Strawberry",
      "D. Mike Piazza"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of these years did the New York Mets qualify for the postseason as the National League Wild Card team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1999 and 2000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000 and 2004",
      "B. 1999 and 2000",
      "C. 2000 and 2003",
      "D. 1999 and 2004"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country won the most medals at the 2012 Summer Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. China",
      "B. Great Britain",
      "C. Russia",
      "D. USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these disciplines was included for the first time in the Olympic program at the 2012 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "womens boxing",
    "choices": [
      "A. womens weightlifting",
      "B. womens boxing",
      "C. mens rhythmic gymnastics",
      "D. womens judo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following female swimmers did not set a world record at the 2012 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Elizabeth Beisel",
    "choices": [
      "A. Missy Franklin",
      "B. Rebecca Soni",
      "C. Dana Vollmer",
      "D. Elizabeth Beisel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what 2012 Summer Olympics athletics competition did the gold, silver and bronze medals go to Jamaica?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mens 200 metres",
    "choices": [
      "A. Womens 400 metres",
      "B. Mens 100 metres",
      "C. Mens 200 metres",
      "D. Womens 100 metres"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What track and field athlete became double Olympic champion at the 2012 Olympic Games in London, taking gold in both the 5000 and 10,000 metres?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mo Farah",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mo Farah",
      "B. Galen Rupp",
      "C. David Rudisha",
      "D. Tariku Bekele"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these gymnastics disciplines, contested at the 2012 Olympic Games, was the last to be recognised as an Olympic discipline?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "trampolining",
    "choices": [
      "A. rhythmic gymnastics",
      "B. artistic gymnastics",
      "C. They all became Olympic disciplines in the same year.",
      "D. trampolining"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2012 Summer Olympics, this athlete won four gold and two silver medals, making him the most decorated Olympic athlete for the third Olympics in a row.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Michael Phelps",
    "choices": [
      "A. Usain Bolt",
      "B. Missy Franklin",
      "C. Mo Farah",
      "D. Michael Phelps"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mens national team is NOT correctly matched with the sport in which they won a gold medal in the 2012 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brazil - indoor volleyball",
    "choices": [
      "A. France - Handball",
      "B. The USA - basketball",
      "C. Brazil - indoor volleyball",
      "D. Football - Mexico"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What member of the British royal family won a silver medal in the 2012 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zara Phillips",
    "choices": [
      "A. Prince Edward",
      "B. Prince William",
      "C. Zara Phillips",
      "D. Prince Harry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Some of the swimming events at the 2012 Olympic Games were held in this venue, which also hosts a race every Christmas morning for the Peter Pan Cup.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the Serpentine",
    "choices": [
      "A. the Serpentine",
      "B. the English Channel",
      "C. the Avon",
      "D. the Thames"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the New England Patriots become a franchise?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1960",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1959",
      "B. 1981",
      "C. 1989",
      "D. 1960"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first logo of the New England Patriots?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "a hat",
    "choices": [
      "A. a head",
      "B. a banana",
      "C. a boot",
      "D. a hat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the New England Patriots go to their first Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1986",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1994",
      "B. 2001",
      "C. 1975",
      "D. 1986"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did New England Patriots play against in their second Super Bowl appearance?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the Packers",
    "choices": [
      "A. the Rams",
      "B. the 49ers",
      "C. the Cowboys",
      "D. the Packers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did the New England Patriots win their first Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2001",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2003",
      "B. 2006",
      "C. 2000",
      "D. 2001"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the New England Patriots first round pick in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Laurence Maroney",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sammy Morris",
      "B. Laurence Maroney",
      "C. Richard Seymour",
      "D. Tom Brady"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the the New England Patriots first round draft pick in 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brandon Meriweather",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ellis Hobbs",
      "B. Jerod Mayo",
      "C. Randy Moss",
      "D. Brandon Meriweather"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the New England Patriots first round pick in 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerod Mayo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Daniel Graham",
      "B. Jerod Mayo",
      "C. Jason Webster",
      "D. Tebucky Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What New England Patriots player was named AP Defensive Rookie of the Year for 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerod Mayo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Logan Mankins",
      "B. Jerod Mayo",
      "C. Vince Wilfork",
      "D. Terry Glenn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first Super Bowl MVP for the New England Patriots?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Brady",
    "choices": [
      "A. Drew Bledsoe",
      "B. Randy Moss",
      "C. Deion Branch",
      "D. Tom Brady"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kobe Bryant said on TNT that he wanted this jersey number as a rookie in the 2006-2007 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "24",
    "choices": [
      "A. 24",
      "B. 33",
      "C. 12",
      "D. 19"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what NBA season was Kobe Bryant awarded the regular seasons MVP Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2007-08",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000-01",
      "B. 2007-08",
      "C. 2005-06",
      "D. 1998-1999"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did Kobe Bryant get drafted by in 1996?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hornets",
    "choices": [
      "A. LA Lakers",
      "B. Hornets",
      "C. Nets",
      "D. Suns"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many consecutive NBA championships did Kobe Bryant win with the Lakers in the early 2000s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Kobe Bryants dads nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jellybean",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jellybean",
      "B. Highflyer",
      "C. Hot Hands",
      "D. The Philadelphia Prolific"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did Kobe Bryant take to his senior prom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brandy Norwood",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brittany Spears",
      "B. Jessica Simpson",
      "C. Brandy Norwood",
      "D. Jessica Alba"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Kobe Bryant first become a member of the USA Mens Senior Olympics Team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2008",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2004",
      "B. 1996",
      "C. 2000",
      "D. 2008"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is Kobe Bryants nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Black Mamba",
    "choices": [
      "A. Beef",
      "B. Black Mamba",
      "C. The Kid",
      "D. Jellybean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What name was given to the London 2012 Olympic Games Opening Ceremony that took place on 27 July 2012?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Isles of Wonder",
    "choices": [
      "A. Beautiful Olympics",
      "B. Games of Courage",
      "C. Isles of Wonder",
      "D. Isles of Inspiration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Danny Boyle, the artistic director of 2012 Summer Olympics Opening Ceremony, won an Academy Award for which of the following movies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Slumdog Millionaire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shallow Grave",
      "B. Slumdog Millionaire",
      "C. 28 Days Later",
      "D. Trainspotting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On July 27 2012, Queen Elizabeth II opened the Olympic Games for the second time in her reign. When was the first time she opened the Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Montreal, Canada 1976",
    "choices": [
      "A. Munich, West Germany 1972",
      "B. Sidney, Australia 2000",
      "C. Montreal, Canada 1976",
      "D. Rome, Italy 1960"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who played James Bond in the BBC short film, Happy and Glorious, which stars Queen Elizabeth II as herself?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Daniel Craig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Daniel Craig",
      "B. Timothy Dalton",
      "C. Pierce Brosnan",
      "D. None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team led the Parade of Nations at the 2012 Summer Olympic Games Opening Ceremony?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the team of Greece",
    "choices": [
      "A. the team of Greece",
      "B. the team of Afghanistan",
      "C. the team of Great Britain",
      "D. the team of China"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the slogan of the 2012 Summer Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Inspire a Generation",
    "choices": [
      "A. Inspire a Generation",
      "B. One World, One Dream",
      "C. Friends Forever",
      "D. Share the Spirit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What song was used at the climax of the 2012 Summer Olympics opening ceremony, immediately following the lighting of the cauldron?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eclipse by Pink Floyd",
    "choices": [
      "A. Another Brick in the Wall by Pink Floyd",
      "B. Beautiful Day by U2",
      "C. Eclipse by Pink Floyd",
      "D. Rolling in the Deep by Adele"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 2012 Summer Olympic Games Opening Ceremony, this celebrity was seen driving a motor boat down the River Thames and under Tower Bridge to the music I Heard Wonders by David Holmes.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Beckham",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ryan Giggs",
      "B. David Beckham",
      "C. Moris Green",
      "D. Rowan Sebastian Atkinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A segment of the London 2012 Opening Ceremony paid tribute to the victims of this terrorist attack.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the 2005 London Bombings",
    "choices": [
      "A. All of these",
      "B. the 1972 Munich Massacre",
      "C. the 18 July 2012 terrorist attack on Israeli tourists in Bourgas, Bulgaria",
      "D. the 2005 London Bombings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Paul McCartney closed the opening ceremony of the 2012 Summer Olympics singing this song and inviting the audience to join in on the coda.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hey Jude",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hey Jude",
      "B. Let It Be",
      "C. Yesterday",
      "D. Live and Let Die"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Jeff Hardy got suspended for 60 days in May 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "For illegal drug use",
    "choices": [
      "A. For illegal drug use",
      "B. Not showing for a match",
      "C. He has never been suspended.",
      "D. None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year was Jeff Hardy released from WWE because of his erratic behavior, drug use, and refusal to go to rehab?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2003",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2007",
      "B. 2001",
      "C. 2003",
      "D. 2000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Jeff Hardy make his WWE debut?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1998",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1997",
      "B. 1998",
      "C. 1996",
      "D. 1995"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Jeff Hardys favorite sport besides wrestling?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Motocross",
    "choices": [
      "A. Basketball",
      "B. Motocross",
      "C. Snowboarding",
      "D. Football"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Shane Battier born and raised?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Birmingham, Michigan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Birmingham, Michigan",
      "B. Cleveland, Ohio",
      "C. Detroit, Michigan",
      "D. Madison, Wisconsin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What position did Shane Battier play at Duke?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Small Forward",
    "choices": [
      "A. Center",
      "B. Point Guard",
      "C. Power Forward",
      "D. Small Forward"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did the Duke Blue Devils beat in 2001 to win the NCAA National Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arizona Wildcats",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maryland Terrapins",
      "B. Michigan State Spartans",
      "C. University of Southern California Trojans",
      "D. Arizona Wildcats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What award did Shane Battier win in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "National Player of the Year",
    "choices": [
      "A. National Defender of the Year",
      "B. ACC Scorer of the Year",
      "C. National Player of the Year",
      "D. ACC Defender of the Year"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shane Battier had his number retired at Duke. What was his number?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "31",
    "choices": [
      "A. 23",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 31",
      "D. 5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Shane Battier major in at Duke?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Religion",
    "choices": [
      "A. Music",
      "B. Mathematics",
      "C. Religion",
      "D. Political Science"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team was Shane Battier selected by in the 2001 NBA draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Memphis Grizzlies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington Wizards",
      "B. Memphis Grizzlies",
      "C. Houston Rockets",
      "D. Miami Heat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team was Shane Battier traded to in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Houston Rockets",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston Rockets",
      "B. New Orleans Hornets",
      "C. Boston Celtics",
      "D. Atlanta Hawks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shane Battier appeared on the cover of what video game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NCAA March Madness 2002",
    "choices": [
      "A. NBA Live 2007",
      "B. NCAA March Madness 2001",
      "C. NCAA March Madness 2002",
      "D. NBA Live 2006"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tinku sounds like the noise my old car made but its not. What phrase would you connect with this art?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Potosi region of Bolivia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mexican professional wrestling",
      "B. Potosi region of Bolivia",
      "C. Founded in 1980 by Robert Puch",
      "D. African slaves in Brazil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kajukenbo is not a computer game. What statement best suits this form of martial art?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It originated on the territory of Hawaii, USA",
    "choices": [
      "A. It originated on the territory of Hawaii, USA",
      "B. It was developed by Morihei Ueshiba.",
      "C. It is the art of espionage.",
      "D. It means Way of the Sword."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true about Hwa Rang Do in Korea?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "it means The Way of the Flowering Knights",
    "choices": [
      "A. it means The Way of the Flowering Knights",
      "B. It originated in the kingdom of Gogoryeo",
      "C. It is a system of 18 techniques.",
      "D. it is used by members of the Royal Court and traveling monks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true about the Asian martial art Lethwei?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is unarmed Burmese martial art.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was created by the Chinese community of SE Asia.",
      "B. It was developed in Hue, Vietnam.",
      "C. It is a Filipino foot fight.",
      "D. It is unarmed Burmese martial art."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Glima sounds like a nasty disease but it really is what?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Icelandic term for wrestling",
    "choices": [
      "A. acronym for a style of Russian fighting",
      "B. unarmed combat from the Holy Roman Empire",
      "C. technique of stick fighting",
      "D. Icelandic term for wrestling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is specific to the stick fighting known as Istunka?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It is a martial arts festival in Somalia.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It comes from Southern Sudan.",
      "B. It is practiced by herd boys.",
      "C. It uses fire-hardened sticks.",
      "D. It is a martial arts festival in Somalia."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bok-Fu or Bok Fu Do sounds akin to Kung-Fu but it really fits this description.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It translates to White Tiger.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It is a type of Chinese Wushu.",
      "B. It translates to White Tiger.",
      "C. It means means to bear a weapon.",
      "D. It is a Persian martial art."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement is true about Sli Beatha?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was founded in 1996 by police officer Craig Smith.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was founded in 1996 by police officer Craig Smith.",
      "B. It is performed while brandishing a dirk.",
      "C. It means face to face combat.",
      "D. It means stick fighting in Irish martial arts."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kbach Kun Boran and Kbach Kun Dambong Veng are associated with which country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cambodia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Thailand",
      "B. Vietnam",
      "C. Myanmar (Burma)",
      "D. Cambodia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Schwingen is considered a national sport in this country and takes this form.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Switzerland - grappling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Germany - grappling",
      "B. Austria - grappling without touching the legs",
      "C. Switzerland - grappling",
      "D. Germany - grappling with swords"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Red Bulls MLS team based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington DC",
      "B. Los Angeles",
      "C. New York",
      "D. Houston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "United is an American professional soccer club located in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington DC",
    "choices": [
      "A. Washington DC",
      "B. Chicago",
      "C. Dallas",
      "D. Boston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city does the Fire MLS team play in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston",
      "B. Seattle",
      "C. Chicago",
      "D. New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what city is the Sounders team based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Seattle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seattle",
      "B. Los Angeles",
      "C. Miami",
      "D. Philadelphia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Union is an American professional soccer team based in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Philadelphia",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York",
      "B. Philadelphia",
      "C. Houston",
      "D. Toronto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what city is the Crew MLS team based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Columbus",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Antonio",
      "B. Boston",
      "C. Columbus",
      "D. Toronto"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is Club Deportivo Chivas USA based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carson",
      "B. Kansas City",
      "C. Seattle",
      "D. Boston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Wizards team based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas City",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miami",
      "B. Kansas City",
      "C. Washington D.C.",
      "D. Boston"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the New England Revolution team based?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Foxborough",
    "choices": [
      "A. Houston",
      "B. Foxborough",
      "C. Salt Lake",
      "D. New York"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Dynamo is an MLS team based in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Houston",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas",
      "B. Cleveland",
      "C. Houston",
      "D. Portland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Chicgao Blackhawks selected this player with the first overall pick in the 2007 NHL Entry Draft.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Patrick Kane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marian Hossa",
      "B. Jonathan Toews",
      "C. Patrick Kane",
      "D. Duncan Keith"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the ice hockey team based in Stillwater, Minnesota?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Stllwater Ponies",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Stllwater Tigers",
      "B. The Stllwater Rockets",
      "C. The Stllwater Ponies",
      "D. The Stllwater Stallions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became coach of the Minnesota Wild in the 2009-2010 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Todd Richards",
    "choices": [
      "A. Todd Richards",
      "B. Jacques Lemaire",
      "C. Brad Bomadiar",
      "D. Phil Housley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, who joined the Minnesota Wild in the 2001â2002 NHL season, is nicknamed Bruno.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Andrew Brunette",
    "choices": [
      "A. Andrew Brunette",
      "B. Pierre Marc-Bouchard",
      "C. Cal Clutterbuck",
      "D. Mikko Koivu"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did Alex Goligoski join in 2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "None of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis Blues",
      "B. Pittsburgh Penguins",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. New York Islanders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these teams did Wayne Gretzky play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles Kings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Los Angeles Kings",
      "B. Pittsburgh Penguins",
      "C. Detroit Red Wings",
      "D. Chicago Blackhawks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Martin Broduer started his professional career with this ice hockey team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Jersey Devils",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pittsburgh Penguins",
      "B. New York Rangers",
      "C. New York Islander",
      "D. New Jersey Devils"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sidney Crosbys Pittsburgh Penguins jersey was the top seller on the NHLs website from September 2005 to February 2008. What number was it?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "87",
    "choices": [
      "A. 77",
      "B. 17",
      "C. 87",
      "D. 67"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 2006â07 Ashes series, which batsman took the single winning run as Australia dashed to a 5-0 whitewash against England for the first time in 86 years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mathew Hayden",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mathew Hayden",
      "B. Adam Gilchrist",
      "C. Ricky Ponting",
      "D. Justin Langer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Australian players was NOT playing the last test of his career in the 5th-and the final-test of the 2006-07 Ashes series as Australia concluded the series 5-0?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mathew Hayden",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shane Warne",
      "B. Justin Langer",
      "C. Glenn McGrath",
      "D. Mathew Hayden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the fourth test, at the Melbourne Cricket Ground (MCG), Australian leg-spinner Shane Warne snared his 700th wicket, the first bowler in Test history to do so. Who did he bowl out?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Andrew Strauss",
    "choices": [
      "A. Andrew Flintoff",
      "B. Andrew Strauss",
      "C. Chris Read",
      "D. Paul Collingwod"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English batsman took six catches in the first innings of the fourth test of the 2006â07 cricket series, becoming only the third player in Test history to do so?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Read",
    "choices": [
      "A. Paul Collingwood",
      "B. Paul Nixon",
      "C. Chris Read",
      "D. Geraint Jones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "By scoring 206 runs in the first innings of the second test of the 2006â07 Ashes series, he became only the third Englishman to score a double-century in Australia. Can you name him?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul Collingwood",
    "choices": [
      "A. Andrew Strauss",
      "B. Paul Collingwood",
      "C. Marcus Trescothick",
      "D. Kevin Pietersen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the third Ashes test, Adam Gilchristâs century in the second innings became the second fastest century in any test match and the fastest in any Ashes test. How many balls did his century score off?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "57",
    "choices": [
      "A. 47",
      "B. 67",
      "C. 77",
      "D. 57"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2006â07 Ashes series was notable for the retirement of several Australian players. Additionally, the Australian coach also announced prior to the Ashes series that the Ashes 2006-07 was his last series of test matches as coach. What was the name of the Australian coach?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Buchanan",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Buchanan",
      "B. Bob Simpsons",
      "C. Gary Kristen",
      "D. Geoff Marsh"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the first innings of the fifth test of the 2006-07 Ashes series, Australia amassed 393 all out. Surprisingly, in the second innings they needed only 46 runs to clinch the final test. By how many wickets did Australia win the match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 8",
      "D. 10"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Spanish football team is nicknamed Los Cules, or The Bottoms?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "FC Barcelona",
    "choices": [
      "A. Real Oviedo",
      "B. Valencia",
      "C. FC Barcelona",
      "D. Real Madrid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What interesting nickname was given to Spanish football club Atletico Madrid?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mattress Makers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dish Washers",
      "B. Mattress Makers",
      "C. Carpet Cleaners",
      "D. Leg Warmers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of the Italian football club Napoli?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Donkey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rooster",
      "B. Horse",
      "C. Ram",
      "D. Donkey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What delicious nickname is used to refer to the English football club Everton?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Toffees",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Truffles",
      "B. The Caramels",
      "C. The Toffees",
      "D. The Chocolates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What German football club is nicknamed The Hollywood Football Club?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "FC Bayern Munich",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eintracht Frankfurt",
      "B. Hamburger SV",
      "C. FC St. Pauli",
      "D. FC Bayern Munich"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What European football club has been nicknamed The Yellow Submarine?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Villarreal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Villarreal",
      "B. Nantes",
      "C. Liverpool",
      "D. Chelsea"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of the Arsenal F.C. English football club?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Gunners",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Rifles",
      "B. The Revolvers",
      "C. The Spikes",
      "D. The Gunners"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Italian football team is known by the nickname Il Grifone, or The Griffin?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Genoa",
    "choices": [
      "A. Inter",
      "B. Juventus",
      "C. Genoa",
      "D. Parma"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What nickname was given to the Italian football club AC Milan?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Devil",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Demon",
      "B. The Icon",
      "C. The Angel",
      "D. The Devil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English football team has been nicknamed The Pensioners?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chelsea",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tottenham Hotspur",
      "B. Manchester United",
      "C. Chelsea",
      "D. Liverpool"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Bobby Fischer born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago, Illinois",
    "choices": [
      "A. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania",
      "B. Boston, Massachusetts",
      "C. Atlanta, Georgia",
      "D. Chicago, Illinois"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bobby Fischer was a member of this church/denomination.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Worldwide Church of God",
    "choices": [
      "A. Unitarian Universalist",
      "B. Worldwide Church of God",
      "C. Jehovahs Witnesses",
      "D. First United Methodist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Bobby Fischer become the world chess champion?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1972",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1968",
      "B. 1972",
      "C. 1978",
      "D. 1977"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1992, after 20 years of isolation, Bobby Fischer re-emerged to play a match against this player in Yugoslavia.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Spassky",
    "choices": [
      "A. Berlitz",
      "B. Karpov",
      "C. Spassky",
      "D. Kasparov"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On a radio show in Budapest, Hungary in 1999, Bobby Fischer described himself as a victim of which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "An international Jewish conspiracy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Assassination attempts by the CIA",
      "B. Child abuse",
      "C. A black magic curse",
      "D. An international Jewish conspiracy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1988 Bobby Fischer filed a U.S. patent for what?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "a digital chess clock",
    "choices": [
      "A. a type of laptop computer",
      "B. a rechargeable battery",
      "C. a software program",
      "D. a digital chess clock"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was Bobby Fischer detained at Narita international airport in Narita, Japan in 2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Using a revoked U.S. passport",
    "choices": [
      "A. Possession of a firearm",
      "B. Possession of marijuana",
      "C. Using a revoked U.S. passport",
      "D. Making comments about committing terrorism"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After being detained in Japan in 2004, Bobby Fischer was granted citizenship in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Iceland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Iceland",
      "B. Italy",
      "C. Poland",
      "D. Germany"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1984, Bobby Fischer wrote to the editors of this publication to have his name removed from it.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Encyclopedia Judaica",
    "choices": [
      "A. Encyclopedia Britannica",
      "B. Encyclopedia Americana",
      "C. Encyclopedia Judaica",
      "D. Colliers encyclopedia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Bobby Fischer win the United States Junior Chess Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "July 1956",
    "choices": [
      "A. July 1956",
      "B. August 1954",
      "C. January 1960",
      "D. April 1959"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what country did Joseph Pilates develop the exercise system Pilates?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Germany",
    "choices": [
      "A. Switzerland",
      "B. Greece",
      "C. Germany",
      "D. USA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Pilates based on?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yoga and Aerobics",
    "choices": [
      "A. Body Building and Yoga",
      "B. Yoga and Aerobics",
      "C. Yoga and Gymnastics",
      "D. Aerobics and Meditation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When Joseph Pilates moved to England at the age of 32, what did he do for a living?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was a boxer.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was a banker.",
      "B. He was a professor.",
      "C. He was a physical therapist.",
      "D. He was a boxer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pilates coordinates your movements with which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "your breathing",
    "choices": [
      "A. your partners movements",
      "B. your balance",
      "C. your strength",
      "D. your breathing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joseph Pilates used this term to refer to the muscle group comprised of the abs, buttocks, lower back and hips. All the energy begins in this group and flows outward.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Powerhouse",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Shell",
      "B. The Panel",
      "C. The Powerhouse",
      "D. The Engine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not a reported benefit of Pilates?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Decreased appetite",
    "choices": [
      "A. Decreased appetite",
      "B. Improved flexibility",
      "C. Improved Posture",
      "D. Decreased back pain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Though not necessary, there are several pieces of apparatus that can be used in a Pilates work out. Which of these is not used in Pilates?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Balance Beam",
    "choices": [
      "A. Balance Beam",
      "B. Floor mat",
      "C. Large exercise balls",
      "D. Resistance Bands"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Approximately how many people claimed to regularly practice Pilates in the United States according to a 2008 survey?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3,500,000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 500,000",
      "B. 12,000",
      "C. 3,500,000",
      "D. 10,000,000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the Missouri Tigers first conference championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1917-18",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1917-18",
      "B. 1920-21",
      "C. 1929-30",
      "D. 1975-76"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is known as the father Missouri Tiger Basketball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Norm Stewart",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Anderson",
      "B. Don Faurot",
      "C. Norm Stewart",
      "D. Warren Hearnes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Norm Stewart win his first Conference Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1976",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1987",
      "B. 1981",
      "C. 1994",
      "D. 1976"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Missouri coach Mike Anderson served as an assistant for a 17-years?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Arkansas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tulsa",
      "B. University of Arkansas",
      "C. University of Alabama at Birmingham",
      "D. University of Missouri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the real first name of golf champion Tiger Woods?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eldrick",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ewan",
      "B. Eldrick",
      "C. Edward",
      "D. Edwin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was Tiger Woods nicknamed Tiger when he was younger?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He got the nickname from a Vietnamese soldier.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Because he was a womanizer",
      "B. He got the nickname from a Vietnamese soldier.",
      "C. All of these",
      "D. Because he was very fast"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What religion did Tiger Woods acquire from his mother, Kultida Woods?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Buddhism",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roman Catholicism",
      "B. Buddhism",
      "C. Protestantism",
      "D. Islam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Tiger Woods first-born child, who was born on June 18, 2007?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sam",
    "choices": [
      "A. Elin",
      "B. Michaela",
      "C. Christine",
      "D. Sam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Tiger Woods was undoubtedly a child prodigy. At what age did he start playing golf?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Two",
    "choices": [
      "A. Seven",
      "B. Five",
      "C. Two",
      "D. Four"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the beginning of his professional golf career, Tiger Woods signed a contract with this sports equipment giant.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nike",
    "choices": [
      "A. Adidas",
      "B. Puma",
      "C. Kappa",
      "D. Nike"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How is Tiger Woods playing style often described?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cautious",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cautious",
      "B. Aggressive",
      "C. Energetic",
      "D. Confident"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What were the initial aims of The Tiger Woods Foundation?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Helping disadvantaged children",
    "choices": [
      "A. Helping erase poverty and hunger in Africa",
      "B. Helping AIDS patients",
      "C. Helping save endangered animals",
      "D. Helping disadvantaged children"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the title of the book written by Tiger Woods in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "How I Play Golf",
    "choices": [
      "A. How To Be A Tiger",
      "B. Be The Best",
      "C. How I Play Golf",
      "D. The Way Of The Golf Ball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Tiger Woods undergo surgery in 1994?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He had a tumor.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He had a tumor.",
      "B. He donated one of his kidneys.",
      "C. He suffered from appendicitis.",
      "D. He had rhinoplasty."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Football player Diego Maradona was born on October 30, 1960 in this country.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Argentina",
    "choices": [
      "A. Portugal",
      "B. Colombia",
      "C. Argentina",
      "D. Brazil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Italian football player turned out to be the first-born son of football star Diego Armando Maradona?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Diego Sinagra",
    "choices": [
      "A. Diego Sinagra",
      "B. Diego Anjel",
      "C. Diego Aguero",
      "D. Diego Christiano"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the reason for Diego Maradonas fading health after the end of his professional football career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Drug addiction",
    "choices": [
      "A. All of these",
      "B. Hereditary ailments",
      "C. Drug addiction",
      "D. HIV infection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of surgery did football star Diego Maradona undergo on March 6, 2005?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gastric bypass surgery",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gastric bypass surgery",
      "B. Knee surgery",
      "C. Plastic surgery",
      "D. Brain surgery"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What recognition did Diego Maradona receive in 2000?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was voted FIFA Best Football Player of the Century",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was voted Best Player of the FIFA World Cup.",
      "B. He was voted Sportsman of the Year",
      "C. He was voted FIFA Best Football Player of the Century",
      "D. He was voted Best Footballer in the World."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first European football team for which Diego Maradona played professionally?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barcelona",
    "choices": [
      "A. Barcelona",
      "B. Real Madrid",
      "C. Napoli",
      "D. Sevilla"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many goals did Diego Maradona manage to score throughout his professional career, from 1976 to 1997?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "258 goals",
    "choices": [
      "A. 564 goals",
      "B. 258 goals",
      "C. 198 goals",
      "D. 1000 goals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What interesting name was given to the goal scored by Diego Maradona in 1986 at the FIFA World Cup quarter-final in Mexico between Argentina and England?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hand of God",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hand of God",
      "B. Head of Jesus",
      "C. Hand of an angel",
      "D. Arm of St. Paul"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What institution was founded on October 30, 1998 in the city of Rosario, Santa Fe, Argentina in honor of football legend Diego Maradona?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Church of Maradona",
    "choices": [
      "A. All of these",
      "B. Bureau of Maradona",
      "C. Church of Maradona",
      "D. University of Maradona"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Diego Maradona became friends with this political leader and even tattooed hit portrait on his left leg.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fidel Castro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fidel Castro",
      "B. George H. W. Bush",
      "C. Mikhail Gorbachev",
      "D. Lech Walesa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1890 MIZZOU played its first football game against whom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Washington University",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nebraska",
      "B. Illinois",
      "C. Washington University",
      "D. Kansas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is Mizzous arch rival in all sports?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas Jayhawks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Illinois",
      "B. Nebraska",
      "C. Kansas Jayhawks",
      "D. Oklahoma"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first 20 games of the Tiger/ Jayhawk rivalry were played off campus in Kansas City or in St Joesph. The Tigers hosted the first game on campus in 1911. What is significant about this game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was the first Homecoming game in the country.",
    "choices": [
      "A. There was  a riot after the game.",
      "B. a 3 to 3 tie",
      "C. The game was played at Rollins field.",
      "D. It was the first Homecoming game in the country."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who replaced coach Don Faurot when he retired in 1956?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Frank Broyles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Onofrio",
      "B. Dan Devine",
      "C. Frank Broyles",
      "D. Chauncey Simpson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1990 the Colorado Buffaloes beat the Tigers due to which of the following?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Both of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. bad officiating",
      "B. Both of these",
      "C. a fifth down",
      "D. None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1978 the Missouri Tigers travelled to Nebraska and won 35-31. What year was the next Tiger victory over Nebraska ?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2003",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1992",
      "B. 1983",
      "C. 1988",
      "D. 2003"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Hall of Fame coach was with the Tigers from 1958-1970?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dan Devine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Faurot",
      "B. Andy Reid",
      "C. Don Shula",
      "D. Dan Devine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former Missouri Tiger players has the most super bowl rings?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eric Wright",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eric Wright",
      "B. Johnny Roland",
      "C. Tony Galbreath",
      "D. Chase Daniel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the worst defeat by points that the Missouri Tigers had during the 20th century?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "77-0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 77-0",
      "B. 69-0",
      "C. 49-3",
      "D. 56-0"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What player quarterbacked the Missouri Tigers in the 1997 Holiday Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Corby Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chase Daniel",
      "B. Corby Jones",
      "C. Brad Smith",
      "D. Brad Perry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Nobody knows for sure why Love means nothing on a tennis court. Which of these theories is NOT one of the common theories of where this usage originated?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Love is a more pleasant word than zero. Since tennis is a highly civilized sport, love evolved as a tactful way of denoting a score zero.",
    "choices": [
      "A. In the Dutch phrase, iets voor lof doen (to do something for nothing), lof means nothing.",
      "B. In French, Lheure means The hour. Since some people think that the 15-30-40 scoring refers to 15, 30 and 40 minutes after the hour, the hour might mean zero.",
      "C. In French, Loeuf means Egg and an egg is in the shape of a zero.",
      "D. Love is a more pleasant word than zero. Since tennis is a highly civilized sport, love evolved as a tactful way of denoting a score zero."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lets say John and Judy are playing a mixed doubles match against Mary and Mike. Its Marys turn to serve. She starts the game by serving to Judy. Mary and Mike win the point. Now the score is 15-love. For the next point, who serves to whom?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mary serves to John.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mary serves to Judy again.",
      "B. Mike serves to John.",
      "C. Mary serves to John.",
      "D. Mike serves to Judy."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 3 of the 4 major tennis tournaments, the deciding set of the match (5th set for men, 3rd set for women) does not utilize a tie break if the score is tied at 6-6. In which of these tournaments is a tie break used even in the deciding set of a match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "U.S. Open",
    "choices": [
      "A. French Open",
      "B. U.S. Open",
      "C. Australian Open",
      "D. Wimbledon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In tennis, how much time does the server have between the time the previous point ends and the time he/she serves the ball for the next point, to avoid being cited by the umpire for delaying the game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "20 seconds",
    "choices": [
      "A. 25 seconds",
      "B. 20 seconds",
      "C. 40 seconds",
      "D. 30 seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lets say your opponent hits a shot to your side of the net, but he hits it so far over to one side of the tennis court that, when you finally get to it, youre way off to the side of the court. You hit the ball so that it goes around the outside of the net, landing in your opponents court. Your shot did not go over the net. Rather, it went around the net. Your opponent then misses the shot. Who wins the point, if anybody?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "You win the point. Its not required to hit the ball over the net. It can go over the net or around it.",
    "choices": [
      "A. You win the point. Its not required to hit the ball over the net. It can go over the net or around it.",
      "B. Nobody wins the point. This is a let. The point is played over.",
      "C. Your opponent wins the point. Your shot around the outside of the net was not a legal shot.  The tennis ball has to go over the net to be in play.",
      "D. This situation is impossible. It isnt physically possible to hit the ball around the outside of the net."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your opponent in tennis hits a drop shot. It lands just on your side of the net. You run as fast as you can to get to it. Your opponent has hit it with so much slice (back-spin) that, before you can get to it, it bounces back over to his side of the net. Your opponent then hits the ball out of bounds. Who wins the point, if anybody, and why?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Your opponent wins the point, because you failed to hit the ball back to his side of the net when he hit the drop shot.",
    "choices": [
      "A. You win the point, because your opponents previous shot, the drop-shot which bounced back over to his side of the court, was an illegal shot.",
      "B. Nobody wins the point. Its a let. Whenever a hit ball bounces on one side of the net and goes back to the other side of the net without being hit back, the point is played over.",
      "C. You win the point, because your opponent hit the ball out.",
      "D. Your opponent wins the point, because you failed to hit the ball back to his side of the net when he hit the drop shot."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you hit the tennis ball toward your opponent, and hes standing at the net, and he reaches over the net and hits the ball before it crosses over the net to his side of the court, and it lands in your court, and then you hit it out of bounds, who wins the point and why?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "You win the point because your opponent hit the ball before it crossed into his side of the court.",
    "choices": [
      "A. You win the point because your opponents racket crossed over the net into your court.",
      "B. Your opponent wins the point because he was able to hit the ball before it got to his side of the net.",
      "C. You win the point because your opponent hit the ball before it crossed into his side of the court.",
      "D. Your opponent wins the point because you hit it out."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lets say you hit the ball so hard back to your opponent that it hits him in the chest. He does not hit the ball back. Who wins the point, and why?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "You win the point because your opponent touched the ball with his body.",
    "choices": [
      "A. You win the point because your opponent touched the ball with his body.",
      "B. Your opponent wins the point because you used unnecessary force.",
      "C. You win the point because your opponent didnt hit the ball back to your side of the court.",
      "D. Your opponent wins the point because you engaged in unsportsmanlike conduct."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the sequence of serves in a 7-point tie-break?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Player A serves to the deuce court. Player B then serves to the Ad court. Player B then serves to the deuce court. Player A then serves to the Ad court.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Player A serves to the deuce court. Player A then serves to the Ad court. Player B then serves to the deuce court. Player B then serves to the Ad court.",
      "B. Player A serves to the deuce court. Player B then serves to the Ad court. Player B then serves to the deuce court. Player A then serves to the Ad court.",
      "C. Player A serves to the Ad court. Player B then serves to the deuce court. Player B then serves to the Ad court. Player A then serves to the deuce court.",
      "D. Player A serves to the deuce court. Player B then serves to the Ad court. Player A then serves to the Ad court. Player B then serves to the deuce court."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When was Italian football club A.C. Milan founded?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "16 December 1899",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12 March 1900",
      "B. 16 December 1899",
      "C. 29 November 1899",
      "D. 22 January 1900"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the color of A.C. Milans home jersey?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "red and black stripes",
    "choices": [
      "A. all white",
      "B. green and yellow",
      "C. red and black stripes",
      "D. all black"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who acquired soccer club A.C. Milan in 1986?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Silvio Berlusconi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Silvio Berlusconi",
      "B. Benito Craxi",
      "C. Joy Damato",
      "D. Tinto Brass"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This football player, who spent his entire career with Serie A club A.C. Milan, has been acknowledged as one of the greatest defenders ever to play the game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Franco Baresi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Franco Baresi",
      "B. Andrey Shevshenko",
      "C. Hernan Crespo",
      "D. Kaka"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which A.C Milan former player was close to becoming president of his native country?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Weah",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Weah",
      "B. Cesare Maldini",
      "C. Cafu",
      "D. marco Van Basten"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these famous Italians are known as A.C Milan fans?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Laura Pausini and Cristina Scabbia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Laura Pausini and Cristina Scabbia",
      "B. Mussolini and Gratsiani",
      "C. Luciano Pavarotti and Luca Damiano",
      "D. Verdi and Rafaelo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did AC Milan win their first UEFA champions league final?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1963",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1970",
      "B. 1980",
      "C. 1963",
      "D. 1945"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which company became A.C. Milans main sponsor during the 2010/2011 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fly Emirates",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bwin",
      "B. Opel",
      "C. Fly Emirates",
      "D. Pierelli"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Players from which country did NOT play for A.C. Milan from the foundation of the club until the 2010/2011 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Serbia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brazil",
      "B. Sweden",
      "C. Serbia",
      "D. Netherlands"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what Arabian country has A.C. Milan played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. Qatar",
      "B. Saudi Arabia",
      "C. United Arabian Emirates",
      "D. All of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first womens title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alundra Blayze Vs Bertha Faye",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alundra Blayze Vs Bertha Faye",
      "B. Melina Vs Mickie James",
      "C. Fabulous Moohlah Vs Wendi Richter",
      "D. Trish Stratus Vs Lita"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first tag team title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Demolition Vs The Hart Foundation",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hart Foundation Vs Legion of Doom",
      "B. Andre The Giant And Haku Vs Legion of Doom",
      "C. Demolition Vs The Hart Foundation",
      "D. Andre The Giant and Haku Vs Demolition"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first WWE title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bret Hart Vs The Undertaker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bret Hart Vs The Undertaker",
      "B. Shawn Micheals Vs Vader",
      "C. Hulk Hogan Vs Zues",
      "D. Randy Savage Vs Ric Flair"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the fist IC Title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Ultimate Warrior Vs Honky Tonk Man",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ultimate Warrior Vs Randy Savage",
      "B. The Ultimate Warrior Vs Hercules",
      "C. The Ultimate Warrior Vs Honky Tonk Man",
      "D. Ultimate Warrior Vs Rick Rude"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first European title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "D-Lo Brown Vs Jeff Jarrett",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Snow Vs Val Venis",
      "B. Triple H Vs Shawn Michaels",
      "C. Triple H Vs Jeff Jarrett",
      "D. D-Lo Brown Vs Jeff Jarrett"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first Hardcore title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Al Snow Vs Bossman",
    "choices": [
      "A. Crash Holly Vs Mean Street Posse",
      "B. Bossman Vs Hardcore Holly",
      "C. Al Snow Vs Bossman",
      "D. Hardcore Holly Vs Crash Holly"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the fist US title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chris Benoit Vs Orlando Jordan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chris Benoit Vs Chris Jericho",
      "B. John Cena Vs Booker T",
      "C. Chris Benoit Vs Orlando Jordan",
      "D. John Cena Vs Carlito"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first Unification title match at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lightweight Champion X-Pac Vs Cruiserweight Champion Tajiri",
    "choices": [
      "A. WWE World Tag Champions The Undertaker  Kane Vs WCW Tag Champions DDP  Kanyon",
      "B. WWE Champion C.M. Punk Vs WWE champion John Cena",
      "C. IC Champion Jeff Jarrett Vs Euorpeon Champion D-Lo Brown",
      "D. Lightweight Champion X-Pac Vs Cruiserweight Champion Tajiri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first title to change hand in a ladder match at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hardcore",
    "choices": [
      "A. IC",
      "B. Hardcore",
      "C. WWE",
      "D. European"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the fist WCW/World title change at SummerSlam?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Rock Vs Booker T",
    "choices": [
      "A. Randy Orton Vs Chris Benoit",
      "B. C.M.Punk Vs Jeff Hardy",
      "C. Triple H Vs Shawn Michaels",
      "D. The Rock Vs Booker T"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capacity of the Twickenham Stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "82,000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 97,000",
      "B. 82,000",
      "C. 67,000",
      "D. 75,000"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Premier teams home ground is nearest to Twickenham Stadium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harlequins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wasps",
      "B. Harlequins",
      "C. Saracens",
      "D. London Irish"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Erica Roe is famous for her streak at Twickenham Stadium in 1982. But who were England playing against?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Australia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ireland",
      "B. Wales",
      "C. France",
      "D. Australia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rugby player Tim Rodber, of Northampton and England, was a member of which of the British armed forces?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Army",
    "choices": [
      "A. Royal Marines",
      "B. The Army",
      "C. Royal Air Force",
      "D. Royal Navy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The team that became Gloucester RFC played their first game on this site in 1873, which was later developed as the clubs home.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kingsholm",
    "choices": [
      "A. Franklins Gardens",
      "B. Queensholm",
      "C. The Shed",
      "D. Kingsholm"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English Premier rugby teams ground is furthest north?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Newcastle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Newcastle",
      "B. Leeds",
      "C. Glasgow",
      "D. Sale"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the previous name of the club that became Harlequins in 1860?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hampstead Football Club",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hampstead Football Club",
      "B. Hanwell Football Club",
      "C. Hanworth Football Club",
      "D. Harrow Football Club"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Several Rugby clubs play their home games at stadiums which are also used for football (soccer). Where do Saracens play their home matches?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vicarage Road",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vicarage Road",
      "B. Loftus Road",
      "C. Adams Park",
      "D. The Emirates Stadium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 2007/08 season, Wasps play their home matches at Adams Park. In which Buckinghamshire town is it located?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "High Wycombe",
    "choices": [
      "A. High Wycombe",
      "B. Aylesbury",
      "C. Milton Keynes",
      "D. Bletchley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Travis Pastrana born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Annapolis, Maryland",
    "choices": [
      "A. Los Angeles, California",
      "B. Annapolis, Maryland",
      "C. Provedence, Rode Island",
      "D. Branson, Missouri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What nationality is Travis Pastranas father?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Puerto Rican",
    "choices": [
      "A. Italian",
      "B. Puerto Rican",
      "C. Cuban",
      "D. Mexican"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number do Travis Pastranas motorcycles carry?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "199",
    "choices": [
      "A. 199",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 183",
      "D. 123"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Travis Pastrana when he separated his spine from his pelvis as a result of a serious injury?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 16",
      "C. 14",
      "D. 19"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Travis Pastrana when he won his first X Games gold metal?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "15",
    "choices": [
      "A. 13",
      "B. 15",
      "C. 22",
      "D. 18"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What gas is the most abundant gas in the atmospheric air we breathe every day?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nitrogen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carbon Dioxide",
      "B. Helium",
      "C. Oxygen",
      "D. Nitrogen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you blow up a balloon to a volume of one liter of air at the surface, and then take the balloon down to a depth of 10 meters, what will happen?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The balloon will decrease in volume to 1/2 liter.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The balloon will completely collapse.",
      "B. The balloon will blow up.",
      "C. The balloon will decrease in volume to 1/2 liter.",
      "D. The balloon will increase in volume to 2 liters."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What device reduces the pressure in the cylinder to the pressure of the surroundings, so that the diver will always be breathing in air at the appropriate pressure of the current depth?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The regulator",
    "choices": [
      "A. The submersible pressure gauge",
      "B. The regulator",
      "C. The buoyancy compensator",
      "D. The mask"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Under what circumstances is it okay to touch underwater creatures?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Under no circumstances should you touch underwater creatures.",
    "choices": [
      "A. You can touch underwater creatures if you are not wearing gloves.",
      "B. You can touch underwater creatures if you are wearing gloves.",
      "C. Under no circumstances should you touch underwater creatures.",
      "D. You can touch underwater creatures if they are not dangerous."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you are at 10 meters of depth, and fill a balloon with one liter of air from the cylinder, and then ascend to the surface, what will happen to the balloon?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The balloon will expand to a volume of 2 liters, and possibly burst.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The balloon will shrink to a volume of 1/3 liter.",
      "B. The balloon will shrink to a volume of 1/2 liter.",
      "C. The balloon will expand to a volume of 2 liters, and possibly burst.",
      "D. The balloon will expand to a volume of 1 1/2 liters, and possibly burst."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "If you are diving and begin to choke, what should you do?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cough into the regulator.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hold your breath and swim to the surface immediately.",
      "B. Take off your regulator and cough.",
      "C. Cough into the regulator.",
      "D. Swim to the surface immediately, exhaling as you go."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why does a diving mask cover the nose?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "To prevent mask squeeze",
    "choices": [
      "A. To increase your visibility",
      "B. To keep water from going up your nose",
      "C. To prevent mask squeeze",
      "D. To allow you to breathe through your nose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When you are breathing compressed air at depth, a certain amount of the air gets dissolved in the tissues of your body. When you ascend, what happens to this dissolved air?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It comes out of solution, forming gas bubbles in your tissues.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nothing",
      "B. It comes out of solution, forming gas bubbles in your tissues.",
      "C. It passes into your urine, whence it is excreted when you go to the bathroom.",
      "D. It moves into your brain, causing you to become delirious."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the abbreviation SCUBA stand for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Self-Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Swimming Confined to Underwater Breathable Air",
      "B. Swimming Continuously Underwater Breathing Air",
      "C. Swimming Confidently Underwater Breathing Air",
      "D. Self-Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When Utah first broke the BCS, they played against this team in this BCS Bowl Game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pittsburgh/Fiesta Bowl",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pittsburgh/Fiesta Bowl",
      "B. Tulsa/Armed Forces Bowl",
      "C. Alabama/Sugar Bowl",
      "D. Georgia Tech/Emerald Bowl"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year did football become a program for the University of Utah?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1892",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1911",
      "B. 1905",
      "C. 1900",
      "D. 1892"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former Utah football player became a member of the Carolina Panthers in 2001?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kevin Dyson",
      "B. Steve Smith",
      "C. Eric Weddle",
      "D. Jamal Anderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the head football coach for Utah from 1990-1998?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron McBride",
    "choices": [
      "A. Urban Meyer",
      "B. Jack Cutrice",
      "C. Ron McBride",
      "D. Ray Nagel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which former Ute was nominated for the Heisman Trophy, and drafted number 1 in the 2005 NFL Draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alex Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Quinton Ganther",
      "B. Alex Smith",
      "C. Eric Weddle",
      "D. Paris Warren"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did Utah play in the Sugar Bowl the second time they broke the BCS?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alabama",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alabama",
      "B. Louisville",
      "C. Michigan",
      "D. Oregon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What medicinal properties do Calendula plants, commonly known as pot marigold, possess?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Anti-inflammatory",
    "choices": [
      "A. All of these",
      "B. Anti-inflammatory",
      "C. Aphrodisiac",
      "D. Laxative"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city did the Kansas City As move to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Oakland",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Louis",
      "B. Chicago",
      "C. Oakland",
      "D. Philadelphia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1958 season, the Brooklyn Dodgers moved to what city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tampa",
      "B. Chicago",
      "C. Nashville",
      "D. Los Angeles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did the Boston Braves move to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Milwaukee",
    "choices": [
      "A. Milwaukee",
      "B. Atlanta",
      "C. San Diego",
      "D. Washington"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The St. Louis Browns packed up and went to which city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Baltimore",
    "choices": [
      "A. Baltimore",
      "B. Chicago",
      "C. Los Angeles",
      "D. San Francisco"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city did the Philadelphia As move to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kansas City",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kansas City",
      "B. Oakland",
      "C. St. Louis",
      "D. Las Vegas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city did the New York Giants move to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "San Francisco",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Diego",
      "B. San Francisco",
      "C. Seattle",
      "D. Tampa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Milwaukee Braves left town to move where?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Atlanta",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston",
      "B. Nashville",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. Atlanta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What city did the Seattle Pilots move to?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Milwaukee",
    "choices": [
      "A. Atlanta",
      "B. San Francisco",
      "C. Washington",
      "D. Milwaukee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Washington Senators moved to this city after the 1971 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arlington",
    "choices": [
      "A. El Paso",
      "B. Arlington",
      "C. Houston",
      "D. Dallas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Washington Senators of 1960 left for which one of these cities?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Minneapolis",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago",
      "B. Minneapolis",
      "C. Detroit",
      "D. Milwaukee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many are the Grand Slam tournaments?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8",
      "B. 5",
      "C. 4",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the Grand Slam tournaments are matches played on clay courts?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roland Garros",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australian Open",
      "B. Wimbledon",
      "C. Roland Garros",
      "D. US Open"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which is the oldest and most prestigious event in the sport of tennis?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wimbledon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australian Open",
      "B. French Open",
      "C. Wimbledon",
      "D. US Open"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city does the Australian Open take place?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Melbourne",
    "choices": [
      "A. Adelaide",
      "B. Sydney",
      "C. Melbourne",
      "D. Canberra"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which year was the Association of Tennis Professionals (ATP) formed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1972",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1960",
      "B. 1983",
      "C. 1951",
      "D. 1972"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these female tennis players has held the longest winning streak?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Martina Navratilova",
    "choices": [
      "A. Margaret Court",
      "B. Chris Evert",
      "C. Martina Navratilova",
      "D. Steffi Graf"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tennis player won the first Golden Slam in the history of tennis?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steffi Graf",
    "choices": [
      "A. Martina Navratilova",
      "B. Steffi Graf",
      "C. John McEnroe",
      "D. Pete Sampras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the tennis players was born in Novi Sad, Yugoslavia (now Vojvodina, Serbia and Montenegro)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Monica Seles",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ivan Lendl",
      "B. Martina Navratilova",
      "C. Monica Seles",
      "D. Ilie Nastase"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the colourful celebration, conducted by the of the offensive players of the St. Louis Rams in the end zone, after scoring a touchdown?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Bob and Weave",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Bounce",
      "B. The Bob and Weave",
      "C. The Ram Wiggle",
      "D. The Circle Jerk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which quarterback in the NFL is the second cousin of Atlanta Falcons quarterback Michael Vick?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Aaron Brooks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve McNair",
      "B. Mike Vanderjagt",
      "C. Aaron Brooks",
      "D. T. J. Houshmanzadah"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At University High School in Waco, Texas, during his first game, football player LaDanian Tomlinson, nicknamed LT, scored how many touchdowns?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 0",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two football players played high school football together at Mount Carmel High School?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Donovan McNabb and Simeon Rice",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marvin Harrison and Jerry Rice",
      "B. Tiki and Ronde Barber",
      "C. Warren Sapp and Terrell Owens",
      "D. Donovan McNabb and Simeon Rice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the quarterback for the Baltimore Ravens when they won the super bowl in 2000?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Trent Dilfer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Trent Dilfer",
      "B. Tony banks",
      "C. Jeff Goerge",
      "D. Brooks Bollinger"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the former head coach of the Minnesota Vikings, succeeded by Brad Childress?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Tice",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Tice",
      "B. John Gruden",
      "C. Marty Schottenheimer",
      "D. Norv Turner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sir Purr is the mascot of what NFL football team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Panthers",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Falcons",
      "B. The Panthers",
      "C. The saints",
      "D. The Bucks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which football tight end said Im a f*****g soldier. in a an interview, after a game against the University of Tennessee?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kellen WInslow Jr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kellen WInslow Jr",
      "B. Terrell Owens",
      "C. Randy Moss",
      "D. Jeremy Shockey"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these college-nickname pairs from 2006 is wrong?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "University of Denver - Rams",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Southern Illinois - Salukis",
      "B. Sacramento State - Hornets",
      "C. University of Denver - Rams",
      "D. Syracuse - Orange(men)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of San Diego State University during 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Aztecs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aztecs",
      "B. Indians",
      "C. Warriors",
      "D. Colonials"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Georgetown Universitys mascot is a bulldog. What is its nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hoyas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wildcats",
      "B. Panthers",
      "C. Hoyas",
      "D. Huskies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the nickname of Oregon State University in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Beavers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ducks",
      "B. Badgers",
      "C. Beavers",
      "D. Birds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the nickname of the University of Cincinnati?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bearcats",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bearcats",
      "B. Tigers",
      "C. Wildcats",
      "D. Bearpack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is UNC Wilmingtons nickname?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Seahawks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tribe",
      "B. Rams",
      "C. Seahawks",
      "D. Wolfpack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Having played only one season in the majors with the 1959 Phillies, this player, popularly known as Sparky, later made his mark as a manager.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Anderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. John McGraw",
      "B. Earl Weaver",
      "C. Walter Alston",
      "D. George Anderson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Old Aches and Pains played twenty years for the Chicago White Sox, winning batting titles in 1936 and 1943. What is his real name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Luke Appling",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luis Aparicio",
      "B. Luke Appling",
      "C. Frank Malzone",
      "D. Tony Lazzeri"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, nicknamed Mr. Cub, spent nineteen seasons in the Windy City with the Chicago Cubs.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ernie Banks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sammy Sosa",
      "B. Ferguson Jenkins",
      "C. Ernie Banks",
      "D. Ryne Sandberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This classy left-hander, known as Lefty, was a ten-time All-Star and winner of four Cy Young Awards.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Carlton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Randy Jones",
      "B. Whitey Ford",
      "C. Steve Carlton",
      "D. Warren Spahn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Drafted by the Montreal Expos in 1972, The Kid won three Gold Gloves as a catcher. He finished his career with 324 home runs and was elected to the Hall of Fame in 2003. What is his real name?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gary Carter",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gary Carter",
      "B. Lance Parrish",
      "C. Ted Simmons",
      "D. Carlton Fisk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, nicknamed Baby Bull, made his debut on April 15, 1958 hitting a home run against the L.A. Dodgers. He hit 379 home runs over a seventeen-year career and was the national League MVP in 1967.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Orlando Cepeda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Orlando Cepeda",
      "B. Bobby Bonds",
      "C. Danny Tartabull",
      "D. Wes Westrum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Old Timer, known as Dizzy Dean, pitched twelve years for the St. Louis Cardinals, Chicago Cubs, and St. Louis Browns.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jay Hanna",
    "choices": [
      "A. Peter Paul",
      "B. Marvin Edward",
      "C. Henry Haymaker",
      "D. Jay Hanna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, known as The Lip, began his career with the Yankees in 1925 and finished it with the St. Louis Browns in 1945. He is a three time All-Star, elected to the Hall of Fame in 1994.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leo Durocher",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Durham",
      "B. Frank Crosetti",
      "C. Leo Durocher",
      "D. Norm Siebern"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This diminutive second baseman, known as Nellie Fox, led the Chicago White Sox into the World Series in 1959 against the Dodgers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jacob Nelson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jacob Nelson",
      "B. Samuel Sheridan",
      "C. Mordecai Abraham",
      "D. Frank James"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, known as the Iron Horse, spent seventeen seasons with the New York Yankees hitting 493 home runs. When he retired, he brought the crowd at Yankee Stadium to tears by saying he was the luckiest man on the face of the earth.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Gehrig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Babe Ruth",
      "B. Hank Bauer",
      "C. Joe DiMaggio",
      "D. Lou Gehrig"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was caught stealing a total of 335 bases in his major league career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rickey Henderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rickey Henderson",
      "B. Maury WIlls",
      "C. Joe Morgan",
      "D. Lou Brock"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What player stole home a record 54 times while playing with the Tigers and As?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ty Cobb",
    "choices": [
      "A. Joe Morgan",
      "B. Al Kaline",
      "C. John Roseboro",
      "D. Ty Cobb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This batter was hit by a pitch 50 times in a season in 1971.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Hunt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dock Ellis",
      "B. Gary Carter",
      "C. Ron Hunt",
      "D. Reggie Jackson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which old timer struck out a total of 4 times in 1920 while playing with the Indians?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Sewell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jimmy Foxx",
      "B. Billy Martin",
      "C. Joe Sewell",
      "D. Don Mattingly"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these pitchers threw 7 no hitters during his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nolan Ryan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nolan Ryan",
      "B. Sandy Koufax",
      "C. J.R. Richard",
      "D. Bob Moose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Yankee slugger hit a total of 23 Grand Slams in his career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lou Gehrig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mickey Mantle",
      "B. Lou Gehrig",
      "C. Yogi Berra",
      "D. Reggie Jackson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Known as Charlie Hustle, this player played with Cincinnati, Montreal, and Philadelphia.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Perez",
      "B. Hank Aaron",
      "C. Gary Templeton",
      "D. Pete Rose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these players collected over 200 hits ten times during his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Keeler",
      "B. Pete Rose",
      "C. Wade Boggs",
      "D. Ty Cobb"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player was a feared homerun hitter during his major league playing career. He started his major league career in Milwaukee Braves and ended it in Milwaukee Brewers.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Willie Mays",
      "C. Barry Bonds",
      "D. Babe Ruth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which pitcher recorded 511 wins while pitching in the big leagues?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cy Young",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jack Chesbro",
      "B. Cy Young",
      "C. Walter Johnson",
      "D. Sandy Koufax"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won Treble in 1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Manchester United",
    "choices": [
      "A. Manchester United",
      "B. Arsenal",
      "C. Chelsea",
      "D. Liverpool"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many premiership titles did  Liverpool win during the period of 1992-2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 0",
      "D. 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What trophie did Chelsea win in 2000?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "FA Cup",
    "choices": [
      "A. League Cup",
      "B. FA Cup",
      "C. Premiership Cup",
      "D. UEFA Cup"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1999s match for the FA Cup between Arsenal and Manchester United, who misses the penalty during the first period of extra-time, and who scores later on, thus deciding the outcome of the match?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bergkamp - Ryan Giggs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kanu - Ryan Giggs",
      "B. Bergkamp - Ryan Giggs",
      "C. Bergkamp - Beckham",
      "D. Henry - Ryan Giggs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During which season did Arsenal become Englands Champion for the first time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1930-31",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1930-31",
      "B. 1970-71",
      "C. 1932-33",
      "D. 1942-43"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2003-04, who became the new owner of Chelsea?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roman Abramovich",
    "choices": [
      "A. Not listed here as an option",
      "B. Roman Abramovich",
      "C. Malcolm Glaizer",
      "D. Ivan Abramovich"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During which season was the number of teams in the English Premiership reduced to 20?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1995-96",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1997-98",
      "B. 1995-96",
      "C. 1993-94",
      "D. 1992-93"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team wins the English Premiership in the 1994-95 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Blackburn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Manchester United",
      "B. Newcastle",
      "C. Blackburn",
      "D. Arsenal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 2004-2005 season, which team ended Arsenals streak of 49 matches without defeat?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Manchester United",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fulham",
      "B. Manchester United",
      "C. Liverpool",
      "D. Chelsea"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "With which team did Joe Carter start his career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cubs",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cubs",
      "B. Indians",
      "C. Padres",
      "D. Blue Jays"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe DiMaggio had two brothers who played in the baseball major leagues. One was Dom or Dominick. What was the name of his other brother?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vince",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vance",
      "B. Vince",
      "C. Jim",
      "D. Denny"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Joe was the youngest player to pitch during the 20th century.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nuxhall",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nuxhall",
      "B. Cronin",
      "C. Torre",
      "D. Mauer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Joe roamed the outfield during the Oakland As heyday of the early 1970s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rudi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rudi",
      "B. Girardi",
      "C. Morgan",
      "D. Carter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Joe played primarily first base for the Yankees starting in 1962.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pepitone",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pepitone",
      "B. Skowron",
      "C. Jacoby",
      "D. Jeter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many seasons did Joe Jackson play in the baseball major leagues?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "13",
    "choices": [
      "A. 14",
      "B. 15",
      "C. 13",
      "D. 16"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman hit a game winning home run in the 1960 world series.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Mazeroski",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Rose",
      "B. Jackie Robinson",
      "C. Joe Morgan",
      "D. Bill Mazeroski"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which second baseman was known for breaking the color barrier?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jackie Robinson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nellie Fox",
      "B. Joe Morgan",
      "C. Johnny Evers",
      "D. Jackie Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman was in the middle of the Tinker to _______ to Chance double play combination.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Johnny Evers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Mazeroski",
      "B. Johnny Evers",
      "C. Frank Grant",
      "D. Nap Lajoie"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman had a batting average of .424 in 1924 while playing with the St. Louis Cardinals.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rogers Hornsby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ryne Sandberg",
      "B. Ty Cobb",
      "C. Tony Lazzeri",
      "D. Rogers Hornsby"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman played for the Twins and the Angels during his career.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rod Carew",
    "choices": [
      "A. Johnny Evers",
      "B. Joe Morgan",
      "C. Rod Carew",
      "D. Bid McPhee"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman, elected to the Hall of Fame in 1989 by the Veterans Committee, played with Stan Musial, another Hall of Famer.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Red Schoendienst",
    "choices": [
      "A. Red Schoendienst",
      "B. Joe Morgan",
      "C. Ryne Sandberg",
      "D. Rod Carew"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman played for the Cincinnati Reds with Pete Rose, Johnny Bench, and Tony Perez.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Joe Morgan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Mazeroski",
      "B. Frank Grant",
      "C. Ryne Sandberg",
      "D. Joe Morgan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which second baseman was known as the silent captain of the Red Sox?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bobby Doerr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Doerr",
      "B. Bid McPhee",
      "C. Joe Morgan",
      "D. Johnny Evers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman played for the Chicago Cubs in the 1980s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ryne Sandberg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ryne Sandberg",
      "B. Tony Lazzeri",
      "C. Frankie Frisch",
      "D. Frank Grant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This second baseman was part of the New York Yankees murderers row.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tony Lazzeri",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rod Carew",
      "B. Tony Lazzeri",
      "C. Jackie Robinson",
      "D. Joe Morgan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two teams had the best NBA records in the 1997-1998 Season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls and Utah jazz",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Antonio and L.A. Lakers",
      "B. Chicago Bulls and Utah jazz",
      "C. Houston Rockets and Seattle Supersonics",
      "D. New York Knicks and Miami Heat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the 1970-1971 season, which Eastern Conference team had the best record and got the Most Valuable Player Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Milwaukee Bucks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Milwaukee Bucks",
      "B. NY Knicks",
      "C. Boston Celtics",
      "D. Philadelphia 76ers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The San Diego Clippers, who moved to Los Angeles, California and changed their name to the Los Angeles Clippers, finished 1984 with what record?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "31-51",
    "choices": [
      "A. 20-62",
      "B. 31-51",
      "C. 25-57",
      "D. 15-67"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What expansion team finished with the NBA worst win/loss record during their first season in 1995â96?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vancouver Grizzlies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vancouver Grizzlies",
      "B. Charlotte Bobcats",
      "C. Toronto Raptors",
      "D. Orlando Magic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which two NBA teams had the two best records in 1960-1961?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston Celtics and St Louis Hawks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston Celtics and St Louis Hawks",
      "B. Los Angeles Lakers and Boston Celtics",
      "C. New York Knicks and St Louis Hawks",
      "D. Philly Warriors and Detriot Pistons"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1996-1997 season, which team broke the best record for an NBA season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Bulls",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Pistons",
      "B. Boston Celtics",
      "C. San Antonio Spurs",
      "D. Chicago Bulls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When keeping a baseball boxscore, which number signifies the shortstop?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 6",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This baseball shortstop player donated $3.9 million to renovate the baseball field at The University of Miami and also won two Gold Gloves.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alex Rodriguiz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Banks",
      "B. Alex Rodriguiz",
      "C. Miguel Tejada",
      "D. Derek Jeter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player broke the record for the most home runs by a shortstop in one season in 2002?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alex Rodriguez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Banks",
      "B. Miguel Tejada",
      "C. Derek Jeter",
      "D. Alex Rodriguez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This shortstop had a great year in 1962 winning his second consecutive Gold Glove, the NL MVP Award, and hitting a homerun both rightly and lefty in one game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maury Wills",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Banks",
      "B. Alvin Dark",
      "C. Maury Wills",
      "D. Dick Groat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Born in 1931 in Dallas, this player was a fan favorite as well as a Hall of Famer. He wore #14 and played his whole career for one team, a team whose inability to win had nothing to do with its star shortstops ability.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ernie Banks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Luis Aparicio",
      "B. Tony Kubek",
      "C. Ernie Banks",
      "D. Johnny Logan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe Tinker was the shortstop in the famous combination Tinkers to Evers to Chance.â What was the name of the famous poem that immortalized these three players?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Baseballs Sad Lexicon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Baseballs Sad Lexicon",
      "B. Casey at the Bat",
      "C. The Deadly Trio",
      "D. Bad Days in Chi-town"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Venezuelan was a great fielding shortstop for the White Sox. On White Sox he teamed with Nellie Fox to form a great fielding duo. Who was this famous #11?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Luis Aparicio",
    "choices": [
      "A. Felix Lopez",
      "B. Luis Aparicio",
      "C. Chico Fernandez",
      "D. Chico Carrasquel"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This college basketball coach won seven straight National Championships between 1967 and 1973. Four times his teams went 30 - 0 and, during a stretch between 1971 and 1974, his team won 88 straight games. He was known as The Wizard of Westwood.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Wooden",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dean Smith",
      "B. Bobby Knight",
      "C. John Wooden",
      "D. Larry Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, known as Chocolate Thunder, was the first to jump right from high school to the NBA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Darryl Dawkins",
    "choices": [
      "A. Marvin Webster",
      "B. Darryl Dawkins",
      "C. Moses Malone",
      "D. Bob McAdoo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This two-time MVP player, known as The Mailman, was selected in 1996 as one of the 50 Greatest Players in NBA History.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Karl Malone",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Cartright",
      "B. Bernard King",
      "C. Karl Malone",
      "D. Larry Bird"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NHL player, known as Boom Boom, was credited with popularizing the slap shot. He was inducted into the Hockey Hall of Fame in 1972.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bernie Geoffrion",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Mahavolich",
      "B. Rod Gilbert",
      "C. Bobby Hull",
      "D. Bernie Geoffrion"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "These NHL relatives were known as the Rocket and the Pocket Rocket.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maurice and Henri Richard",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maurice and Henri Richard",
      "B. Bobby and Brett Hull",
      "C. Frank and Peter Mahavolich",
      "D. Brent and Brian Sutter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NHL goalie won the Rookie of the Year in 1952 with the New York Rangers. Known as Gump, he was one of the last goalies to play the position without a mask.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lorne Worsley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lorne Worsley",
      "B. Glenn Hall",
      "C. Terry Sawchuck",
      "D. Johnny Bower"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following statements about Major League baseball player Marvellous Marv Throneberry is false?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "He was chosen by the Mets in the 1961 Expansion Draft.",
    "choices": [
      "A. He was the first sportsman to appear in a Miller Lite beer commercial.",
      "B. He appeared in a World Series game with the New York Yankees.",
      "C. He was part of a trade package in which the Yankees acquired Roger Maris.",
      "D. He was chosen by the Mets in the 1961 Expansion Draft."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This switch hitter, known as the Commerce Comet, was inducted into the Hall of Fame in 1974.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mickey Mantle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Singleton",
      "B. Eddie Murray",
      "C. Bobby Murcer",
      "D. Mickey Mantle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This first baseman, known as Stretch, played 22 seasons of Major League baseball.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willie McCovey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lou Whittaker",
      "B. Cecil Fielder",
      "C. Willie McCovey",
      "D. Jim Gentile"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former NFL player, nicknamed Mad Stork, stood 67 and weighed 220 lbs. He began his playing career with the Baltimore Colts in 1969 â 1970.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ted Hendricks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ed Jones",
      "B. Gino Marchetti",
      "C. Ted Hendricks",
      "D. Larry Little"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This NFL defensive back, called Night Train, began his career in 1952 and led the league in interceptions as a rookie. He was elected to the Professional Football Hall of Fame in 1974.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dick Lane",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bobby Layne",
      "B. Dick Patton",
      "C. Dick Lane",
      "D. Ronnie Lott"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This football player, known as Sweetness, spent his entire 13-year career with the same NFL team. He ran for 275 yards in a game in 1977 and is one of the few players to run for, throw for, and catch a touchdown pass in the same game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walter Payton",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Riggins",
      "B. Otis Anderson",
      "C. Walter Payton",
      "D. Jim Brown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was Babe Ruth born?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1895",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1901",
      "B. 1902",
      "C. 1899",
      "D. 1895"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many major league baseball teams did Babe Ruth play for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2",
      "B. 4",
      "C. 5",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What number did the Babe wear for the New York Yankees?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "3",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8",
      "B. 9",
      "C. 6",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Babe Ruths second wife?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Claire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Cindy",
      "B. Cloris",
      "C. Claire",
      "D. Clara"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many home runs did the Babe hit while playing major league baseball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "714",
    "choices": [
      "A. 714",
      "B. 716",
      "C. 715",
      "D. 713"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "With what team did Babe Ruth finish his major league baseball playing career?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston Braves",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Yankees",
      "B. St. Louis Cardinals",
      "C. None Of These",
      "D. Boston Braves"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about athlete Danuta Rosani is true?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "She was the first athlete in the track and field events to be disqualified in the Olympics for a banned  substance.",
    "choices": [
      "A. She was the first Italian female athlete to win an Olympic gold medal.",
      "B. She was the first female athlete found to be technically a male.",
      "C. She was the first Russian athlete to escape to the USA.",
      "D. She was the first athlete in the track and field events to be disqualified in the Olympics for a banned  substance."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The actor who played Oddjob in the Bond movie Goldfinger won an Olympic Medal. Which statement is true about him?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "His name was Toshiyuki Harold Sakata.",
    "choices": [
      "A. His name was Toshiyuki Harold Sakata.",
      "B. He won an Olympic Gold Medal in karate in the 1960 Olympics.",
      "C. He won an Olympic Gold Medal in weightlifting  in the 1956 Olympics.",
      "D. He was born in Japan and died in Los Angeles, California."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Baseball Hall of Famer is credited with throwing the first curveball?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "William Arthur Cummings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Martyn Stephen Darrow",
      "B. Harold Joseph Chandler",
      "C. William Arthur Cummings",
      "D. Denton True Young"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "It is generally accepted that the phrase red herring, which has been in popular parlance for many years, is derived from which sport?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fox hunting",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fencing",
      "B. Golf",
      "C. Bowling",
      "D. Fox hunting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What distinction does Masanori Murakami hold?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The first Japanese-born major league baseball player.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The first player to steal a base in the Olympics.",
      "B. The first player to hit a home run in an international competition.",
      "C. The first Japanese-born major league baseball player.",
      "D. The first player to hit a home run in the Olympics."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who has the highest ranking in an NFL game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Referee",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Backfield Judge",
      "B. The Referee",
      "C. The Head Linesman",
      "D. The Umpire"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Cleveland Tigers, the Muncie Flyers, the Hammond Pros, and the Dayton Triangles were some of the original teams in which league?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "NFL",
    "choices": [
      "A. NBA",
      "B. NHL",
      "C. NFL",
      "D. Major League Baseball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which sport would you find Bay Matuka, Blue Charm, Green Highlander, Silver Stoat, and Logie?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Salmon Fishing",
    "choices": [
      "A. Harness Racing",
      "B. Thoroughbred  Horse racing",
      "C. Salmon Fishing",
      "D. Trout Fishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What trophy is awarded to the Super Bowl-winning team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vince Lombardi Trophy",
    "choices": [
      "A. Vince Lombardi Trophy",
      "B. Heisman Trophy",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. Don Vamdo Trophy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What quarter back led in passing yards in 2002?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rich Gannon",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rich Gannon",
      "B. Donovan McNabb",
      "C. Brett Farve",
      "D. Payton Manning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the first two losing teams in the Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chiefs and Raiders",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rams and Eagles",
      "B. Chiefs and Raiders",
      "C. Falcons and Colts",
      "D. Chiefs and Packers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these NFL players played the most career games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Blanda",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry Rice",
      "B. They played the same number of games.",
      "C. Dan Marino",
      "D. George Blanda"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What uniform number did Walter Payton wear when he played for the Bears?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "34",
    "choices": [
      "A. 29",
      "B. 34",
      "C. 54",
      "D. 99"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the first team to both play in and lose four Super Bowls.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vikings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Falcons",
      "B. Vikings",
      "C. Colts",
      "D. Rams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was drafted by the Cleveland Browns first overall in the 2000 NFL draft?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Courtney Brown",
    "choices": [
      "A. Courtney Brown",
      "B. Michael Vick",
      "C. Warrick Dunn",
      "D. Alge Crumpler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first NFL kicker to finish the regular season with a 100% success rate on field goals and extra points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gary Anderson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Young",
      "B. Trey Vickrey",
      "C. Gary Anderson",
      "D. Jerry Rice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had the most touchdown passes in a season before Payton Manning set a new record?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dan Marino",
    "choices": [
      "A. Michael Vick",
      "B. Dan Marino",
      "C. Dauntee Coulpper",
      "D. Steve Macnair"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What team did Tony Dorsett play for after he left the Cowboys?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Broncons",
    "choices": [
      "A. Broncons",
      "B. Falcons",
      "C. Vikings",
      "D. Colts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the score of the 2008 Super Bowl?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "17-14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 21-17",
      "B. 17-14",
      "C. 32-28",
      "D. 42-24"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who had the most home runs in the 2007 Major League Baseball season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alex Rodriguez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Alex Rodriguez",
      "B. David Ortiz",
      "C. Vladimir Guerrero",
      "D. Troy Glaus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what city and year did Muhammad Ali win the Olympic gold medal for the United States of America in the boxing light heavyweight division?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rome 1960",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rome 1960",
      "B. Tokyo 1964",
      "C. Melbourne 1956",
      "D. Mexico City 1968"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Although Muhammad Ali was from Louisville, Kentucky he represented this major American city as a junior in the Golden Gloves.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York",
      "B. Chicago",
      "C. Washington",
      "D. Dallas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Muhammad Alis first professional fight and victory against?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tunney Hunsacker",
    "choices": [
      "A. Archie Moore",
      "B. Tunney Hunsacker",
      "C. Joe Louis",
      "D. Alonzo Johnson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Muhammad Ali defeat Sonny Liston to win the World Heavyweight Championship?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "February 1964",
    "choices": [
      "A. December 1963",
      "B. October 1964",
      "C. February 1964",
      "D. May 1964"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of his boxing opponents did Muhammad Ali label The Washer Woman?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "George Chuvalo",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Chuvalo",
      "B. Clevland Williams",
      "C. Ernie Terrell",
      "D. Zora Folley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During a fight, Muhammad Ali kept asking this boxer, What is my name?.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ernie Terrell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ernie Terrell",
      "B. Floyd Patterson",
      "C. Zora Folley",
      "D. Clevland Williams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Muhammad Alis last opponent before his boxing license was suspended in 1967?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zora Folley",
    "choices": [
      "A. Zora Folley",
      "B. Ernie Terell",
      "C. Cleveland Williams",
      "D. George Chuvalo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who did Muhammad Ali fight against in his come-back match in 1970?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerry Quarry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Zora Folley",
      "B. Jerry Quarry",
      "C. Oscar Bonavena",
      "D. Jimmy Ellis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On his way to fighting George Foreman, Muhammad Ali lost a fight against this boxer.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ken Norton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ken Norton",
      "B. Jergin Blin",
      "C. Alvin Lewis",
      "D. Mac Foster"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which African country did Muhammad Ali fight George Foreman in a match referred to as The Rumble in the Jungle?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zaire",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ghana",
      "B. Cameroon",
      "C. Zaire",
      "D. Egypt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What name was given to the tactic that Muhammad Ali used to defeat George Foreman?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rope a Dope",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rope a Dope",
      "B. Run and Hide",
      "C. Rope and Hope",
      "D. Hope and Pray"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the fight referred to as The Thrilla in Manila?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ali won by a technical knock out after 14 rounds.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ali won by a technical knock out after 14 rounds.",
      "B. Ali won on points",
      "C. Ali knocked out Frazier after 14 rounds.",
      "D. Ali knocked out Frazier in the final round."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1978, Muhammad Ali lost to this boxer but then defeated him later that year, thus regaining the heavyweight championship title for a record 3rd time.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leon Spinks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Leon Spinks",
      "B. Ken Norton",
      "C. Joe Frazier",
      "D. Joe Bugner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 1988 Olympics, this lady earned a bronze medal, thus becoming the first African-American to win an Olympic medal.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Debi Thomas",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rory Flack",
      "B. Debi Thomas",
      "C. None of these",
      "D. Jill Trenary"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1989, the Figure Skating World Championships had a new nation as a contender for possible glory. Who was the first Japanese female skater to win the World Championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Midori Ito",
    "choices": [
      "A. None of these",
      "B. Midori Ito",
      "C. Yuka Sato",
      "D. Shizuka Arakawa"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Japanese dynamo became the first lady to land a quadruple jump in competition. It was a junior competition, but it still counts as a figure skating first.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Miki Ando",
    "choices": [
      "A. Miki Ando",
      "B. Shizuka Arakawa",
      "C. Mao Asada",
      "D. Mai Asada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first lady to perform a successful triple Axel in a figure skating competition?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Midori Ito",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tonya Harding",
      "B. Midori Ito",
      "C. Nancy Kerrigan",
      "D. Oksana Baiul"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At the 1992 Olympics in Albertville, this figure skater became the first Asian-American to medal at the Winter Olympics.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kristi Yamaguchi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kristi Yamaguchi",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Michelle Kwan",
      "D. Karen Kwan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1999, the reigning World Champion Michelle Kwan lost to a Russian who became the first woman from her country to win a Figure Skating World Championship. Who is she?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maria Butyrskaya",
    "choices": [
      "A. Irina Slutskaya",
      "B. Maria Butyrskaya",
      "C. Ekaterina Gordeeva",
      "D. Oksana Baiul"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1994 in Lilihammer, this lady became the first Chinese skater to win a medal.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lu Chen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Caroline Zhang",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Dan Fang",
      "D. Lu Chen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first Ladies Figure Skating World Champion was crowned in this year.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1906",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1896",
      "B. 1912",
      "C. 1904",
      "D. 1906"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first lady to win the Figure Skating World Championships?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Madge Syers-Cave",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maribel Vinson Owen",
      "B. Sonja Hennie",
      "C. Herma Szabo",
      "D. Madge Syers-Cave"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2005, Michelle Kwan won her 9th US title, tying the record set by what other American female skater?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Maribel Vinson Owen",
    "choices": [
      "A. Maribel Vinson Owen",
      "B. Kristi Yamaguchi",
      "C. Dorothy Hamill",
      "D. Carol Heiss"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these ladies has 10 Figure Skating World Championship Gold Medals?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sonja Hennie",
    "choices": [
      "A. Peggy Flemming",
      "B. Michelle Kwan",
      "C. Sonja Hennie",
      "D. Dorothy Hamill"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Two of the founding members of the NFL are in existence today. What are their original names?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Decatur Staleys and Racine Cardinals",
    "choices": [
      "A. Racine Cardinals and Green Bay Packers",
      "B. Decatur Staleys and Racine Cardinals",
      "C. Dayton Triangles and Canton Bulldogs",
      "D. Canton Bulldogs and Akron Pros"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1936, the NFL instituted the first ever draft of college players. Who was the first player ever drafted into the NFL?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jay Berwanger",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Halas",
      "B. Woody Strode",
      "C. Jay Berwanger",
      "D. Red Grange"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the NFL Players Association formed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1956",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1945",
      "B. 1972",
      "C. 1956",
      "D. 1964"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What university did Bob Gibson attend?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Creighton University",
    "choices": [
      "A. University of Missouri",
      "B. Creighton University",
      "C. University of Kansas",
      "D. University of Colorado"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the only Major League Baseball team Bob Gibson played for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cardinals",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rockies",
      "B. Dodgers",
      "C. Yankees",
      "D. Cardinals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of pitcher was Bob Gibson?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Starting righthander",
    "choices": [
      "A. Righthanded reliever",
      "B. Starting lefthander",
      "C. Starting righthander",
      "D. Lefthanded reliever"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob Gibson was the second pitcher to strikeout 3,000 batters. Who was the first?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walter Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson",
      "B. Christy Mathewson",
      "C. Cy Young",
      "D. Red Ruffing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times did Bob Gibson win a Golden Glove Award?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "9",
    "choices": [
      "A. 9",
      "B. 8",
      "C. 6",
      "D. 7"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many Cy Young Awards did Bob Gibson win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Bob Gibsons primary uniform number?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "45",
    "choices": [
      "A. 7",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 44",
      "D. 45"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Michael Phelps (USA, swimming) declared he would set a record by winning 8 gold medals at the Olympic Games in Beijing. How many did he actually win?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "8",
    "choices": [
      "A. 6",
      "B. 8",
      "C. 7",
      "D. 9"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country was represented by the highest number of athletes at the Olympic Games of 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "China",
    "choices": [
      "A. USA",
      "B. India",
      "C. China",
      "D. Russia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who became the fastest man by setting a world record of 9.69s at the 2008 Olympics 100m run?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Usain Bolt (Jamaica)",
    "choices": [
      "A. Asafa Powell (Jamaica)",
      "B. Richard Thompson (Trinidad  Tobago)",
      "C. Usain Bolt (Jamaica)",
      "D. Walter Dix (USA)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Athletes representing which discipline were the first to compete during the 2008 Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Football / Soccer",
    "choices": [
      "A. Field  Track",
      "B. Gymnastics",
      "C. Swimming",
      "D. Football / Soccer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Two of the 2008 Olympic Games competitors, Natalia Partyka (Poland, table tennis) and Natalie du Toit (South Africa, swimming) are known for something very unusual. What do the two Natalys have in common, besides their first names?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They competed both in 2008 Olympic Games and 2008 Summer Paralympics",
    "choices": [
      "A. They gave birth just days before the opening ceremony but still managed to take part in their competitions",
      "B. They competed both in 2008 Olympic Games and 2008 Summer Paralympics",
      "C. Aged 13, they were the youngest competitors",
      "D. They are twin sisters adopted by the different families just after birth; they met during the Olympics for the first time"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country took all medals in the 100m womens sprint race at the Beijing Olympic Games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jamaica",
    "choices": [
      "A. China",
      "B. UK",
      "C. USA",
      "D. Jamaica"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Ara Abrahamian (Sweden, wrestling) do at the medal ceremony for 84kg greco-roman event of the 2008 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Stepped from the podium, dropped his medal and walked off",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shouted Russia will pay dearly for attacking Georgia in his native language, Armenian",
      "B. Took off his t-shirt and displayed another with the flag of Tibet",
      "C. Refused to accept the gold medal",
      "D. Stepped from the podium, dropped his medal and walked off"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first days of the 2008 Olympic Games were held in the shadow of a military confrontation between Georgia and Russia. In which event did both countries representatives win medals and embraced on the podium?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shooting - 10m air pistol, women",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shooting - 10m air pistol, women",
      "B. Judo - 66kg, men",
      "C. Weightlifting - 48kg, men",
      "D. Athletics - shot put, women"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Yelena Isinbayeva has often been referred to as the tsarina of pole vault, so it was not a surprise when she won the event at the Beijing Olympics. She also set a world record, by jumping this high.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "5.05",
    "choices": [
      "A. 5.05",
      "B. 5.00",
      "C. 6.00",
      "D. 6.05"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Kirsty Coventry won four medals and set a new world record in the 200m backstroke at the 2008 Summer Olympic Games. Which country did she represent?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Zimbabwe",
    "choices": [
      "A. USA",
      "B. Australia",
      "C. Zimbabwe",
      "D. UK"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Afghanistan, a poor war-torn country, managed to win a medal at the 2008 Summer Olympics. Which discipline was it in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Taekwondo",
    "choices": [
      "A. Taekwondo",
      "B. Weightlifting",
      "C. Table tennis",
      "D. Shooting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many of the four top-seeded female tennis players made it to the semifinals at 2008 Summer Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "None",
    "choices": [
      "A. None",
      "B. All",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the mens 200m sprint at the Beijing Olympic Games, the second and third athletes were disqualified. What for?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "For running outside of their tracks",
    "choices": [
      "A. For false-start",
      "B. For running outside of their tracks",
      "C. For doping",
      "D. For their public support of Tibet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What two teams competed in the finals of the mens football (soccer) tournament at the Beijing Olympics?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Argentina-Nigeria",
    "choices": [
      "A. USA-China",
      "B. Argentina-Nigeria",
      "C. Brazil-Argentina",
      "D. USA-Brazil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first FA Cup final took place on this date.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "16 March 1872",
    "choices": [
      "A. 19 March 1913",
      "B. 1 May 1900",
      "C. 22 April 1895",
      "D. 16 March 1872"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In this year Wembley becomes the official host of the competition.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1923",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1944",
      "B. 1929",
      "C. 1923",
      "D. 1934"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This number of trophies have been in use during the competitions long history.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "4",
    "choices": [
      "A. 3",
      "B. 2",
      "C. 1",
      "D. 4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The White Horse Final took place on this date.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "28 April 1923",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4 May 1924",
      "B. 4 April 1924",
      "C. 28 April 1923",
      "D. 28 April 1924"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the most  FA cups during the 1909-2005 period?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Manchester United",
    "choices": [
      "A. Liverpool",
      "B. Manchester United",
      "C. Tottenham Hotspur",
      "D. Arsenal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Stanley Matthews won his first Ever FA Trophy while on this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Blackpool",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fulham",
      "B. Bolton",
      "C. Blackpool",
      "D. Blackburn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This side defeated Herbert Chapmans great Arsenal side 2-0 in 1933.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Walsall",
    "choices": [
      "A. Swansea",
      "B. Walsall",
      "C. Yeovil",
      "D. Bristol City"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Clubs from the top divisions and the Premier League join the competition at this stage.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Third Round",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fifth Round",
      "B. Fourth Round",
      "C. Second Round",
      "D. Third Round"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1978, Sir Bobby Robson wins his first FA Cup trophy as a manager of this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ipswich Town",
    "choices": [
      "A. Derby County",
      "B. Ipswich Town",
      "C. Newcastle United",
      "D. Portsmouth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In this year Welmbley ceases from being the official host of the Competition.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000",
      "B. 2001",
      "C. 1998",
      "D. 1999"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was appointed NFL Commissioner after the retirement of Paul Tagliabue?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Goodell",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roger Goodell",
      "B. Terrell Owens",
      "C. Mark Cohon",
      "D. Bert Bell"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1992 this owner and President of the Milwaukee Brewers became Commissioner of Major League baseball.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Allan Selig",
    "choices": [
      "A. Phil Knight",
      "B. Allan Selig",
      "C. Jerome Holtzman",
      "D. Barry Bonds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Beginning in 1998 he had a significant role in CBS getting the rights to NFL games through at least 2012. His father was a truly great sportscaster.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sean McManus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Robert Barber",
      "B. Henry Rodgers, Jr.",
      "C. Sean McManus",
      "D. Jonathan Buck"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2002 this man, who was President of Indiana University, became President of the NCAA.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Myles  Brand",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sean McManus",
      "B. Tony Ponturo",
      "C. David Hill",
      "D. Myles  Brand"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This company, with a huge ad budget in the world of sports, has a sports marketing division which creates advertising material for the Super Bowl.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Anheuser-Busch",
    "choices": [
      "A. Verizon",
      "B. Anheuser-Busch",
      "C. Concast",
      "D. Colgate-Palmolive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This basketball player, drafted by the Cleveland Cavaliers in 2003, is famous for doing commercials for Sprite, Nike, and Upper Deck.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "LeBron James",
    "choices": [
      "A. LeBron James",
      "B. Kellen Winslow III",
      "C. Brad Daugherty",
      "D. Bob Lemon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1986 he became Executive Director of the Major League Baseball Players Association.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Donald Fehr",
    "choices": [
      "A. Donald Fehr",
      "B. Marvin Miller",
      "C. Theodore Forstmann",
      "D. Chuck Commisky"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is known as the owner of the Boston Red Sox and Roush Fenway Racing.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Henry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Manny Ramirez",
      "B. Robert Kraft",
      "C. John Henry",
      "D. Brian Roberts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This family has had three starting NFL quarterbacks who have won at least two Super Bowls in a row.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Manning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Griese",
      "B. Manning",
      "C. Simms",
      "D. Hassellback"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who purchased the Dallas Cowboys in 1989?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jerry Jones",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wellington Mara",
      "B. Lawrence Tisch",
      "C. Jerry Jones",
      "D. Peter Angelos"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Malcolm Glazer purchased these two teams in 1995 and 2005 respectively.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tampa Bay Buccaneers and Manchester United",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tampa Bay Buccaneers and Manchester United",
      "B. Tampa Bay Buccaneers and Tampa Bay (Devil) Rays",
      "C. New Orleans Saints and Charlote Hornets",
      "D. Tampa Bay (Devil) Rays and New Orleans Saints"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2008 owner of the Seattle Seahawks and Portland Trailblazers was a co-founder of this company.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Microsoft",
    "choices": [
      "A. ESPN",
      "B. Microsoft",
      "C. Lockheed",
      "D. Nike"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This prominent sports agent has represented some of the highest-paid baseball players, including\nManny Ramirez, Mark Teixeira, and Andruw Jones.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Scott Boras",
    "choices": [
      "A. Leigh Steinberg",
      "B. Paul Allen",
      "C. Mark Parker",
      "D. Scott Boras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He grew up in a suburb of Pittsburgh. In 2002 he became the owner of the Dallas Mavericks.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mark Cuban",
    "choices": [
      "A. George Pyne",
      "B. Jeff Urban",
      "C. Mark Cuban",
      "D. Peter Uberroth"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was born in 1987 and is considered one of the top player in his sport. He was nicknamed The Next One.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sidney Crosby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tiger Woods",
      "B. Sidney Crosby",
      "C. LaDamien Tomlinson",
      "D. Evan Longoria"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He has been a fine Super Bowl-winning NFL coach, a football commentator and a video game icon.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Madden",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Madden",
      "B. Buell Gallagher",
      "C. Frank Caliendo",
      "D. Terrell Owens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was a bellhop, an aerobics instructor and an amateur boxer. In 1992 he began the UFC for mixed  martial arts.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dana White",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jim Plank",
      "B. Tito Sanchez",
      "C. Dana White",
      "D. Dan Goldberg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This agent has represented Yao Ming, Tracy McGrady, T.J. Ford, Ben Wallace, Jordan Farmar and Jermaine ONeal.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arn Tellum",
    "choices": [
      "A. Arn Tellum",
      "B. Tom Condon",
      "C. Leigh Steinberg",
      "D. LeMarcus Perkins"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He moved from running Radio City Music Hall to becoming CEO of The United States Tennis Association.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Arlen Kantarian",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Silve",
      "B. Stan Kroenke",
      "C. Arlen Kantarian",
      "D. Jon Litner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He is one of the most influential sports agents in the NFL. His clients have included Steve Young, Troy Aikman, Warren Moon, and Kordell Stewart.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Leigh Steinberg",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ed Condon",
      "B. Leigh Steinberg",
      "C. Max Plank",
      "D. Tom Phelan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the video, Searching for Animal Chin of successful skate team Bones Brigade, who was Animal Chin?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The master of skateboarding",
    "choices": [
      "A. Stacy Peralta",
      "B. Lance Mountain",
      "C. Tony Hawk",
      "D. The master of skateboarding"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the 1980s Tony Hawks father, Frank Hawk was head of what organization?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The National Skateboard Association",
    "choices": [
      "A. Coca Cola of North America",
      "B. The National Rifle Association",
      "C. The National Skateboard Association",
      "D. The CIA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the two brothers who were both professional skaters in the late 70s, then resurfaced in the 80s to become dominant riders once again?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve and Mickey Alba",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve and Tony Alva",
      "B. Frank and Duane Peters",
      "C. Steve and Mickey Alba",
      "D. Stan and Mike McGill"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This man, born in 1963 in New york, is the inventor of the ollie, a skateboarding move.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alan Gelfand",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike McGill",
      "B. Alan Gelfand",
      "C. Tommy Guerro",
      "D. Natas Kapas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He invented the aerial skateboarding trick, McTwist and first performed it in public in 1984 at the Del-Mar Skatepark contest.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike McGill",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lance Mountain",
      "B. Mike McGill",
      "C. Tony Hawk",
      "D. Steve Cabellero"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What skateboard company switched their focus and skyrocketed to success with their clothing line in the mid eighties?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Vision Street Wear",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mad Rats",
      "B. Vans",
      "C. Rector",
      "D. Vision Street Wear"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In skateboarding, what is a Boneless one?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A classic trick, invented by Garry Scott Davis",
    "choices": [
      "A. A classic trick, invented by Garry Scott Davis",
      "B. A skater that doesnt like to fall",
      "C. A skateboard without a nose guard",
      "D. A fall that doesnt break anything"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was on the cover of the first issue of Transworld Skateboarding magazine?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Steve Caballero",
    "choices": [
      "A. Christian Hosoi",
      "B. Tony Hawk",
      "C. Steve Caballero",
      "D. Stacy Peralta"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Texas artist drew the artwork for Zorlac skateboards and was a regular contributing artist for Thrasher magazine.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pushead",
    "choices": [
      "A. Lance Armstrong",
      "B. Vincent VanGogh",
      "C. Henry Vincent",
      "D. Pushead"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the reader mail section of  monthly skateboarding magazine, Thrasher, in the 1980s?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mail Drop",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mail Drop",
      "B. Air Mail",
      "C. The Daily Grind",
      "D. Skater Forum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is not one of the colors for the Atlanta Braves team uniforms?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Green",
    "choices": [
      "A. Blue",
      "B. Green",
      "C. White",
      "D. Red"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the previous name of the Chicago Cubs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Chicago Colts",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago Red Stockings",
      "B. Chicago Dolphins",
      "C. Chicago Bears",
      "D. Chicago Colts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these became the Red Soxs home ballpark in 1912?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Fenway Park",
    "choices": [
      "A. Fenway Park",
      "B. Wrigley Fields",
      "C. PNC Park",
      "D. National Park"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who broke Hank Aarons career home run record?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barry Bonds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Larry Bonds",
      "B. Barry Bonds",
      "C. Binny Jane",
      "D. Boe Jinards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What baseball team was founded in Manhattan in 1960?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York Mets",
    "choices": [
      "A. New York Rockies",
      "B. New York Mets",
      "C. New York Brewers",
      "D. New York Cardinals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the cap insignia of the Los Angeles Dodgers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "A over L",
    "choices": [
      "A. A over L",
      "B. D over L",
      "C. T over A",
      "D. A over D"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What baseball team played their first game on April 5, 1993?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Colorado Rockies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Florida Marlins",
      "B. Atlanta Braves",
      "C. Colorado Rockies",
      "D. Houston Astros"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which player, nicknamed The Captain, was the 1970 NBA Finals MVP?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Willis Reed",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jerry West",
      "B. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "D. Willis Reed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, called Cap or Captain, was the 1971 NBA Finals MVP.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
    "choices": [
      "A. John Havlicek",
      "B. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "C. Rick Barry",
      "D. Wilt Chamberlain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, nicknamed The Big Dipper, Goliath and Mr.100, became the 1972 NBA Finals MVP.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wilt Chamberlain",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Walton",
      "B. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
      "C. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "D. JoJo White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the 1974 NBA Finals MVP who was nicknamed Hondo.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John Havlicek",
    "choices": [
      "A. JoJo White",
      "B. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. John Havlicek",
      "D. Rick Barry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What player nicknamed Greyhound was the NBA Finals MVP in 1975?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rick Barry",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rick Barry",
      "B. Wes Unseld",
      "C. Dennis Johnson",
      "D. Bill Walton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the NBA Finals MVP in 1976?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "JoJo White",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bill Walton",
      "B. JoJo White",
      "C. Wes Unseld",
      "D. Rick Barry"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, nicknamed âBig Red-Headâ, was the NBA Finals MVP in 1977?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bill Walton",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wes Unseld",
      "B. Dennis Johnson",
      "C. Bill Walton",
      "D. JoJo White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the NBA Finals MVP in 1978?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Wes Unseld",
    "choices": [
      "A. Wes Unseld",
      "B. Dennis Johnson",
      "C. Bill Walton",
      "D. JoJo White"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the NBA Finals MVP in 1979?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. JoJo White",
      "B. Bill Walton",
      "C. Dennis Johnson",
      "D. Wes Unseld"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did karate originally begin?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Japan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Malaysia",
      "B. Indonesia",
      "C. China",
      "D. Japan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the karate terminology, what does kata mean?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Form",
    "choices": [
      "A. Form",
      "B. Position",
      "C. Way",
      "D. Fist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is considered the father of Shotokan Karate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gichin Funakoshi",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kenwa Mabuni",
      "B. Gichin Funakoshi",
      "C. Motobu Choki",
      "D. Ano Itosou"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Karate had a major influence on what other country also known for its martial art?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Korea",
    "choices": [
      "A. Russia",
      "B. India",
      "C. Thailand",
      "D. Korea"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which was the first US state in which karate was taught?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hawaii",
    "choices": [
      "A. Louisiana",
      "B. New York",
      "C. Hawaii",
      "D. Texas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A major concept of karate is attitude. What is it called in Japanese?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kokoro",
    "choices": [
      "A. Kumite",
      "B. Kokoro",
      "C. Sapporo",
      "D. Tadashi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these cyclists has the most Tour De France wins?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Lance Armstrong",
    "choices": [
      "A. Jacques Anquetil",
      "B. Eddie Merckx",
      "C. Bernard Hinault",
      "D. Lance Armstrong"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What golfer won his 18th major championship in 1986?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Jack Nicklaus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tiger Woods",
      "B. Jack Nicklaus",
      "C. Ben Hogan",
      "D. Walter Hagen"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What mens basketball team won their 11th NCAA Championship in 1996?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "UCLA",
    "choices": [
      "A. Duke",
      "B. UCLA",
      "C. Kentucky",
      "D. North Carolina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the listed NBA players has the most career points?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Karl Malone",
      "B. Wilt Chamberlain",
      "C. Michael Jordan",
      "D. Kareem Abdul-Jabbar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former MLB players has the most career strike outs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Nolan Ryan",
    "choices": [
      "A. Steve Carlton",
      "B. Nolan Ryan",
      "C. Curt Schilling",
      "D. Chet Lemon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What MLB player set a record for most career hits in 1985?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Pete Rose",
      "B. Ty Cobb",
      "C. Hank Aaron",
      "D. Stan Musial"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What MLB player won his 7th MVP Award in 2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barry Bonds",
    "choices": [
      "A. Roy Campanella",
      "B. Stan Musial",
      "C. Mike Schmidt",
      "D. Barry Bonds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What player  won his 7th Cy Young Award in 2004?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Roger Clemens",
    "choices": [
      "A. Greg Maddux",
      "B. Sandy Koufax",
      "C. Randy Johnson",
      "D. Roger Clemens"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former MLB players has the most career RBIs?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Hank Aaron",
    "choices": [
      "A. Hank Aaron",
      "B. Lou Gehrig",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Brad Wilkerson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these former NFL quarterbacks has the most passing yards?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brett Favre",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brett Favre",
      "B. Dan Marino",
      "C. John Elway",
      "D. Warren Moon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On May 17, 1998 the Yankees won a perfect game 4-0 over the Twins. Who was the wining pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Wells",
    "choices": [
      "A. David Cone",
      "B. David Wells",
      "C. Jimmy Keys",
      "D. Al Leiter"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Joe Girardi caught a perfect game on July 18, 1999. Who was the winning pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "David Cone",
    "choices": [
      "A. Al Leiter",
      "B. Jimmy Keys",
      "C. David Wells",
      "D. David Cone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the first man to catch more than one perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ron Hassey",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ron Hassey",
      "B. Joe Giradi",
      "C. Yogi Berra",
      "D. Jeff Torborg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first perfect game played in Calfornia was played in this city.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Los Angeles",
    "choices": [
      "A. San Francisco",
      "B. Los Angeles",
      "C. San Diego",
      "D. Oakland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He was the first 40-year-old to pitch a perfect game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Randy Johnson",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dizzy Dean",
      "B. Don Drysdale",
      "C. Randy Johnson",
      "D. Kenny Rogers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This is the first team to win more than one perfect game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Yankees",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rangers",
      "B. Braves",
      "C. Dodgers",
      "D. Yankees"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first non-American born pitcher to pitch a perfect game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dennis Martinez",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ferguson Jenkins",
      "B. Pedro Martinez",
      "C. Elmer Valo",
      "D. Dennis Martinez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first player to play in three perfect games?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Paul ONeil",
    "choices": [
      "A. Don Zimmer",
      "B. Pedro Martinez",
      "C. Don Baylor",
      "D. Paul ONeil"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This  is the first team to have three perfect games pitched against them.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dodgers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dodgers",
      "B. Blue Jays",
      "C. White Sox",
      "D. Rangers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1917, a starting pitcher walked the first batter, was ejected and then the relief pitcher pitched perfectly for the rest of the game. Who was the ejected pitcher?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Babe Ruth",
    "choices": [
      "A. Walter Johnson",
      "B. Ed Cicotte",
      "C. Babe Ruth",
      "D. Dizzy Dean"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On May 26, 1959 this pitcher pitched 12 perfect innings.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Harvey Haddix",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Gibson",
      "B. Don Drysdale",
      "C. Warren Sphan",
      "D. Harvey Haddix"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What do these major leaguers have in common: Jim Bibby, Robin Roberts, Curt Simmons, and Woody Fryman?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "They all pitched 27 consecutive outs but had perfect games foiled by the first batter.",
    "choices": [
      "A. They all hit winning homers in perfect games.",
      "B. They were all losing pitchers in two perfect games.",
      "C. They were all on the field for two perfect games.",
      "D. They all pitched 27 consecutive outs but had perfect games foiled by the first batter."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In this movie, the protagonist pitched a perfect game in his first pro baseball game.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Scout",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Scout",
      "B. Maybe a Miracle",
      "C. The Best Day",
      "D. For Love of the Game"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pittsburgh Pirates were a great team in baseballs early years. Unfortunately they lost the first modern World Series in 1903 to this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Boston Red Sox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Chicago Cubs",
      "B. Boston Red Sox",
      "C. New York Yankees",
      "D. The Bad News Bears"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1909 the Pirates won their first World Series versus the Detroit Tigers. This same year they started playing in this Ball Park that would be their home until 1970.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Forbes Field",
    "choices": [
      "A. Two Rivers Stadium",
      "B. Central Park of Pittsburgh",
      "C. Allegheny Ball Park",
      "D. Forbes Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This famous actor/singer owned the Pittsburgh Pirates in the 1940s.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bing Crosby",
    "choices": [
      "A. Frank Sinatra",
      "B. Bing Crosby",
      "C. Bob Hope",
      "D. Dean Martin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On October 13,1960, the Pirates got a homerun from Bill Mazeroski. What is significant about this homerun in baseball history?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "It was the first walk off homerun in a World Series Game 7 that won the Series against the Yankees.",
    "choices": [
      "A. It was the first walk off homerun in a World Series Game 7 that won the Series against the Yankees.",
      "B. It completed the only hitting for a cycle in a World Series game winning the series for Pittsburgh in game 6.",
      "C. It was the first Grand Slam in World Series history, winning Game 7 and the Series versus the Yankees.",
      "D. It is the only inside the park homerun in a World Series Game that beat the Yankees in Game 5 of the World Series."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This song by Sister Sledge was the anthem of the 1979 World Champion Pittsburgh Pirates.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "We Are Family!",
    "choices": [
      "A. Reach Your Peak!",
      "B. Easy Street!",
      "C. We Are Family!",
      "D. Blockbuster Boy!"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Pittsburgh Pirates moved from Three Rivers Stadium to this ball park at the start of the 2001 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "PNC Park",
    "choices": [
      "A. Willie Stargell Stadium",
      "B. Forbes Field",
      "C. PNC Park",
      "D. Federal Field"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This catcher for the 1983 Phillies wore uniform #6. He was killed by a satellite dish that fell on him.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Bo Diaz",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ozzie Virgil",
      "B. Bo Diaz",
      "C. Luis Aguayo",
      "D. Darren Daulton"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player, nicknamed The Sarge, played left field for the 1983 Phillies and wore #34.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gary Matthews",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Dernier",
      "B. Greg Gross",
      "C. Gary Matthews",
      "D. Bill Robinson"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He played 3rd base for the 1983 Phillies and wore uniform #20.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Mike Schmidt",
    "choices": [
      "A. Mike Schmidt",
      "B. Jeff Stone",
      "C. Steve Jeltz",
      "D. Tony Perez"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "He played 1st base for the 1983 Phillies and wore uniform #14.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Rose",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tony Perez",
      "B. Juan Samuel",
      "C. Pete Rose",
      "D. Joe Lefebvre"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This center fielder for the 1983 Phillies was nicknamed Secretary of Defense and wore uniform #31.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Garry Maddox",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bob Molinaro",
      "B. Alejandro Sanches",
      "C. Garry Maddox",
      "D. Greg Gross"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What shortstop for the 1983 Phillies wore uniform # 11?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ivan DeJesus",
    "choices": [
      "A. Purfi Altamirano",
      "B. Tony Ghelfi",
      "C. Ivan DeJesus",
      "D. Steve Jeltz"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the right fielder for the 1983 Phillies who wore #9.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Von Hayes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Von Hayes",
      "B. Jeff Stone",
      "C. Sixto Lezcano",
      "D. Bob Dernier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What player, wearing uniform #45, pitched the final strike for the 1980 World Champion Philadelphia Phillies?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tug McGraw",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tug McGraw",
      "B. Mike Schmidt",
      "C. Steve Carlton",
      "D. Pete Rose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Stanley Cup at the end of the 1993-1994 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New York Rangers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Montreal Canadiens",
      "B. New Jersey Devils",
      "C. New York Rangers",
      "D. New York Islanders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the Stanley Cup champions for the 1994-1995 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Jersey Devils",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings",
      "B. Colorado Avalanche",
      "C. New Jersey Devils",
      "D. Quebec Nordiques"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who sipped from the Stanley Cup following the 1995-1996 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Colorado Avalanche",
    "choices": [
      "A. Ottawa Senators",
      "B. Detroit Red Wings",
      "C. Colorado Avalanche",
      "D. New York Islanders"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the NHL Stanley Cup winner for 1996-1997?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Detroit Red Wings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tampa Bay Lightning",
      "B. Philadelphia Flyers",
      "C. Detroit Red Wings",
      "D. New Jersey Devils"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team captured the NHL title and the coveted Stanley Cup for the 1997-1998 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Detroit Red Wings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings",
      "B. Colorado Avalanche",
      "C. Buffalo Sabres",
      "D. Washington Capitals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Stanley Cup champion in 1998-1999?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Dallas Stars",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings",
      "B. Colorado Avalanche",
      "C. New Jersey Devils",
      "D. Dallas Stars"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which team won the Stanley Cup following the 1999-2000 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Jersey Devils",
    "choices": [
      "A. Dallas Stars",
      "B. Mighty Ducks of Anaheim",
      "C. New Jersey Devils",
      "D. Colorado Avalanche"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the NHLs holy grail for the 2000-2001 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Colorado Avalanche",
    "choices": [
      "A. New Jersey Devils",
      "B. Carolina Hurricanes",
      "C. Colorado Avalanche",
      "D. Detroit Red Wings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Stanley Cup went to this team following the 2001-2002 season.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Detroit Red Wings",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings",
      "B. Carolina Hurricanes",
      "C. Edmonton Oilers",
      "D. New Jersey Devils"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who got to take the Stanley Cup home to their families following the 2002-2003 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Jersey Devils",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carolina Hurricanes",
      "B. Detroit Red Wings",
      "C. New Jersey Devils",
      "D. Colorado Avalanche"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Stanley Cup champion following the 2003-2004 NHL season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tampa Bay Lightning",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tampa Bay Lightning",
      "B. Calgary Flames",
      "C. Carolina Hurricanes",
      "D. Detroit Red Wings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who won the Stanley Cup for the 2004-2005 NHL season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "None of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. None of these",
      "B. Colorado Avalanche",
      "C. New Jersey Devils",
      "D. Anaheim Ducks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the Stanley Cup winner for 2005-2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Carolina Hurricanes",
    "choices": [
      "A. Colorado Avalanche",
      "B. New Jersey Devils",
      "C. Ottawa Senators",
      "D. Carolina Hurricanes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2006-2007 NHL Stanley Cup Finals were won by this team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Anaheim Ducks",
    "choices": [
      "A. Detroit Red Wings",
      "B. Anaheim Ducks",
      "C. Ottawa Senators",
      "D. Phoenix Coyotes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these horses is not a child of  thoroughbred race horse, Seabiscuit?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Sea Orbit",
    "choices": [
      "A. Sea Sovereign",
      "B. First Biscuit",
      "C. Sea Swallow",
      "D. Sea Orbit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the trainer of thoroughbred race horse, Seabiscuit, that rarely spoke?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Tom Smith",
    "choices": [
      "A. Richard Fitzsimmons",
      "B. John Smith",
      "C. James Fitzsimmons",
      "D. Tom Smith"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Golf player A tees off, he mutters a few f-bombs as he watches his ball fly far right into trees and says, Ill play another one. Then he re-tees another ball. His 2nd ball is straighter - in the fairway. Player B claims foul as he did not say he was playing a provisional ball, using those exact words. What should then be done?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Player A is disqualified for illegally playing a shot.",
    "choices": [
      "A. Player A is disqualified for swearing.",
      "B. Player A is disqualified for illegally playing a shot.",
      "C. Player A and B both decide that it was meant as a provisional and thus Player A plays his 3rd shot from the fairway using his 2nd ball.",
      "D. Player B is disqualified for accusing his partner for cheating."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A golf player addresses their ball and is half way through their backswing when a gust of wind rolled the ball back an inch. What is the ruling?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The player takes one penalty stroke and plays the ball as it lies.",
    "choices": [
      "A. The player takes one penalty stroke and replaces the ball.",
      "B. The player should take no penalty but replay the shot.",
      "C. The player takes one penalty stroke and plays the ball as it lies.",
      "D. Since Mother Nature is to blame for the movement, there is no penalty and the player now plays the ball as it lies."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A golf ball embeds into the side of the hole. How should the player who hit it proceed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Place the ball on the nearest edge of the hole and play from there",
    "choices": [
      "A. Replay the shot for no penalty",
      "B. Play the ball as it lies",
      "C. Place the ball on the nearest edge of the hole and play from there",
      "D. Consider the ball holed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After marking their ball on the green, a golf player tosses it to their caddie to clean. Thanks to the caddies excellent hand-eye coordination, he dropped it and the ball rolled into a lake. How should the player proceed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Either retrieve the ball from the lake and play on or take a 2 stroke penalty and continue the hole with a new ball",
    "choices": [
      "A. None of these",
      "B. Either retrieve the ball from the lake and play on or take a 1 stroke penalty and continue the hole with a new ball",
      "C. Either retrieve the ball from the lake and play on or take a 2 stroke penalty and continue the hole with a new ball",
      "D. Continue the hole with a new ball for no penalty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You hit your tee shot deep into the woods, where it might be lost. You announce that youll play a provisional and immediately hit before your playing partner. Your buddy says you should be penalized for playing out of turn. What should you do according to golf rules?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Take no penalty because you were not going out of order to give one player an advantage",
    "choices": [
      "A. Take no penalty but replay your provisional in order",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Take no penalty because you were not going out of order to give one player an advantage",
      "D. Take a 1-stroke penalty for not waiting for all other playing partners to hit before taking a provisional"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You mark your golf ball on the green with a coin, but when you return the ball to its spot, you realize you stepped on the coin and its now stuck to your shoe. What should you do?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Add 1 stroke to your score and replace it as near as possible to its original position",
    "choices": [
      "A. Take a 2-stroke penalty and replace your marker",
      "B. Pretend that nothing happened any quickly toss the coin down so your partners dont suspect foul",
      "C. Add 1 stroke to your score and replace it as near as possible to its original position",
      "D. Replace the marker as close as possible to the original location without penalty"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After playing an approach shot into the green, you find that some prankster in the group ahead had jammed the flag some 40 feet from where the actual golf hole was. How do you proceed?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Play the ball as it lies",
    "choices": [
      "A. Play the ball as it lies",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Move the ball to the same distance from the hole as it was with the fake hole",
      "D. Replay the shot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Hockey Hall of Fame located in Toronto, Ontario, has inducted some of the greatest of hockey players over the years. Which member of the Montreal Canadiens was inducted into the Hockey Hall of Fame in 2006?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The 44th",
    "choices": [
      "A. The 44th",
      "B. The 42nd",
      "C. The 63rd",
      "D. The 51st"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There is no greater honour for a professional athlete to have his number retired by the franchise for which he used to play. Prior to the 2007-2008 season, how many retired numbers were there in the Montreal Canadiens hockey team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "11",
    "choices": [
      "A. 11",
      "B. 7",
      "C. 12",
      "D. 16"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Of all the great playersâ numbers retired by the Montreal Canadiens, one number has actually been retired more than once. Which number is it?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 1",
      "C. 10",
      "D. 9"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Montreal Canadiens Head Coach Guy Carbonneau was once a Habs player. What year was he traded and to which team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1994 to the St-Louis Blues",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1995 to the Dallas Stars",
      "B. 1994 to the Chicago Black Hawks",
      "C. 1994 to the St-Louis Blues",
      "D. 1993 to the Detroit Red Wings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what season did the Montreal Canadiens win their first Stanley Cup?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1915-1916",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1917-1918",
      "B. 1915-1916",
      "C. 1916-1918",
      "D. 1919-1920"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What year was the Montreal Canadiens hockey team founded?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1909",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1908",
      "B. 1917",
      "C. 1909",
      "D. 1902"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before the 2009 playoffs began, New York Rangers head coach Tom Renney and this assistant coach were fired.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Perry Pearn",
    "choices": [
      "A. Perry Pearn",
      "B. Matt Berrie",
      "C. Mike Pelino",
      "D. Glen Sather"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2009, Tom Renney, ex-head coach of the New York Rangers, became the new assistant coach of what team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Edmonton Oilers",
    "choices": [
      "A. Los Angeles Kings",
      "B. Colorado Avalanche",
      "C. Phoenix Coyotes",
      "D. Edmonton Oilers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following New York Rangers retired after the 2008-09 season?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Markus Naslund",
    "choices": [
      "A. Brendan Shanhan",
      "B. Jaromir Jagr",
      "C. Markus Naslund",
      "D. Wade Redden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This former ice hockey defenseman, born in Ontario, Canada, played 465 games as a New York Ranger and wore number 2.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Brad Park",
    "choices": [
      "A. Guy Lafleur",
      "B. Clint Smith",
      "C. Brad Park",
      "D. Maurice Richard"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Glen Sather become President and GM of the New York Rangers?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2000",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2000",
      "B. 1995",
      "C. 2003",
      "D. 2005"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2009, New York Rangers defenseman Michal RozsÃ­val switched to this number.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "33",
    "choices": [
      "A. 76",
      "B. 19",
      "C. 33",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The 2009 US Open Golf Championship was played at Bethpage Black. What was its par?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "70",
    "choices": [
      "A. 70",
      "B. 71",
      "C. 72",
      "D. 69"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Open Championship was first played on 17 October 1860 at this golf course.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Prestwick",
    "choices": [
      "A. St. Andrews",
      "B. Royal Birkdale",
      "C. Lahinch Golf Club",
      "D. Prestwick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the first ever US Masters Golf tournament played?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Augusta National",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bethpage",
      "B. Augusta National",
      "C. Pebble Beach",
      "D. Outside the US"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a golfer said to have, if he is entitled to hit off first?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "the honour",
    "choices": [
      "A. the hit",
      "B. the honour",
      "C. the turn",
      "D. the badge"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What golf term refers to a score of a 3 on a par 5?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Eagle",
    "choices": [
      "A. Eagle",
      "B. Bogey",
      "C. Birdie",
      "D. Par"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Tiger Woods win the US Open Championship held at Torrey Pines?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2008",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2009",
      "B. 2007",
      "C. 2008",
      "D. 2006"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The US Open Tennis Championships were first contested in 1881 as the US National Championships. What events did the players compete in?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "mens singles",
    "choices": [
      "A. mens singles and mens doubles",
      "B. mens singles and womens singles",
      "C. mens singles",
      "D. mens singles and womens doubles"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What tennis player won the US Open in 1990, becoming the youngest ever US Open champion in mens singles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pete Sampras",
    "choices": [
      "A. John McEnroe",
      "B. Bill Tilden",
      "C. Andre Agassi",
      "D. Pete Sampras"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not one of the players who have won five US Open titles?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "John McEnroe",
    "choices": [
      "A. John McEnroe",
      "B. Pete Sampras",
      "C. Roger Federer",
      "D. Jimmy Connors"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times did Roger Federer defeat an American player in the final during his successive five championship wins (2004-2008)?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1",
      "B. 0",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When did Bob and Mike Bryan win the US Open doubles final for the first time?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "2005",
    "choices": [
      "A. 2008",
      "B. 2000",
      "C. 2005",
      "D. 1998"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which country won the maximum number of US Open championships since the beginning of the Open Era in 1968 until 2008?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "United States",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australia",
      "B. Spain",
      "C. United States",
      "D. Switzerland"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Until 2008, only three Spanish players made it to the finals of the US Open. Manuel Santana and Manuel Orantes lifted the trophy in 1965 and 1975, respectively. Who stayed runner-up in the 2003 final?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Juan Carlos Ferrero",
    "choices": [
      "A. Rafael Nadal",
      "B. Tommy Robredo",
      "C. Carlos Moya",
      "D. Juan Carlos Ferrero"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The production of the worlds first commercially available bicycles began in what year?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1867",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1867",
      "B. 1973",
      "C. 1493",
      "D. 1843"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of handlebar would you normally find on a road bike?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Drop handlebar",
    "choices": [
      "A. Drop handlebar",
      "B. Straight handlebar",
      "C. Crooked handlebar",
      "D. Fallen handlebar"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what year did Specialized Bicycle Components produce the first mountain bike called the Stumpjumper?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1982",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1982",
      "B. 1973",
      "C. 1978",
      "D. 1984"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the mechanism at the bottom of pro-cyclists shoes?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Cleats",
    "choices": [
      "A. Beat",
      "B. Sleet",
      "C. Cleats",
      "D. Fleats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What world famous trail is located near Moab, Utah?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Slickrock Bike Trail",
    "choices": [
      "A. White Rim Trail",
      "B. Poison Spider Mesa",
      "C. Slickrock Bike Trail",
      "D. Klondike Bluffs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Looking to expand the alternatives for Bike to Work Day, Jeff Obst coined the phrase B-BOP (Bike, Bus, Or carPool) Day. In what year was this campaign initiated?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "1991",
    "choices": [
      "A. 1973",
      "B. 1989",
      "C. 1996",
      "D. 1991"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Fat Tire Week takes place in what town in the state of Colorado?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Crested Butte",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aspen",
      "B. Fort Collins",
      "C. Crested Butte",
      "D. Denver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess opening involves up to 3 knight moves in succession before any other piece or pawn is moved.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Alekhine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nimzovitch",
      "B. Sicilian",
      "C. Pirc",
      "D. Alekhine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess opening involves the move P-KB4 (f4) by white, and often the fianchetto of the queens bishop.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Birds Opening",
    "choices": [
      "A. Birds Opening",
      "B. Queens Gambit",
      "C. Benko Gambit",
      "D. Wing Gambit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Fischer Defense to the Kings Gambit involves which of the following moves by black?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "P-Q3, P-KN4, P-KR3, B-KN2",
    "choices": [
      "A. P-Q4, N-KB3, and in some cases QxP",
      "B. B-QB4, N-KB3, N-QB3",
      "C. N-KB3, Q-K2, P-Q3, N-Q2",
      "D. P-Q3, P-KN4, P-KR3, B-KN2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first world champion, Steinitz lost many games against this opening which involves the moves 1 P-K4 P-K4 2 N-KB3 N-QB3 3 B-B4 B-B4 4 P-QN4.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Evans Gambit",
    "choices": [
      "A. Trompowsky Attack",
      "B. Wing Gambit",
      "C. Benko Gambit",
      "D. Evans Gambit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess opening was named after a mythical creature.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Dragon Variation of the Sicilian Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Dragon Variation of the Sicilian Defense",
      "B. The Phoenix Variation of the Trompowsky Attack",
      "C. The Unicorn Variation of the Kings Gambit",
      "D. The Centaur Variation of the Queens Gambit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Hypermodern opening?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "English Opening",
    "choices": [
      "A. Benko Gambit",
      "B. English Opening",
      "C. Sicilian Defense",
      "D. Queens Gambit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The first move by white 1 N-KB3 could result in all of the following openings except which one?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Kings Gambit",
    "choices": [
      "A. English Opening",
      "B. Kings Gambit",
      "C. Spanish Opening",
      "D. Kings Indian Attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This chess opening involves no pawn moves beyond the third rank.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Hedgehog Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. The British Defense",
      "B. The Hedgehog Defense",
      "C. The Hamster Defense",
      "D. The Squirrel Defense"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This defense to the first move P-K4 involves the move P-QB3. It is considered solid, and was a favorite of world champion Anatoly Karpov.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Caro-Kann Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. Nimzovitch Defense",
      "B. Caro-Kann Defense",
      "C. Sicilian Defense",
      "D. French Defense"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This defense to the first move P-K4 involves the move P-K3. It is a very difficult opening to play and was a favorite of Victor Korchnoi.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The French Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Two-Knights Defense",
      "B. The Korchnoi Defense",
      "C. The Falkbeer Counter-gambit",
      "D. The French Defense"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There are open, semi-open and closed openings. Which of the following openings would be considered an open game?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Two Knights Defense",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Queens Indian Defense",
      "B. The Two Knights Defense",
      "C. The Kings Indian Defense",
      "D. The Queens Gambit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andy Corno is known as the starting face off midfielder for this lacrosse team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Barrage",
    "choices": [
      "A. Machine",
      "B. Bayhawks",
      "C. Rattlers",
      "D. Barrage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these lacrosse teams was founded in Chicago?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Machine",
    "choices": [
      "A. Bayhawks",
      "B. Pride",
      "C. Barrage",
      "D. Machine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 2004, this company acquired Warrior Lacrosse, the manufacturer of lacrosse equipment.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "New Balance",
    "choices": [
      "A. New Balance",
      "B. Under Armour",
      "C. Nike",
      "D. STX"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mens field lacrosse is played with how many players on each team?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "10",
    "choices": [
      "A. 8",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 9",
      "D. 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After graduating from Duke University, Matt Breslin became the goalie for this Major League Lacrosse team.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "The Pride",
    "choices": [
      "A. The Pride",
      "B. The Lizards",
      "C. The Outlaws",
      "D. The Cannons"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of these lacrosse teams is paired with the correct city?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Toronto - Nationals",
    "choices": [
      "A. Boston - Outlaws",
      "B. Washington - Lizards",
      "C. Long Island  - Machine",
      "D. Toronto - Nationals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This player started practicing tennis at the age of 12, choosing the sport over football. He has been given the Prince of Asturias Award for Sports.",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Rafael Nadal",
    "choices": [
      "A. Carlos Moya",
      "B. Juan Carlos Ferrero",
      "C. Rafael Nadal",
      "D. Tommy Robredo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1982, Spain hosted the FIFA World Cup for the first time. How many cities in Spain hosted this world tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "14",
    "choices": [
      "A. 10",
      "B. 14",
      "C. 12",
      "D. 8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times a Spanish cyclist has won the Tour de France until 2009?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "12",
    "choices": [
      "A. 12",
      "B. 10",
      "C. 14",
      "D. 16"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What rank did Spain achieve on the Medal table in the Summer Olympics in 1992?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "6th",
    "choices": [
      "A. 4th",
      "B. 10th",
      "C. 6th",
      "D. 8th"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many games did Spain lose in the UEFA Euro 2008 Tournament?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "0",
    "choices": [
      "A. 0",
      "B. 3",
      "C. 2",
      "D. 1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A variation of which of these sports is called Killer?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Pool",
    "choices": [
      "A. Aerobatics",
      "B. Kickboxing",
      "C. Pool",
      "D. Windsurfing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what country did the disc dog sport, commonly known as frisbee dog, originate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "United States",
    "choices": [
      "A. China",
      "B. Australia",
      "C. Scotland",
      "D. United States"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what type of environment is the sport called parkour most often practiced?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "In urban areas",
    "choices": [
      "A. In urban areas",
      "B. In an open bare field",
      "C. In swimming pools",
      "D. In a gym"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To what other popular sport is the game called korfball similar?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Basketball",
    "choices": [
      "A. Basketball",
      "B. Football",
      "C. Baseball",
      "D. Volleyball"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of body movement is involved in the sport called snowkiting?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Gliding on ice",
    "choices": [
      "A. Gliding on ice",
      "B. Jumping from considerable heights",
      "C. All of these",
      "D. Gliding in midair"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country did the sport called campdrafting originate?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Australia",
    "choices": [
      "A. Australia",
      "B. United states",
      "C. Ireland",
      "D. Canada"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of sport is Popinjay, also known as Popingo?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Shooting",
    "choices": [
      "A. Shooting",
      "B. Board sport",
      "C. Combat sport",
      "D. Gymnastics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "On what kind of surface is the sport called bandy practiced?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Ice",
    "choices": [
      "A. Grass",
      "B. Trampoline",
      "C. Ice",
      "D. Wooden floor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of sport is enduro?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "Motorcycle sport",
    "choices": [
      "A. Running marathon",
      "B. None of these",
      "C. Motorcycle sport",
      "D. Martial art"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Elements of which sport does the game called pickleball include?",
    "category": "sports.txt",
    "answer": "All of these",
    "choices": [
      "A. Tennis",
      "B. Ping-pong",
      "C. Badminton",
      "D. All of these"
    ]
  }
]